<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Help on xgDebug&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Help on xgDebug&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>xgDebug&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://www.xgdebug.com/images/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/images/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.136.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 22:08:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clear Thinking</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clearthinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 22:08:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clearthinking/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Clear Thinking in Ordinary Moments</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It doesn’t matter what position you find yourself in right now. What matters is whether you improve your position today.<br>
你现在处境并不重要。重要的是你今天是否改善了处境。</p>
<h2 id="清晰思维的敌人">清晰思维的敌人</h2>
<p>Never forget that your unconscious is smarter than you, faster than you, and more powerful than you. It may even control you. You will never know all of its secrets.<br>
永远不要忘记，你的潜意识比你更聪明，比你更快，比你更强大。它甚至可能控制你。你永远不会知道它的所有秘密。</p>
<p>Criticizing others is easier than coming to know yourself.<br>
批评别人比了解自己更容易。</p>
<p>I never allow myself to have an opinion on anything unless I know the other side’s argument better than they do.<br>
发言者在表达自己的观点之前，会确保自己充分理解并掌握了与自己相对立的观点，甚至比持有这些观点的人更深入地了解。这种态度表明了对全面思考和公正性的高度重视，只有在全面掌握双方论据后，才会形成并表达自己的看法。</p>
<p>Life gets easier when you don’t blame other people and focus on what you can control.<br>
当你不责怪别人并专注于你能控制的事情时，生活会变得更容易</p>
<h2 id="决策行动中的清晰思路">决策：行动中的清晰思路</h2>
<h3 id="定义问题">定义问题</h3>
<p>If you choose not to decide, you still have made a choice.<br>
如果你选择不做决定，你仍然做出了选择。</p>
<p>Defining the problem starts with identifying two things: (1) what you want to achieve, and (2) what obstacles stand in the way of getting it.</p>
<p>定义问题首先要确定两件事：</p>
<ol>
<li>你想要实现什么</li>
<li>哪些障碍阻碍了实现它。</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>THE DEFINITION PRINCIPLE: Take responsibility for defining the problem. Don’t let someone define it for you. Do the work to understand it. Don’t use jargon to describe or explain it.<br>
定义原则：负责定义问题。不要让别人为你定义它。做工作来理解它。不要使用行话来描述或解释它。<br>
THE ROOT CAUSE PRINCIPLE: Identify the root cause of the problem. Don’t be content with simply treating its symptoms.<br>
根本原因原则：确定问题的根本原因。不要满足于简单地治疗其症状。</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="探索可能的解决方案">探索可能的解决方案</h3>
<p>Once you’re clear on the problem, it’s time to think of possible solutions—ways of overcoming the obstacles to get what you want. The way to come up with possible solutions is by imagining different possible futures—different ways the world could turn out.<br>
一旦你弄清楚了问题，就该考虑可能的解决方案了——克服障碍以获得你想要的东西的方法。想出可能的解决方案的方法是想象不同的可能未来——世界可能变成不同的方式。</p>
<p>One of the most common errors at this stage of the decision-making process is avoiding the brutal realities.<br>
在决策过程的这个阶段，最常见的错误之一是避免残酷的现实。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>THE OPPORTUNITY-COST PRINCIPLE: Consider what opportunities you’re forgoing when you choose one option over another.<br>
机会成本原则：考虑当您选择一个选项而不是另一个选项时，您会放弃哪些机会。</p>
<p>The second principle is closely related:<br>
第二个原则密切相关：<br>
THE 3-LENS PRINCIPLE: View opportunity costs through these three lenses:</p>
<ul>
<li>(1) Compared with what?</li>
<li>(2) And then what?</li>
<li>(3) At the expense of what?[*]<br>
三视角原则：通过这三个视角看待机会成本：</li>
<li>(1）与什么相比？</li>
<li>(2）然后呢？</li>
<li>(3）以牺牲什么为代价？[*]</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="do-it">Do it</h2>
<p>You’ve considered the options. You’ve evaluated them. You’ve found the best. It’s time to act!</p>
<p>您已经考虑过这些选项。你已经评估了它们。你已经找到了最好的。是时候采取行动了！</p>
<p>There is no purpose to knowing what you should do and not doing it. If you want results, you need action.</p>
<p>知道你应该做什么和不做什么是没有目的的。如果你想要结果，你需要行动。</p>
<p>Consequential decisions affect the things that matter most: whom you marry, where you live, which business you launch. The more a decision affects what matters to you—either in the short term or the long term—the more consequential it is.</p>
<p>重大决策会影响最重要的事情：你嫁给谁，你住在哪里，你开展哪项业务。一个决定对你的影响越大——无论是短期还是长期——它就越重要。</p>
<h3 id="行动的三项原则">行动的三项原则</h3>
<h4 id="the-asap-principle-if-the-cost-to-undo-the-decision-is-low-make-it-as-soon-as-possible">THE ASAP PRINCIPLE: If the cost to undo the decision is low, make it as soon as possible.</h4>
<p>尽快原则：如果撤销决定的成本很低，请尽快做出。</p>
<h4 id="the-alap-principle-if-the-cost-to-undo-a-decision-is-high-make-it-as-late-as-possible">THE ALAP PRINCIPLE: If the cost to undo a decision is high, make it as late as possible.</h4>
<p>阿拉普原则：如果撤销决策的成本很高，请尽可能晚。</p>
<p>When the stakes are high, and there are no take-backs, you want to decide at the last moment possible, and keep as many options on the table as you can while continuing to gather information.</p>
<p>当赌注很高，而且没有收回时，你要在最后一刻做出决定，并在继续收集信息的同时尽可能多地保留选择。</p>
<h4 id="the-stop-flop-know-原则">“THE STOP, FLOP, KNOW” 原则</h4>
<p>用来帮助人们确定何时停止收集信息并作出决策。这个原则的核心思想是避免陷入过度分析，及时采取行动。它由三个部分组成：</p>
<p>STOP：当你不再能收集到有用的信息时，应该停止信息收集并做出决策。即如果继续收集不会对决策带来实质性帮助，那么就是停止的时刻。</p>
<p>FLOP（First Lose an OPportunity）：如果你已经错失了一个重要机会，那么意味着你等得太久，可能是时候做出决定了。这个点提醒你不要因为犹豫或过多分析而错失时机。</p>
<p>KNOW：当你获得了一条关键信息，足以让你清楚应该选择哪个选项时，就应该立刻做出决定。这意味着如果某条信息已经让你的选择显而易见了，那就不要再拖延。</p>
<h2 id="安全边际">安全边际</h2>
<p>A margin of safety is like having insurance. If you know in advance you won’t need to make a claim this year, it’s a waste of money to buy insurance. The problem is that you don’t know in what year you’ll need to make a claim, so you buy it every year. It might seem like a waste of money in years when nothing happens, but it shows its real value in years when something does.</p>
<p>安全边际就像有保险一样。如果您提前知道今年不需要提出索赔，那么购买保险就是浪费钱。问题是你不知道在哪一年需要提出索赔，所以你每年都会购买。在什么都没发生的时候，这似乎是在浪费钱，但在发生事情的年份里，它显示了它的真正价值。</p>
<p>TIP: The margin of safety is often sufficient when it can absorb double the worst-case scenario. So the baseline for a margin of safety is one that could withstand twice the amount of problems that would cause a crisis, or maintain twice the amount of resources needed to rebuild after a crisis.<br>
提示：当安全边际可以吸收两倍的最坏情况时，安全边际通常就足够了。因此，安全边际的基线是能够承受两倍于导致危机的问题，或者保持两倍于危机后重建所需资源的数量。</p>
<p>Yet even established patterns aren’t foolproof. As Nassim Taleb writes in The Black Swan, “Consider a turkey that is fed every day. Every single feeding will firm up the bird’s belief that it is the general rule of life to be fed every day by friendly members of the human race ‘looking out for its best interests,’ as a politician would say. On the afternoon of the Wednesday before Thanksgiving, something unexpected will happen to the turkey. It will incur a revision of belief.” Our outcomes can sometimes upend even our most well-established expectations.</p>
<p>然而，即使是既定的模式也不是万无一失的。正如纳西姆·塔勒布（Nassim Taleb）在《黑天鹅》（The Black Swan）中所写的那样，“想想每天喂食的火鸡。每一次喂食都会坚定这只鸟的信念，即每天由友好的人类成员喂食是生命的一般规则，正如政治家所说的那样，“为它的最大利益着想”。感恩节前的星期三下午，火鸡会发生意想不到的事情。这将导致信仰的修正。我们的结果有时甚至会颠覆我们最既定的期望。</p>
<p>However, if you have a lot of expertise and data, you can reduce your margin of safety yet further. Here’s an example: Warren Buffett aims to buy stocks that are 30–50 percent less than their true value. So he has a 30–50 percent margin of safety on stocks. But he’ll pay close to a dollar on the dollar for stocks that he understands well. So there’s only maybe a 20 percent margin of safety on the stocks he’s the most confident in.</p>
<p>但是，如果您拥有大量专业知识和数据，则可以进一步降低安全边际。举个例子：沃伦·巴菲特（Warren Buffett）的目标是购买比真实价值低30-50%的股票。因此，他在股票上有30-50%的安全边际。但他会为他熟悉的股票支付接近一美元的价格。因此，他最有信心的股票可能只有20%的安全边际。</p>
<p>One of Warren Buffett’s core tenets for buying a business is that if he doesn’t understand it, he doesn’t buy it. In other words, if he doesn’t have enough information to calculate a margin of safety, he doesn’t invest at all. He also knows that not all margins of safety will protect him—the goal isn’t to get it perfect for every stock he buys; it’s to use the best possible strategy for all his stocks in the big picture.</p>
<p>沃伦·巴菲特（Warren Buffett）购买企业的核心原则之一是，如果他不了解它，他就不会购买它。换句话说，如果他没有足够的信息来计算安全边际，他根本不会投资。他也知道，并非所有的安全边际都能保护他——目标不是让他购买的每一只股票都完美无缺;这是在大局中为他的所有股票使用最佳策略。</p>
<p>Here’s the bottom line: Predicting the future is harder than it seems. Things are great until they’re not. If things are good, a margin of safety seems like a waste. When things go wrong, though, you can’t live without it. You need a margin of safety most at the very moment you start to think you don’t.</p>
<h2 id="想要重要的东西">想要重要的东西</h2>
<p><strong>Think of yourself as dead. You have lived your life. Now take what’s left and live it properly.</strong></p>
<p>GOOD DECISION-MAKING COMES down to two things:
好的决策归结为两件事：</p>
<ol>
<li>Knowing how to get what you want  知道如何得到你想要的东西</li>
<li>Knowing what’s worth wanting 知道什么是值得想要的</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>学校没教的一些生活常识</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/life/why_didnt_they_teach_me_this_in_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:08:14 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/life/why_didnt_they_teach_me_this_in_school/</guid>
      <description>Why didn’t they teach me this in school?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="不要攀比永远有人比你过得更好">不要攀比，永远有人比你过得更好</h2>
<p>You are the only one who knows what’s most important to you. Remember that: What is important to YOU? Not what is important to the Joneses next door. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>记录10月的时间是怎么没的</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/diary/2024/1002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 22:38:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/diary/2024/1002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-01&#34;&gt;2024-10-01&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上午 10 点 30 才起，更加厉害了，因为昨天晚上 1 点过才睡觉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;写下了昨天晚上突然闪现的一点思考 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/economics/dictators-response-to-economic-downturn/&#34;&gt;经济衰退一种可能的应对方案
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;下午计划去商场逛一逛，或许找个咖啡店看看书？这就是生活。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-02&#34;&gt;2024-10-02&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;轻松的假期，啥都没做一样。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;下午修理了两个机器人，改了一些BUG。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;还有余额显示的BUG没有修，不想动了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;晚上看了直播，秋实聊到了目前做一个视频号大概是普通人有机会跨越阶级的唯一机会。因为普通人也干不了AI。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-03&#34;&gt;2024-10-03&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;时间好快，今天起得比较早&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上午收到了AWS帐单，感觉好贵，花一上午时间换了一台 512的VPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The greatest Enemies of the Equity investor are &lt;strong&gt;Expenses&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Emotions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;股票投资者最大的敌人是&lt;strong&gt;费用&lt;/strong&gt;和&lt;strong&gt;情绪&lt;/strong&gt;。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;研究了一下债券，这东西感觉和定期存款差不多，主要还是用来与股票做搭配，关键作用是用来再平衡，实现算法上的抄底与逃顶。当然了，代价是截断收益与提前加仓。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;下午和晚上搞了一下 AI ，收人红包800帮人办事，没有复利效应，很不划算。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-05&#34;&gt;2024-10-05&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上午学习了一会儿数字币的安全知识，这世界不存在绝对的安全。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;拒绝了同学的程序开发请求，因为我不想做&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;简单逻辑学&amp;gt;看到50%了，前面都 是一些基础概念，到了后面的计算部分反而觉得简单很多，因为与或非在计算机中常用。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;更新大话计算器，浪费8小时生命&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-08&#34;&gt;2024-10-08&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A股今天开始交易，一开盘就全线涨停。我无法判断是散户的疯狂还是有形之手在操作。从直觉判断，散户应该不会直接挂涨停价买。但是成交量也很高，这让我很困惑。有成交量就说明有人在涨停价出，同时也有人在接手。如果不是自己和自己玩亏手续费。那就是真的有大量散户在入场。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;涨停板并没有封住，很快就一路下滑，最终涨4.59%成交3.5万亿。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上周就开始有公司公布减持，在市场情绪如此高涨时，有钱不赚钱反而开始减持，这里面必然有期原因。我想主要还是他们自己也不相信自己的公司。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;想不明白是谁在真金白银的接盘。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-09&#34;&gt;2024-10-09&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;打包了 MAC 的 AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;写了个记录 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/stock/%E6%9A%B4%E6%B6%A8%E5%90%8E%E9%A6%96%E6%AC%A1%E5%A4%A7%E8%B7%8C/&#34;&gt;暴涨后首次大跌：短期波动还是市场预警？&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-10&#34;&gt;2024-10-10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;今天是个特殊的日子，值得铭记&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;今天下午操作了我的帐户，卖出了50% &lt;em&gt;工商银行&lt;/em&gt;股份。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;今天市场小盘整体下跌，权重大盘股涨了4～5%，同时财政部宣布周6召开新闻发布会。我分析后认为，政策制定者是想要暂时稳住市场所以拉了大盤股，同时释放消息稳定市场信心。 同六的新闻发布会一定会出台一些实际的政策把市场拉回来，因为他们的目的还远没有达成，并且现在也还有很多招没有出，现在不可能放弃市场。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;基于上面的判断，我决定今日与明日分批卖出，每次为卖出时持仓的50% ,并且于下周一周二逐步补回。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;这一次操作违背了我最重要的条原则：不要尝试TIMING市场。 但是我又想真金白银的检验一下自己最近的认知，到底是不是正确，同时不可否认我也有一些贪婪的欲望想要赚钱。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-12&#34;&gt;2024-10-12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;正的智者往往有独立的思想和判断，不依赖他人的认可或社会的标准来确认自己的价值。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-10-13&#34;&gt;2024-10-13&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;内阁根本是个摆设，全部由嘉靖帝一人决定。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="2024-10-01">2024-10-01</h2>
<ul>
<li>上午 10 点 30 才起，更加厉害了，因为昨天晚上 1 点过才睡觉</li>
<li>写下了昨天晚上突然闪现的一点思考 <a href="/posts/economics/dictators-response-to-economic-downturn/">经济衰退一种可能的应对方案
</a></li>
<li>下午计划去商场逛一逛，或许找个咖啡店看看书？这就是生活。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-02">2024-10-02</h2>
<ul>
<li>轻松的假期，啥都没做一样。</li>
<li>下午修理了两个机器人，改了一些BUG。</li>
<li>还有余额显示的BUG没有修，不想动了。</li>
<li>晚上看了直播，秋实聊到了目前做一个视频号大概是普通人有机会跨越阶级的唯一机会。因为普通人也干不了AI。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-03">2024-10-03</h2>
<ul>
<li>时间好快，今天起得比较早</li>
<li>上午收到了AWS帐单，感觉好贵，花一上午时间换了一台 512的VPS</li>
<li>The greatest Enemies of the Equity investor are <strong>Expenses</strong> and <strong>Emotions</strong>.</li>
<li>股票投资者最大的敌人是<strong>费用</strong>和<strong>情绪</strong>。</li>
<li>研究了一下债券，这东西感觉和定期存款差不多，主要还是用来与股票做搭配，关键作用是用来再平衡，实现算法上的抄底与逃顶。当然了，代价是截断收益与提前加仓。</li>
<li>下午和晚上搞了一下 AI ，收人红包800帮人办事，没有复利效应，很不划算。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-05">2024-10-05</h2>
<ul>
<li>上午学习了一会儿数字币的安全知识，这世界不存在绝对的安全。</li>
<li>拒绝了同学的程序开发请求，因为我不想做</li>
<li>&lt;简单逻辑学&gt;看到50%了，前面都 是一些基础概念，到了后面的计算部分反而觉得简单很多，因为与或非在计算机中常用。</li>
<li>更新大话计算器，浪费8小时生命</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-08">2024-10-08</h2>
<ul>
<li>A股今天开始交易，一开盘就全线涨停。我无法判断是散户的疯狂还是有形之手在操作。从直觉判断，散户应该不会直接挂涨停价买。但是成交量也很高，这让我很困惑。有成交量就说明有人在涨停价出，同时也有人在接手。如果不是自己和自己玩亏手续费。那就是真的有大量散户在入场。</li>
<li>涨停板并没有封住，很快就一路下滑，最终涨4.59%成交3.5万亿。</li>
<li>上周就开始有公司公布减持，在市场情绪如此高涨时，有钱不赚钱反而开始减持，这里面必然有期原因。我想主要还是他们自己也不相信自己的公司。</li>
<li>想不明白是谁在真金白银的接盘。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-09">2024-10-09</h2>
<ul>
<li>打包了 MAC 的 AI</li>
<li>写了个记录 <a href="/posts/investment/stock/%E6%9A%B4%E6%B6%A8%E5%90%8E%E9%A6%96%E6%AC%A1%E5%A4%A7%E8%B7%8C/">暴涨后首次大跌：短期波动还是市场预警？</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-10">2024-10-10</h2>
<ul>
<li>今天是个特殊的日子，值得铭记</li>
<li>今天下午操作了我的帐户，卖出了50% <em>工商银行</em>股份。</li>
<li>今天市场小盘整体下跌，权重大盘股涨了4～5%，同时财政部宣布周6召开新闻发布会。我分析后认为，政策制定者是想要暂时稳住市场所以拉了大盤股，同时释放消息稳定市场信心。 同六的新闻发布会一定会出台一些实际的政策把市场拉回来，因为他们的目的还远没有达成，并且现在也还有很多招没有出，现在不可能放弃市场。</li>
<li>基于上面的判断，我决定今日与明日分批卖出，每次为卖出时持仓的50% ,并且于下周一周二逐步补回。</li>
<li>这一次操作违背了我最重要的条原则：不要尝试TIMING市场。 但是我又想真金白银的检验一下自己最近的认知，到底是不是正确，同时不可否认我也有一些贪婪的欲望想要赚钱。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-12">2024-10-12</h2>
<ul>
<li>正的智者往往有独立的思想和判断，不依赖他人的认可或社会的标准来确认自己的价值。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-13">2024-10-13</h2>
<p>内阁根本是个摆设，全部由嘉靖帝一人决定。</p>
<ul>
<li>决策是仓促的</li>
<li>手段是激烈的</li>
<li>效果是极端的</li>
<li>结果是烂尾的</li>
<li>晚上观看了StarShip 第5次发射，Super Heavy 被接住的一刻，我无比激动，人类终于要走向宇宙了。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-14">2024-10-14</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/investment/stock/%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%84%8F%E8%AF%86%E7%9A%84%E6%8A%95%E6%9C%BA%E6%93%8D%E4%BD%9C/">第一次有意识的投机操作</a> 的时候卖出部分，今天与明天计划购回，不过事情并没有像我预期的发展</li>
<li>工商银行今天继续上涨，我没有做任何操作。明日再观察一下，如果没有机会回补那就不回补了，直接加仓到ETF吧。</li>
<li>事实证明我们确实不可能TIMING市场。</li>
<li>晚上给我的BLOG添加了 github action cache</li>
<li>今天没看书，晚上和AI讨论了老半天，有一点点收获，但是不太多</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-15">2024-10-15</h2>
<ul>
<li>半个月已经过了，时间真是太快了，仿佛虚度了半个月，为什么呢？我想大概是因为自己没有做出什么东西来</li>
<li>今天小区停电，最终还是没有出门，不知道是不是懒。</li>
<li>上午看了一上午的书 《The Millionaire Next Door》,前面两章讲的都是节省，不要让你有生活方式超过你的能力。并且要让生活方式远远的低于你的能力。</li>
<li>很多人拥有一堆的负债，无数的东西不断的从他们的口袋里面掏钱出来，但是却没有什么向他们口袋放钱的资产。</li>
<li>除非是你刻意节省，否则你的支出永远等于你的收入</li>
<li>无论你的收入高低，你一定要先为自己工作。而不是为房东，为裁缝店，为肉铺，为学校等等打工。</li>
<li>让你的钱为你工作，这是一个技术活，一定要认真的学习</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-16">2024-10-16</h2>
<ul>
<li>上午看到要重启搞一次城中村改造，今年完成100万套项目，采用货币货安置，也就是涨价去库存2.0</li>
<li>100万套*100万一平方，也就是一万亿而已</li>
<li>并且危房数量是有限的，不可能每年都100万套</li>
<li>平均一年也就是新增加10万套左右的危房而已，所以这也是不可持续的</li>
<li>除非是一把拉起来，让老百姓去接，否则也拉不起来的</li>
<li>今年郑州居然还有60万套烂尾楼?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-17">2024-10-17</h2>
<ul>
<li>10号的判断少考虑了烂尾的因素。</li>
<li>我们可能需要一直修正自己的判断。因为世界是变化的。</li>
<li>那么我们也要收放自如，不停的翻大饼吗？</li>
<li>保持灵活性：由于世界变化迅速，我们需要不断修正自己的判断和策略。无论是投资者、政策制定者还是个人，都应根据新的信息和变化的环境做出调整，避免因过时的判断而陷入困境。</li>
<li>动态应对：不论是经济政策还是投资决策，都应采取动态应对策略。对于经济刺激措施的效果保持警惕，观察其对实际经济的反馈，并根据新情况及时调整。对长期趋势和短期波动保持平衡的视角，避免过度依赖某种措施或理论。</li>
<li>夫处世之道，亦即应变之术，岂可偏执一端。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-18">2024-10-18</h2>
<ul>
<li>居民存款与贷款变成了开发商的房款</li>
<li>开发商的房款变成土地转让费，开发税费，盖章好处费。</li>
<li>最终变成了官吏们的付款，没有车的高速，豪华的办公大楼，以及开发商手里无力开发的荒废土地</li>
<li>下午A股又拉起来了，看来之前的判断还是有一定的道理。先不想了</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-19">2024-10-19</h2>
<ul>
<li>重读旧书，Just Keep Buying 前面主要是讲储蓄，感觉没什么劲。</li>
<li>选股会导致自己的情绪受到极大影响，这与短期投机一样。</li>
<li>不要考验自己的情绪管理能力。</li>
<li>凡是选择，必有代价。</li>
<li>晚上我计算了一下5年前持有工商银行，到现在收益约 9.14 ，长江电力约为14.8%。所以，你不可能打败指数。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-21">2024-10-21</h2>
<ul>
<li>又是忙碌的周一</li>
<li>更新了我的F3P固件</li>
<li>写了T15更新说明</li>
<li>重构了我的BLOG</li>
<li>开始阅读新书</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-10-24">2024-10-24</h2>
<ul>
<li>这三天时间不知道去哪儿了对吧？这三天时间被我卖了。 很不划算又无可奈何</li>
<li>人太忙碌了也不好，时间过得太快了。 大脑被代码占满。完全没有时间思考 。</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>尝试开始写日记，记录时间是怎么没的</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/diary/2024/0929/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 11:01:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/diary/2024/0929/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024-09-29&#34;&gt;2024-09-29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上午 10 点半才起床，把我的 blog 部署到了 github,改为使用 github action 来部署，感觉比以前两个仓库方便多了&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上午 11 点开始放视频，所以接下来这一个小时基本上要浪费掉的。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="2024-09-29">2024-09-29</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>上午 10 点半才起床，把我的 blog 部署到了 github,改为使用 github action 来部署，感觉比以前两个仓库方便多了</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>上午 11 点开始放视频，所以接下来这一个小时基本上要浪费掉的。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>下午给我的 blog 加上了搜索功能，感觉很快时间就过了。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>晚上开始阅读了一点 The 48 Law Of Power ,这本书感觉有点暗黑，我不喜欢。 但是我怀疑我这种君子情节是受到了封建礼教的毒害，万一当个小人更加快乐呢？天知道。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>一天过完，人生就是这么的快。</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2024-09-30">2024-09-30</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>上午依然 10 点起床，然后开始了疯狂的一天,整个股市一篇欢腾，开盘 30 分钟成交量破万亿，到下午大盘上涨了 8%。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>下午在群里看大家发各种段子，一天时间就这样被浪费掉了。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>今天我没有作任何的操作，上午有调整一下仓位的想法，但是很快打消了念头，目前我的持仓很合理。到了下午又想起了看的书。4 根大阳线无法改变我的信仰。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>最终我花了一点时间，把今天发生的事写了下来: <a href="/posts/economics/the-largest-signle-day-surge-in-the-history-of-chinas-stock-market/">写在 A 股历史性的爆涨之日:虚假繁荣还是稳步上行？
</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>何谓三观不合</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BD%95%E8%B0%93%E4%B8%89%E8%A7%82%E4%B8%8D%E5%90%88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 15:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BD%95%E8%B0%93%E4%B8%89%E8%A7%82%E4%B8%8D%E5%90%88/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;你敬畏天理，他崇拜权威，&lt;br&gt;
这是世界观不同；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你站在良知一边，他站在强者一边，&lt;br&gt;
这是价值观不同；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你努力是为理想的生活，&lt;br&gt;
他努力是做人上人，&lt;br&gt;
这是人生观不同。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>你敬畏天理，他崇拜权威，<br>
这是世界观不同；</p>
<p>你站在良知一边，他站在强者一边，<br>
这是价值观不同；</p>
<p>你努力是为理想的生活，<br>
他努力是做人上人，<br>
这是人生观不同。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 06:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. The same way that money multiplies through compound interest, the effects of your habits multiply as you repeat them. They seem to make little difference on any given day and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &amp;gt; Location 313&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;。人们做了一些小的改变，没有看到切实的结果，并决定停止。你会想，“我已经连续一个月每天都跑步了，为什么我的身体没有任何变化？一旦这种想法占据了上风，就很容易让好习惯被抛在一边。但为了产生有意义的改变，习惯需要持续足够长的时间才能突破这个高原——我称之为潜在潜力高原。 People make a few small changes, fail to see a tangible result, and decide to stop. You think, “I’ve been running every day for a month, so why can’t I see any change in my body?” Once this kind of thinking takes over, it’s easy to let good habits fall by the wayside. But in order to make a meaningful difference, habits need to persist long enough to break through this plateau—what I call the Plateau of Latent Potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. The same way that money multiplies through compound interest, the effects of your habits multiply as you repeat them. They seem to make little difference on any given day and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 313</p>
<p>。人们做了一些小的改变，没有看到切实的结果，并决定停止。你会想，“我已经连续一个月每天都跑步了，为什么我的身体没有任何变化？一旦这种想法占据了上风，就很容易让好习惯被抛在一边。但为了产生有意义的改变，习惯需要持续足够长的时间才能突破这个高原——我称之为潜在潜力高原。 People make a few small changes, fail to see a tangible result, and decide to stop. You think, “I’ve been running every day for a month, so why can’t I see any change in my body?” Once this kind of thinking takes over, it’s easy to let good habits fall by the wayside. But in order to make a meaningful difference, habits need to persist long enough to break through this plateau—what I call the Plateau of Latent Potential.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 316</p>
<p>Ha 好习惯难以养成,主要是没有进度条</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 317</p>
<p>If you find yourself struggling to build a good habit or break a bad one, it is not because you have lost your ability to improve. It is often because you have not yet crossed the Plateau of Latent Potential.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 320</p>
<p>When you finally break through the Plateau of Latent Potential, people will call it an overnight success.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 335</p>
<p>All big things come from small beginnings. The seed of every habit is a single, tiny decision. But as that decision is repeated, a habit sprouts and grows stronger. Roots entrench themselves and branches grow. The task of breaking a bad habit is like uprooting a powerful oak within us.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 341</p>
<p>FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 341</p>
<p>忽略目标,专注于打造系统</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 345</p>
<p>I began to realize that my results had very little to do with the goals I set and nearly everything to do with the systems I followed.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 346</p>
<p>系统比目标有用</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 347</p>
<p>Goals are about the results you want to achieve. Systems are about the processes that lead to those results. If you’re a coach, your goal might be to win a championship. Your system is the way you recruit players, manage your assistant coaches, and conduct practice. If you’re an entrepreneur, your goal might be to build a million-dollar business. Your system is how you test product ideas, hire employees, and run marketing campaigns. If you’re a musician, your goal might be to play a new piece. Your system is how often you practice, how you break down and tackle difficult measures, and your method for receiving feedback from your instructor.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 352</p>
<p>目标是想要获得的东西,系统是如何获得的方法论</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 353</p>
<p>Now for the interesting question: If you completely ignored your goals and focused only on your system, would you still succeed? For example, if you were a basketball coach and you ignored your goal to win a championship and focused only on what your team does at practice each day, would you still get results?</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 355</p>
<p>不要设定目标为年级第几,而是设定为爱学习</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 360</p>
<p>Problem #1: Winners and losers have the same goals.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 361</p>
<p>Goal setting suffers from a serious case of survivorship bias.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 361</p>
<p>亚军的目标也是冠军,这就是幸存者偏差</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 368</p>
<p>Problem #2: Achieving a goal is only a momentary change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 368</p>
<p>Imagine you have a messy room and you set a goal to clean it. If you summon the energy to tidy up, then you will have a clean room—for now. But if you maintain the same sloppy, pack-rat habits that led to a messy room in the first place, soon you’ll be looking at a new pile of clutter and hoping for another burst of motivation. You’re left chasing the same outcome because you never changed the system behind it. You treated a symptom without addressing the cause.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 371</p>
<p>整理房间是一个目标,爱整洁才是身份</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 373</p>
<p>When you solve problems at the results level, you only solve them temporarily. In order to improve for good, you need to solve problems at the systems level. Fix the inputs and the outputs will fix themselves.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 375</p>
<p>Problem #3: Goals restrict your happiness.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 376</p>
<p>达不成目标还怎么快乐</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 376</p>
<p>The implicit assumption behind any goal is this: “Once I reach my goal, then I’ll be happy.” The problem with a goals-first mentality is that you’re continually putting happiness off until the next milestone.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 383</p>
<p>A systems-first mentality provides the antidote. When you fall in love with the process rather than the product, you don’t have to wait to give yourself permission to be happy. You can be satisfied anytime your system is running. And a system can be successful in many different forms, not just the one you first envision.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 385</p>
<p>Problem #4: Goals are at odds with long-term progress.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 385</p>
<p>溜溜球效应</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 386</p>
<p>Finally, a goal-oriented mind-set can create a “yo-yo” effect. Many runners work hard for months, but as soon as they cross the finish line, they stop training. The race is no longer there to motivate them. When all of your hard work is focused on a particular goal, what is left to push you forward after you achieve it? This is why many people find themselves reverting to their old habits after accomplishing a goal.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 389</p>
<p>The purpose of setting goals is to win the game. The purpose of building systems is to continue playing the game.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 395</p>
<p>Focusing on the overall system, rather than a single goal, is one of the core themes of this book.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 403</p>
<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. Getting 1 percent better every day counts for a lot in the long-run. Habits are a double-edged sword. They can work for you or against you, which is why understanding the details is essential. Small changes often appear to make no difference until you cross a critical threshold. The most powerful outcomes of any compounding process are delayed. You need to be patient. An atomic habit is a little habit that is part of a larger system. Just as atoms are the building blocks of molecules, atomic habits are the building blocks of remarkable results. If you want better results, then forget about setting goals. Focus on your system instead. You do not rise to the level of your goals. You fall to the level of your systems.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 414</p>
<p>It often feels difficult to keep good habits going for more than a few days, even with sincere effort and the occasional burst of motivation. Habits like exercise, meditation, journaling, and cooking are reasonable for a day or two and then become a hassle. However, once your habits are established, they seem to stick around forever—especially the unwanted ones.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 418</p>
<p>Changing our habits is challenging for two reasons: (1) we try to change the wrong thing and (2) we try to change our habits in the wrong way.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 422</p>
<p>THREE LAYERS OF BEHAVIOR CHANGE</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 425</p>
<p>The first layer is changing your outcomes. This level is concerned with changing your results: losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship. Most of the goals you set are associated with this level of change. The second layer is changing your process. This level is concerned with changing your habits and systems: implementing a new routine at the gym, decluttering your desk for better workflow, developing a meditation practice. Most of the habits you build are associated with this level. The third and deepest layer is changing your identity. This level is concerned with changing your beliefs: your worldview, your self-image, your judgments about yourself and others. Most of the beliefs, assumptions, and biases you hold are associated with this level.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 431</p>
<p>Outcomes are about what you get. Processes are about what you do. Identity is about what you believe.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 434</p>
<p>Many people begin the process of changing their habits by focusing on what they want to achieve. This leads us to outcome-based habits. The alternative is to build identity-based habits. With this approach, we start by focusing on who we wish to become.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 436</p>
<p>目标不是单一成就,而是成为什么人</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 441</p>
<p>Imagine two people resisting a cigarette. When offered a smoke, the first person says, “No thanks. I’m trying to quit.” It sounds like a reasonable response, but this person still believes they are a smoker who is trying to be something else. They are hoping their behavior will change while carrying around the same beliefs. The second person declines by saying, “No thanks. I’m not a smoker.” It’s a small difference, but this statement signals a shift in identity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 446</p>
<p>Most people don’t even consider identity change when they set out to improve. They just think, “I want to be skinny (outcome) and if I stick to this diet, then I’ll be skinny (process).” They set goals and determine the actions they should take to achieve those goals without considering the beliefs that drive their actions. They never shift the way they look at themselves, and they don’t realize that their old identity can sabotage their new plans for change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 454</p>
<p>Behavior that is incongruent with the self will not last.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 457</p>
<p>It’s hard to change your habits if you never change the underlying beliefs that led to your past behavior. You have a new goal and a new plan, but you haven’t changed who you are.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 466</p>
<p>The ultimate form of intrinsic motivation is when a habit becomes part of your identity. It’s one thing to say I’m the type of person who wants this. It’s something very different to say I’m the type of person who is this.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 468</p>
<p>好标签</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 472</p>
<p>True behavior change is identity change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 475</p>
<p>The goal is not to read a book, the goal is to become a reader. The goal is not to run a marathon, the goal is to become a runner. The goal is not to learn an instrument, the goal is to become a musician.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 477</p>
<p>身份认同决定行为</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 477</p>
<p>Your behaviors are usually a reflection of your identity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 482</p>
<p>Doing the right thing is easy. After all, when your behavior and your identity are fully aligned, you are no longer pursuing behavior change. You are simply acting like the type of person you already believe yourself to be.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 496</p>
<p>On any given day, you may struggle with your habits because you’re too busy or too tired or too overwhelmed or hundreds of other reasons. Over the long run, however, the real reason you fail to stick with habits is that your self-image gets in the way. This is why you can’t get too attached to one version of your identity. Progress requires unlearning. Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 499</p>
<p>抛弃旧版本的你,不断迭代</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 502</p>
<p>THE TWO-STEP PROCESS TO CHANGING YOUR IDENTITY</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 503</p>
<p>Your identity emerges out of your habits. You are not born with preset beliefs. Every belief, including those about yourself, is learned and conditioned through experience.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 505</p>
<p>More precisely, your habits are how you embody your identity. When you make your bed each day, you embody the identity of an organized person. When you write each day, you embody the identity of a creative person. When you train each day, you embody the identity of an athletic person.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 506</p>
<p>以身作则的意思是,孩子也想成为和你一样的人(爱学习?可以无限玩手机?)</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 516</p>
<p>Of course, your habits are not the only actions that influence your identity, but by virtue of their frequency they are usually the most important ones. Each experience in life modifies your self-image, but it’s unlikely you would consider yourself a soccer player because you kicked a ball once or an artist because you scribbled a picture. As you repeat these actions, however, the evidence accumulates and your self-image begins to change. The effect of one-off experiences tends to fade away while the effect of habits gets reinforced with time, which means your habits contribute most of the evidence that shapes your identity. In this way, the process of building habits is actually the process of becoming yourself.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 527</p>
<p>Small habits can make a meaningful difference by providing evidence of a new identity. And if a change is meaningful, it actually is big. That’s the paradox of making small improvements. Putting this all together, you can see that habits are the path to changing your identity. The most practical way to change who you are is to change what you do. Each time you write a page, you are a writer. Each time you practice the violin, you are a musician. Each time you start a workout, you are an athlete. Each time you encourage your employees, you are a leader.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 532</p>
<p>Each habit not only gets results but also teaches you something far more important: to trust yourself. You start to believe you can actually accomplish these things.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 537</p>
<p>New identities require new evidence. If you keep casting the same votes you’ve always cast, you’re going to get the same results you’ve always had. If nothing changes, nothing is going to change. It is a simple two-step process: Decide the type of person you want to be. Prove it to yourself with small wins.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 545</p>
<p>“Who is the type of person that could get the outcome I want?” Who is the type of person that could lose forty pounds? Who is the type of person that could learn a new language? Who is the type of person that could run a successful start-up?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 548</p>
<p>This process can lead to beliefs like: “I’m the kind of teacher who stands up for her students.” “I’m the kind of doctor who gives each patient the time and empathy they need.” “I’m the kind of manager who advocates for her employees.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 551</p>
<p>Once you have a handle on the type of person you want to be, you can begin taking small steps to reinforce your desired identity. I have a friend who lost over 100 pounds by asking herself, “What would a healthy person do?” All day long, she would use this question as a guide. Would a healthy person walk or take a cab? Would a healthy person order a burrito or a salad? She figured if she acted like a healthy person long enough, eventually she would become that person. She was right.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 555</p>
<p>Fake it ,untill you make it</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 558</p>
<p>THE REAL REASON HABITS MATTER Identity change is the North Star of habit change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 561</p>
<p>you becoming the type of person you want to become?” The first step is not what or how, but who. You need to know who you want to be. Otherwise, your quest for change is like a boat without a rudder. And that’s why we are starting here.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 568</p>
<p>Ultimately, your habits matter because they help you become the type of person you wish to be. They are the channel through which you develop your deepest beliefs about yourself. Quite literally, you become your habits.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 571</p>
<p>There are three levels of change: outcome change, process change, and identity change. The most effective way to change your habits is to focus not on what you want to achieve, but on who you wish to become. Your identity emerges out of your habits. Every action is a vote for the type of person you wish to become. Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity. The real reason habits matter is not because they can get you better results (although they can do that), but because they can change your beliefs about yourself.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 616</p>
<p>Habits are mental shortcuts learned from experience.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 622</p>
<p>Habits reduce cognitive load and free up mental capacity, so you can allocate your attention to other tasks.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 634</p>
<p>THE SCIENCE OF HOW HABITS WORK The process of building a habit can be divided into four simple steps: cue, craving, response, and reward.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 638</p>
<p>All habits proceed through four stages in the same order: cue, craving, response, and reward.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 645</p>
<p>the cue is the first indication that we’re close to a reward, it naturally leads to a craving. Cravings are the second step, and they are the motivational force behind every habit.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 654</p>
<p>The third step is the response.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 660</p>
<p>The first purpose of rewards is to satisfy your craving. Yes, rewards provide benefits on their own. Food and water deliver the energy you need to survive.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 664</p>
<p>Second, rewards teach us which actions are worth remembering in the future. Your brain is a reward detector. As you go about your life, your sensory nervous system is continuously monitoring which actions satisfy your desires and deliver pleasure.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 673</p>
<p>The four stages of habit are best described as a feedback loop. They form an endless cycle that is running every moment you are alive. This “habit loop” is continually scanning the environment, predicting what will happen next, trying out different responses, and learning from the results.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 676</p>
<p>In summary, the cue triggers a craving, which motivates a response, which provides a reward, which satisfies the craving and, ultimately, becomes associated with the cue.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 689</p>
<p>All behavior is driven by the desire to solve a problem.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 738</p>
<p>How to Create a Good Habit The 1st law (Cue): Make it obvious. The 2nd law (Craving): Make it attractive. The 3rd law (Response): Make it easy. The 4th law (Reward): Make it satisfying.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 743</p>
<p>How to Break a Bad Habit Inversion of the 1st law (Cue): Make it invisible. Inversion of the 2nd law (Craving): Make it unattractive. Inversion of the 3rd law (Response): Make it difficult. Inversion of the 4th law (Reward): Make it unsatisfying.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 750</p>
<p>Whenever you want to change your behavior, you can simply ask yourself: How can I make it obvious? How can I make it attractive? How can I make it easy? How can I make it satisfying?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 757</p>
<p>Every goal is doomed to fail if it goes against the grain of human nature.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 760</p>
<p>Chapter Summary A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic. The ultimate purpose of habits is to solve the problems of life with as little energy and effort as possible. Any habit can be broken down into a feedback loop that involves four steps: cue, craving, response, and reward. The Four Laws of Behavior Change are a simple set of rules we can use to build better habits. They are (1) make it obvious, (2) make it attractive, (3) make it easy, and (4) make it satisfying.</p>
<p>THE 1ST LAW: Make It Obvious</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 791</p>
<p>With enough practice, you can pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it. Automatically, your brain encodes the lessons learned through experience. We can’t always explain what it is we are learning, but learning is happening all along the way, and your ability to notice the relevant cues in a given situation is the foundation for every habit you have.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 800</p>
<p>This is one of the most surprising insights about our habits: you don’t need to be aware of the cue for a habit to begin. You can notice an opportunity and take action without dedicating conscious attention to it. This is what makes habits useful.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 817</p>
<p>“Until you make the unconscious conscious, it will direct your life and you will call it fate.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 828</p>
<p>Pointing-and-Calling is so effective because it raises the level of awareness from a nonconscious habit to a more conscious level.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 833</p>
<p>The more automatic a behavior becomes, the less likely we are to consciously think about it. And when we’ve done something a thousand times before, we begin to overlook things. We assume that the next time will be just like the last.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 836</p>
<p>One of our greatest challenges in changing habits is maintaining awareness of what we are actually doing.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 873</p>
<p>With enough practice, your brain will pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it. Once our habits become automatic, we stop paying attention to what we are doing. The process of behavior change always starts with awareness. You need to be aware of your habits before you can change them. Pointing-and-Calling raises your level of awareness from a nonconscious habit to a more conscious level by verbalizing your actions. The Habits Scorecard is a simple exercise you can use to become more aware of your behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 888</p>
<p>I will partake in at least 20 minutes of vigorous exercise on [DAY] at [TIME] in [PLACE].”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 904</p>
<p>Too many people try to change their habits without these basic details figured out. We tell ourselves, “I’m going to eat healthier” or “I’m going to write more,” but we never say when and where these habits are going to happen.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 908</p>
<p>Many people think they lack motivation when what they really lack is clarity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 912</p>
<p>Simply follow your predetermined plan. The simple way to apply this strategy to your habits is to fill out this sentence: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION]. Meditation. I will meditate for one minute at 7 a.m. in my kitchen. Studying. I will study Spanish for twenty minutes at 6 p.m. in my bedroom. Exercise. I will exercise for one hour at 5 p.m. in my local gym. Marriage. I will make my partner a cup of tea at 8 a.m. in the kitchen.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 927</p>
<p>HABIT STACKING: A SIMPLE PLAN TO OVERHAUL YOUR HABITS</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 940</p>
<p>The Diderot Effect states that obtaining a new possession often creates a spiral of consumption that leads to additional purchases.</p>
<p>Note - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 941</p>
<p>迪德罗效应</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 946</p>
<p>Each action becomes a cue that triggers the next behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 948</p>
<p>One of the best ways to build a new habit is to identify a current habit you already do each day and then stack your new behavior on top. This is called habit stacking.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 953</p>
<p>“After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [NEW HABIT].”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 958</p>
<p>The key is to tie your desired behavior into something you already do each day.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 1011</p>
<p>The 1st Law of Behavior Change is make it obvious. The two most common cues are time and location. Creating an implementation intention is a strategy you can use to pair a new habit with a specific time and location. The implementation intention formula is: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION]. Habit stacking is a strategy you can use to pair a new habit with a current habit. The habit stacking formula is: After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [NEW HABIT].</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1036</p>
<p>Environment is the invisible hand that shapes human behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1089</p>
<p>If you want to make a habit a big part of your life, make the cue a big part of your environment. The most persistent behaviors usually have multiple cues.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1113</p>
<p>habits can be easier to change in a new environment.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1143</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Small changes in context can lead to large changes in behavior over time. Every habit is initiated by a cue. We are more likely to notice cues that stand out. Make the cues of good habits obvious in your environment. Gradually, your habits become associated not with a single trigger but with the entire context surrounding the behavior. The context becomes the cue. It is easier to build new habits in a new environment because you are not fighting against old cues.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1182</p>
<p>Shaming obese people with weight-loss presentations can make them feel stressed, and as a result many people return to their favorite coping strategy: overeating. Showing pictures of blackened lungs to smokers leads to higher levels of anxiety, which drives many people to reach for a cigarette. If you’re not careful about cues, you can cause the very behavior you want to stop.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1185</p>
<p>Bad habits are autocatalytic: the process feeds itself. They foster the feelings they try to numb. You feel bad, so you eat junk food. Because you eat junk food, you feel bad.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1199</p>
<p>If you can’t seem to get any work done, leave your phone in another room for a few hours. If you’re continually feeling like you’re not enough, stop following social media accounts that trigger jealousy and envy. If you’re wasting too much time watching television, move the TV out of the bedroom. If you’re spending too much money on electronics, quit reading reviews of the latest tech gear. If you’re playing too many video games, unplug the console and put it in a closet after each use.</p>
<p>Note - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1203</p>
<p>移除敏感源</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1209</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 1st Law of Behavior Change is make it invisible. Once a habit is formed, it is unlikely to be forgotten. People with high self-control tend to spend less time in tempting situations. It’s easier to avoid temptation than resist it. One of the most practical ways to eliminate a bad habit is to reduce exposure to the cue that causes it. Self-control is a short-term strategy, not a long-term one.</p>
<p>THE 2ND LAW: Make It Attractive</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1236</p>
<p>How to Make a Habit Irresistible</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1276</p>
<p>Make it attractive. The more attractive an opportunity is, the more likely it is to become habit-forming.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1287</p>
<p>If you want to increase the odds that a behavior will occur, then you need to make it attractive. Throughout our discussion of the 2nd Law, our goal is to learn how to make our habits irresistible.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1315</p>
<p>As an adult, daydreaming about an upcoming vacation can be more enjoyable than actually being on vacation.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1358</p>
<p>psychology theory known as Premack’s Principle. Named after the work of professor David Premack, the principle states that “more probable behaviors will reinforce less probable behaviors.” In other words, even if you don’t really want to process overdue work emails, you’ll become conditioned to do it if it means you get to do something you really want to do along the way. You can even combine temptation bundling with the habit stacking strategy we discussed in Chapter 5 to create a set of rules to guide your behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1362</p>
<p>The habit stacking + temptation bundling formula is: After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [HABIT I NEED]. After [HABIT I NEED], I will [HABIT I WANT].</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1371</p>
<p>If you want to check Facebook, but you need to exercise more: After I pull out my phone, I will do ten burpees (need). After I do ten burpees, I will check Facebook (want).</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1378</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 2nd Law of Behavior Change is make it attractive. The more attractive an opportunity is, the more likely it is to become habit-forming. Habits are a dopamine-driven feedback loop. When dopamine rises, so does our motivation to act. It is the anticipation of a reward—not the fulfillment of it—that gets us to take action. The greater the anticipation, the greater the dopamine spike. Temptation bundling is one way to make your habits more attractive. The strategy is to pair an action you want to do with an action you need to do.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1414</p>
<p>one of the deepest human desires is to belong. And this ancient preference exerts a powerful influence on our modern behavior.</p>
<p>Note - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1415</p>
<p>利用归属感可以做很多事情，比如社群，宗教，Niche，小团体。 这也是做产品的方向</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1421</p>
<p>Most of the time, going along with the group does not feel like a burden. Everyone wants to belong. If you grow up in a family that rewards you for your chess skills, playing chess will seem like a very attractive thing to do. If you work in a job where everyone wears expensive suits, then you’ll be inclined to splurge on one as well. If all of your friends are sharing an inside joke or using a new phrase, you’ll want to do it, too, so they know that you “get it.” Behaviors are attractive when they help us fit in.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1425</p>
<p>We imitate the habits of three groups in particular: The close. The many. The powerful.</p>
<p>Note - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1427</p>
<p>模仿习惯的 3 个来源</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1510</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The culture we live in determines which behaviors are attractive to us. We tend to adopt habits that are praised and approved of by our culture because we have a strong desire to fit in and belong to the tribe. We tend to imitate the habits of three social groups: the close (family and friends), the many (the tribe), and the powerful (those with status and prestige). One of the most effective things you can do to build better habits is to join a culture where (1) your desired behavior is the normal behavior and (2) you already have something in common with the group. The normal behavior of the tribe often overpowers the desired behavior of the individual. Most days, we’d rather be wrong with the crowd than be right by ourselves. If a behavior can get us approval, respect, and praise, we find it attractive.</p>
<p>Bookmark - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1518</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1526</p>
<p>“It always starts with your friends. One friend smokes, then you try it.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1546</p>
<p>Some of our underlying motives include:* Conserve energy Obtain food and water Find love and reproduce Connect and bond with others Win social acceptance and approval Reduce uncertainty Achieve status and prestige</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1553</p>
<p>Find love and reproduce = using Tinder Connect and bond with others = browsing Facebook Win social acceptance and approval = posting on Instagram Reduce uncertainty = searching on Google Achieve status and prestige = playing video games</p>
<p>Note - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1556</p>
<p>每个习惯背后都对应着原始欲望,所以最好是替代</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1600</p>
<p>“I’m not confined to my wheelchair—I am liberated by it. If it wasn’t for my wheelchair, I would be bed-bound and never able to leave my house.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1605</p>
<p>Finance. Saving money is often associated with sacrifice. However, you can associate it with freedom rather than limitation if you realize one simple truth: living below your current means increases your future means. The money you save this month increases your purchasing power next month.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1633</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 2nd Law of Behavior Change is make it unattractive. Every behavior has a surface level craving and a deeper underlying motive. Your habits are modern-day solutions to ancient desires. The cause of your habits is actually the prediction that precedes them. The prediction leads to a feeling. Highlight the benefits of avoiding a bad habit to make it seem unattractive. Habits are attractive when we associate them with positive feelings and unattractive when we associate them with negative feelings. Create a motivation ritual by doing something you enjoy immediately before a difficult habit.</p>
<p>THE 3RD LAW: Make It Easy</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1666</p>
<p>Walk Slowly, but Never Backward</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1677</p>
<p>It is easy to get bogged down trying to find the optimal plan for change: the fastest way to lose weight, the best program to build muscle, the perfect idea for a side hustle. We are so focused on figuring out the best approach that we never get around to taking action. As Voltaire once wrote, “The best is the enemy of the good.”</p>
<p>Note - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1680</p>
<p>最好是好的敌人,想要最好就不会行动</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1684</p>
<p>Sometimes motion is useful, but it will never produce an outcome by itself. It doesn’t matter how many times you go talk to the personal trainer, that motion will never get you in shape. Only the action of working out will get the result you’re looking to achieve.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1693</p>
<p>Motion makes you feel like you’re getting things done. But really, you’re just preparing to get something done. When preparation becomes a form of procrastination, you need to change something. You don’t want to merely be planning. You want to be practicing.</p>
<p>Note - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1694</p>
<p>你永远不会准备好,准备是拖延的一种借口</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1742</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 3rd Law of Behavior Change is make it easy. The most effective form of learning is practice, not planning. Focus on taking action, not being in motion. Habit formation is the process by which a behavior becomes progressively more automatic through repetition. The amount of time you have been performing a habit is not as important as the number of times you have performed it.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 12: The Law of Least Effort &gt; Location 1851</p>
<p>When you wake up, making breakfast will be easy. Want to draw more? Put your pencils, pens, notebooks, and drawing tools on top of your desk, within easy reach. Want to exercise? Set out your workout clothes, shoes, gym bag, and water bottle ahead of time. Want to improve your diet? Chop up a ton of fruits and vegetables on weekends and pack them in containers, so you have easy access to healthy, ready-to-eat options during the week.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 12: The Law of Least Effort &gt; Location 1872</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Human behavior follows the Law of Least Effort. We will naturally gravitate toward the option that requires the least amount of work. Create an environment where doing the right thing is as easy as possible. Reduce the friction associated with good behaviors. When friction is low, habits are easy. Increase the friction associated with bad behaviors. When friction is high, habits are difficult. Prime your environment to make future actions easier.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1918</p>
<p>“When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do.” You’ll find that nearly any habit can be scaled down into a two-minute version: “Read before bed each night” becomes “Read one page.” “Do thirty minutes of yoga” becomes “Take out my yoga mat.” “Study for class” becomes “Open my notes.” “Fold the laundry” becomes “Fold one pair of socks.” “Run three miles” becomes “Tie my running shoes.”</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1922</p>
<p>培养从两分钟小习惯开始</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1922</p>
<p>The idea is to make your habits as easy as possible to start.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1923</p>
<p>新的习惯越简单越好,它很容易完成</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1924</p>
<p>this is a powerful strategy because once you’ve started doing the right thing, it is much easier to continue doing it.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1924</p>
<p>A new habit should not feel like a challenge.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1925</p>
<p>行的习惯不应该是挑战</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1943</p>
<p>People often think it’s weird to get hyped about reading one page or meditating for one minute or making one sales call. But the point is not to do one thing. The point is to master the habit of showing up. The truth is, a habit must be established before it can be improved.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1945</p>
<p>微小习惯最容易形成,并且会长大</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1998</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Habits can be completed in a few seconds but continue to impact your behavior for minutes or hours afterward. Many habits occur at decisive moments—choices that are like a fork in the road—and either send you in the direction of a productive day or an unproductive one. The Two-Minute Rule states, “When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do.” The more you ritualize the beginning of a process, the more likely it becomes that you can slip into the state of deep focus that is required to do great things. Standardize before you optimize. You can’t improve a habit that doesn’t exist.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2061</p>
<p>Unsubscribe from emails. Turn off notifications and mute group chats. Set your phone to silent. Use email filters to clear up your inbox. Delete games and social media apps on your phone.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2068</p>
<p>Enroll in an automatic savings plan. Set up automatic bill pay. Cut cable service. Ask service providers to lower your bills.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2070</p>
<p>Of course, there are many ways to automate good habits and eliminate bad ones. Typically, they involve putting technology to work for you. Technology can transform actions that were once hard, annoying, and complicated into behaviors that are easy, painless, and simple. It is the most reliable and effective way to guarantee the right behavior.</p>
<p>Note - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2073</p>
<p>通过自动化手段来消除坏习惯，比如取消游戏订阅</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2076</p>
<p>Medicine: Prescriptions can be automatically refilled. Personal finance: Employees can save for retirement with an automatic wage deduction. Cooking: Meal-delivery services can do your grocery shopping. Productivity: Social media browsing can be cut off with a website blocker.</p>
<p>Note - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2078</p>
<p>比如每天晚上自动断网</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2103</p>
<p>The inversion of the 3rd Law of Behavior Change is make it difficult. A commitment device is a choice you make in the present that locks in better behavior in the future. The ultimate way to lock in future behavior is to automate your habits. Onetime choices—like buying a better mattress or enrolling in an automatic savings plan—are single actions that automate your future habits and deliver increasing returns over time. Using technology to automate your habits is the most reliable and effective way to guarantee the right behavior.</p>
<p>THE 4TH LAW: Make It Satisfying</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2143</p>
<p>The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2173</p>
<p>We are more likely to repeat a behavior when the experience is satisfying. This is entirely logical. Feelings of pleasure—even minor ones like washing your hands with soap that smells nice and lathers well—are signals that tell the brain: “This feels good. Do this again, next time.” Pleasure teaches your brain that a behavior is worth remembering and repeating.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2176</p>
<p>赋予行为意义：打水不是麻烦而是锻炼？ 锻炼不是累而是享受生活？</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2191</p>
<p>The first three laws of behavior change—make it obvious, make it attractive, and make it easy—increase the odds that a behavior will be performed this time. The fourth law of behavior change—make it satisfying—increases the odds that a behavior will be repeated next time. It completes the habit loop.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2193</p>
<p>告诉自己从这个响应里得到了好处</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2234</p>
<p>What is immediately rewarded is repeated. What is immediately punished is avoided.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2235</p>
<p>有奖励的行为被重复，有惩罚的行为被抛弃</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2236</p>
<p>Our preference for instant gratification reveals an important truth about success: because of how we are wired, most people will spend all day chasing quick hits of satisfaction. The road less traveled is the road of delayed gratification. If you’re willing to wait for the rewards, you’ll face less competition and often get a bigger payoff. As the saying goes, the last mile is always the least crowded.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2238</p>
<p>少有人走的路不会拥挤，延迟满足往往有最大的回报</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2243</p>
<p>Here’s the problem: most people know that delaying gratification is the wise approach. They want the benefits of good habits: to be healthy, productive, at peace. But these outcomes are seldom top-of-mind at the decisive moment. Thankfully, it’s possible to train yourself to delay gratification—but you need to work with the grain of human nature, not against it. The best way to do this is to add a little bit of immediate pleasure to the habits that pay off in the long-run and a little bit of immediate pain to ones that don’t.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2246</p>
<p>人性就是立刻满足，我们不能与人性作对，所以需要一点技巧</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2261</p>
<p>One solution is to turn the situation on its head. You want to make avoidance visible. Open a savings account and label it for something you want—maybe “Leather Jacket.” Whenever you pass on a purchase, put the same amount of money in the account. Skip your morning latte? Transfer $5.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2263</p>
<p>开一个梦想账户，当你想买东西时，直接转入替代账户。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2266</p>
<p>One of my readers and his wife used a similar setup. They wanted to stop eating out so much and start cooking together more. They labeled their savings account “Trip to Europe.” Whenever they skipped going out to eat, they transferred $50 into the account. At the end of the year, they put the money toward the vacation.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2275</p>
<p>You do it because it’s who you are and it feels good to be you. The more a habit becomes part of your life, the less you need outside encouragement to follow through. Incentives can start a habit. Identity sustains a habit.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2281</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 4th Law of Behavior Change is make it satisfying. We are more likely to repeat a behavior when the experience is satisfying. The human brain evolved to prioritize immediate rewards over delayed rewards. The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change: What is immediately rewarded is repeated. What is immediately punished is avoided. To get a habit to stick you need to feel immediately successful—even if it’s in a small way. The first three laws of behavior change—make it obvious, make it attractive, and make it easy—increase the odds that a behavior will be performed this time. The fourth law of behavior change—make it satisfying—increases the odds that a behavior will be repeated next time.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2301</p>
<p>Making progress is satisfying, and visual measures—like moving paper clips or hairpins or marbles—provide clear evidence of your progress. As a result, they reinforce your behavior and add a little bit of immediate satisfaction to any activity. Visual measurement comes in many forms: food journals, workout logs, loyalty punch cards, the progress bar on a software download, even the page numbers in a book. But perhaps the best way to measure your progress is with a habit tracker.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2412</p>
<p>Chapter Summary One of the most satisfying feelings is the feeling of making progress. A habit tracker is a simple way to measure whether you did a habit—like marking an X on a calendar. Habit trackers and other visual forms of measurement can make your habits satisfying by providing clear evidence of your progress. Don’t break the chain. Try to keep your habit streak alive. Never miss twice. If you miss one day, try to get back on track as quickly as possible. Just because you can measure something doesn’t mean it’s the most important thing.</p>
<p>Note - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2417</p>
<p>Kindle 的连续读书多少天何尝不是一种习惯进度条呢？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 17: How an Accountability Partner Can Change Everything &gt; Location 2493</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 4th Law of Behavior Change is make it unsatisfying. We are less likely to repeat a bad habit if it is painful or unsatisfying. An accountability partner can create an immediate cost to inaction. We care deeply about what others think of us, and we do not want others to have a lesser opinion of us. A habit contract can be used to add a social cost to any behavior. It makes the costs of violating your promises public and painful. Knowing that someone else is watching you can be a powerful motivator.</p>
<p>Note - 17: How an Accountability Partner Can Change Everything &gt; Location 2498</p>
<p>对坏习惯进行监督与惩罚</p>
<p>ADVANCED TACTICS: How to Go from Being Merely Good to Being Truly Great</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 18: The Truth About Talent (When Genes Matter and When They Don’t) &gt; Location 2686</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The secret to maximizing your odds of success is to choose the right field of competition. Pick the right habit and progress is easy. Pick the wrong habit and life is a struggle. Genes cannot be easily changed, which means they provide a powerful advantage in favorable circumstances and a serious disadvantage in unfavorable circumstances. Habits are easier when they align with your natural abilities. Choose the habits that best suit you. Play a game that favors your strengths. If you can’t find a game that favors you, create one. Genes do not eliminate the need for hard work. They clarify it. They tell us what to work hard on.</p>
<p>Note - 18: The Truth About Talent (When Genes Matter and When They Don’t) &gt; Location 2692</p>
<p>选者你适合的领域</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2717</p>
<p>The human brain loves a challenge, but only if it is within an optimal zone of difficulty. If you love tennis and try to play a serious match against a four-year-old, you will quickly become bored. It’s too easy. You’ll win every point. In contrast, if you play a professional tennis player like Roger Federer or Serena Williams, you will quickly lose motivation because the match is too difficult.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2720</p>
<p>人喜欢挑战，但是没有胜率或者没有互动的挑战无法坚持</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2723</p>
<p>The Goldilocks Rule states that humans experience peak motivation when working on tasks that are right on the edge of their current abilities. Not too hard. Not too easy. Just right.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2724</p>
<p>要找到自己匹配的难度才更有动力</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2757</p>
<p>The greatest threat to success is not failure but boredom.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2757</p>
<p>对成功威胁最大的不是失败，而是无聊</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2790</p>
<p>The only way to become excellent is to be endlessly fascinated by doing the same thing over and over. You have to fall in love with boredom.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2791</p>
<p>如果你无法让它变的有趣，那你就必须爱上无聊</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2791</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The Goldilocks Rule states that humans experience peak motivation when working on tasks that are right on the edge of their current abilities. The greatest threat to success is not failure but boredom. As habits become routine, they become less interesting and less satisfying. We get bored. Anyone can work hard when they feel motivated. It’s the ability to keep going when work isn’t exciting that makes the difference. Professionals stick to the schedule; amateurs let life get in the way.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2796</p>
<p>成功的敌人不是失败，而是无趣与无聊，所以我们必须让它有趣。 做产品也是一样，必须一开始就有人用，有互动，有反馈，否则你坚持不下去的。一定要从一开始就有种子用户，开发中的时候就有一个群的人在期待。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 20: The Downside of Creating Good Habits &gt; Location 2938</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The upside of habits is that we can do things without thinking. The downside is that we stop paying attention to little errors. Habits + Deliberate Practice = Mastery Reflection and review is a process that allows you to remain conscious of your performance over time. The tighter we cling to an identity, the harder it becomes to grow beyond it.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Conclusion: The Secret to Results That Last &gt; Location 2982</p>
<p>That’s the power of atomic habits. Tiny changes. Remarkable results.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>改正一道粗心大意的错题只是临时解决了问题，培养仔细审题的习惯才能永久解决问题</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%94%B9%E6%AD%A3%E4%B8%80%E9%81%93%E7%B2%97%E5%BF%83%E5%A4%A7%E6%84%8F%E7%9A%84%E9%94%99%E9%A2%98%E5%8F%AA%E6%98%AF%E4%B8%B4%E6%97%B6%E8%A7%A3%E5%86%B3%E4%BA%86%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E5%9F%B9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%94%B9%E6%AD%A3%E4%B8%80%E9%81%93%E7%B2%97%E5%BF%83%E5%A4%A7%E6%84%8F%E7%9A%84%E9%94%99%E9%A2%98%E5%8F%AA%E6%98%AF%E4%B8%B4%E6%97%B6%E8%A7%A3%E5%86%B3%E4%BA%86%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E5%9F%B9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;当你在结果层面解决问题时，你只会暂时解决它们。为了取得良好的进步，你需要在系统层面解决问题。修复输入，输出将自行修复。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>当你在结果层面解决问题时，你只会暂时解决它们。为了取得良好的进步，你需要在系统层面解决问题。修复输入，输出将自行修复。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a People Magnet</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-to-become-a-people-magnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 01:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-to-become-a-people-magnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1---understanding-human-nature&#34;&gt;1 - Understanding human nature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are, above all, interested in themselves. Yup. Sorry. No matter who you are people will always be a thousand times more interested in themselves than in you. No judgment here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People’s actions are governed by self-interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every human relationship, your counterpart will always think or ask themselves “what’s in it for me?” Remember this question “What’s in it for me?” By the way, you’re asking this question in all your interactions too, consciously or subconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="1---understanding-human-nature">1 - Understanding human nature</h2>
<p>People are, above all, interested in themselves. Yup. Sorry. No matter who you are people will always be a thousand times more interested in themselves than in you. No judgment here.</p>
<p>People’s actions are governed by self-interest.</p>
<p>In every human relationship, your counterpart will always think or ask themselves “what’s in it for me?” Remember this question “What’s in it for me?” By the way, you’re asking this question in all your interactions too, consciously or subconsciously.</p>
<p>People are above all interested in themselves and not in you.</p>
<h2 id="2---the-most-important-subject-of-any-conversation">2 - The most important subject of any conversation</h2>
<p>The most important subject that anyone will want to talk about with you is… THEMSELVES.</p>
<p>when you talk with people about themselves, they will love you for your wise choice of subject. They will be totally fascinated by the subject and show an enormous interest.</p>
<p>When you are talking to people, forget about “I,” “my,” and “mine” for a while and substitute it with a word that will make you a very sought after conversational partner: The word “YOU.”</p>
<p>When you get from “I,” “my,” “mine,” to “YOU” and “YOUR” your power and influence will increase by a significant degree.</p>
<p>get them talking about themselves. Who doesn’t love to talk about themselves? If you can show true interest and get people to talk about themselves, they will like you a lot, so ask them lots of questions about themselves.</p>
<p>Stop talking about yourself and start talking about the person in front of you or get them to talk about themselves.</p>
<h2 id="3---make-people-feel-important">3 - Make people feel important</h2>
<p>The desire to be recognized. The desire to be important. The desire to be noticed. The desire to be “someone.” This is the most powerful motivator.</p>
<p>Give every person you meet the importance they deserve-which is almost definitely the importance YOU think YOU deserve. Don’t ignore them, don’t talk down on them. Make them feel important. Listen to them! If you don’t listen, they feel unimportant. Compliment them, but only if it’s a sincere compliment.</p>
<p>Don’t interrupt people. Make a short pause before answering. This gives them the feeling that you have listened closely and are interested in what they have to say.</p>
<p>Make people feel important, and they’ll always be on your side.</p>
<h2 id="4---the-most-important-characteristic-agree-with-people">4 - The most important characteristic: Agree with people.</h2>
<p>The most important characteristic: Agree with people.</p>
<p>Well, first of all, people like people who agree with them. Second, people don’t like people who disagree with them. Third, people don’t like being disagreed with. Am I right or am I right? Adopt the attitude of being agreeable. Learn to agree with people and let them know when you do so. Nod your head. Say “yes,” “right,” “I totally agree with you,” “I totally get you.”</p>
<p>“Any fool can disagree with people”<br>
我无常心,众心为心。</p>
<p>“Do I want to be right or do I want to be in peace?”</p>
<p>Agreeing with people, on the other hand, is a wise, intelligent and good decision, even more so when the other person is wrong.<br>
立场为先,不论对错</p>
<p>Don’t argue-even if you are right. Why? Easy: Nobody ever wins an argument. Both lose. One loses, and the other one loses even if he or she is right. You also don’t win a lot of friends by arguing, do you? Who wants to be with a person that argues all the time anyway?</p>
<p>Some people might even want to provoke you because they love fighting. They feed on fights. There’s a saying in Spain: “If one doesn’t want to fight, two won’t fight.” Ignore the fighters. Change the subject, Walk away. Whatever-You don’t want fighters as friends anyway.</p>
<p>If you make a mistake, admit it. It’s a sign of a strong person, and you’ll be admired for it as average and mediocre people don’t admit their mistakes.</p>
<p>Remember people like people who agree with them.</p>
<h2 id="5---how-to-make-people-like-you-immediately">5 - How to make people like you immediately</h2>
<p>&ldquo;You never get a second chance to make a first impression.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the first moment when the door opens, when you make eye contact, even before you say anything; give the person your most sincere smile. A smile can do miracles.</p>
<p>Smile at the baker, the butcher, in the subway, at the newspaper stand and see what happens. Smile even when you are talking on the phone! The person on the other end of the phone will notice it. Smiling is contagious, so in most cases, people will smile back and be nice to you.<br>
伸手不打笑脸人</p>
<p>is not only good for your relationships, but also for your health! Science has demonstrated that laughing or smiling a lot daily improves your mental state and creativity. It also alters your stress response in difficult situations by slowing down your heart rate and decreasing stress levels.</p>
<p>Smile and win in all relationships.</p>
<h2 id="6---how-to-make-a-good-impression">6 - How to make a good impression</h2>
<p>You can’t expect others to believe in you if you don’t believe in you, yet. Start being proud of yourself, of who you are, of where you come from, and of what you do for a living. This is not the time to be modest! Careful though. It’s also not the time to be arrogant. I’m talking about healthy self-esteem. Knowing who you are, knowing your strength, but also knowing that you are not better than anybody else (and remembering that nobody is better than you either).</p>
<p>Say only things you mean and mean the things you say. As I mentioned before, cheap compliments, empty promises, and meaningless words will always be discovered and cause the opposite effect of what you want to achieve.</p>
<p>Being overanxious makes people wonder, and they start doubting. “Why is he so anxious?”, “What does she have to hide?”</p>
<p>Never try to make yourself look good, by putting other people down. This makes you look bad and can damage your effort to make friends and influence people.</p>
<p>a person that treats you nicely and disrespects the waiter is not a nice person.</p>
<p>If you can’t say nice things, say nothing. Don’t put people down.</p>
<p>Other people’s opinion about us is primarily made by how we behave.</p>
<h2 id="7---how-to-connect-with-people">7 - How to connect with people</h2>
<p>One great way to connect with people is by being interested in them and in the things that interest them.<br>
有相同的爱好，玩一样的游戏</p>
<p>If you make an effort to study their interests, you’ll surely get good results. I know a lot of salespeople who know everything that can interest their client even before they meet them the first time in person. Those are also the most successful salespeople. They talk about the interests of their potential clients with true interest and then close the sale.</p>
<p>Be nice. Even on the phone. If you are smiling on the phone, the person on the other end of the line can feel it.</p>
<p>People can smell false praise and played interest from a mile away.</p>
<p>Show true interest in other people and succeed</p>
<h2 id="8---how-to-develop-an-attractive-personality">8 - How to develop an attractive personality</h2>
<p>One of the most important ingredients is Acceptance. You must accept people as they are. So simple and yet sometimes so complicated, right? To make it easier remember these things. People are not like you. They are not perfect (you also aren’t, and-even better-you don’t have to be!). You can’t change them no matter how hard you try. They might not have the same values as you and many times they won’t live up to your high expectations.<br>
你必须接受这帮傻逼,他们学不会和人平等交流。也不想改变自己的想法,你不要尝试改变他们。</p>
<p>Accept and like people just as they are.</p>
<p>Another ingredient is Approval. No matter how many faults somebody has, you can always find something to approve of.<br>
无论多么离谱的人,你也能找到角度来认可他</p>
<p>Appreciation. Next to love, appreciation is probably the most critical force in the universe. When do our marriages and jobs go sour? When we don’t appreciate them anymore.</p>
<p>Accept. Approve of. Appreciate. Use this formula to become a people magnet.</p>
<h2 id="9---its-what-they-want-not-what-you-want">9 - It’s what they want, not what you want</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 416</p>
<p>When you want to influence people always have in mind: It’s what they want, not what you want. I love the example Dale Carnegie put in his classic “How to make friends and influence people”: He loved strawberry and cream, but when he went fishing he didn’t use strawberries with cream to bait the fish, but worms. Fish want worms, not strawberries.</p>
<p>We have to put ourselves in their shoes and see things from their point of view. We have to make them really, really want what we have to offer them. We have to speak their language, use the words they would use and talk in terms of what they want.</p>
<p>The more you think about the needs and want of other people, the more successful relationships you will get. Be careful though and don’t forget your own needs and wants. Remember: It’s what they want, not what you want.<br>
人人都像你祈祷,你就是上帝,赐予他们想要的夸奖,赞美,倾听,认同</p>
<h2 id="10---listen-to-people-actively">10 - Listen to people actively</h2>
<p>One of the most critical skills of a “people magnet” is the ability and skill of &ldquo;active listening&rdquo; or listening profoundly. The more you listen, the smarter you will get. You will also be more liked, and people will love to have conversations with you. Why? Because you’ll be of a rare breed. Most people never listen.</p>
<p>A good listener will always have the advantage over a good talker because he or she always allows people to hear their favorite speaker in the world: themselves.</p>
<p>Listening profoundly means to listen to the person in front of you while giving them your full attention. Look at the person who is talking. Listen with your eyes, with your ears, with your whole body and keep looking at them. Nod your head to show them you are agreeing with their points, smile.</p>
<p>Lean towards the speaker. Show interest. Show them you don’t want to miss a single word. Ask questions. This will show the speaker that you are listening and will flatter him/her. It can be super simple questions like “and then what happened” or “and then what did you do?”</p>
<p>Quiet down the little voice in your head that comes up with advice and a solution thirty seconds after the person starts speaking. Don’t listen to answer. Listen to understand. If you are rehearsing what you are going to say next, you are not listening! Don’t interrupt the speaker until he or she is finished, or don’t just wait for your counterpart to pause so that you can begin to speak. Don’t change subjects. On the contrary ask for more.</p>
<p>If you want to give advice, ask for permission. Most of the time the person who is speaking will come up with the solution-if you let her or him finish.</p>
<p>Don’t forget using “you” and “your” instead of “me, my, mine.”</p>
<p>Try it! Becoming a good listener will take your conversations and relationships to an entirely new level. When people feel that you are listening to them, they will automatically like to be around you. Be a good listener!</p>
<h2 id="11--become-an-influencer">11- Become an influencer</h2>
<p>Influencing people means to get them to do what you want them to do. So, the logical first step will be to find out what will make them do it. You need to know what they want. You need to know what will motivate them, what will move them.</p>
<p>The biggest mistake we make when trying to influence people is that we think that other people like what we like, are motivated by things that motivate us, are after what we are after.<br>
爱好,欲望,信念</p>
<p>Everybody is different. Everyone has different values. Everyone likes different things, and everyone has different motivators.</p>
<p>To influence people, you need to find out what they want. Once you know what they want you can make them take action by telling them what they want to hear.</p>
<p>You show them how they can get what they want by doing what you want them to do. Yup. That’s manipulating at its best-so I hope dear reader that you just wish the best for the people you want to influence because this power-just like the power of electricity or the atom-can be used to create something beautiful, or to destroy. Choose wisely.</p>
<p>First of all, you will have to find out what people want, what they are looking for. If they want security, talk security. If they want to leave their day job, show them ways to leave their day job, if they want financial freedom, you talk financial freedom. The point is to find out what people want and then show them how to get what they want by doing what you want them to do (e.g., buy the course, buy the clothes, come to work for you, etc.).</p>
<p>If you are looking for a job, you would first find out what the employer is looking for, what abilities and responsibilities are needed for the job, and then you would show them that you can fill these needs better than anybody else.</p>
<p>When you know what somebody is looking for, you can talk the language they want to hear.</p>
<p>So, from now on listen very carefully to what people say, watch with great interest what they do and ask lots of questions. Make an effort to find out what people want and then use it to influence them.<br>
仔细倾听,找出他们的喜好欲望,并且加以利用</p>
<p>Find out what people want most.</p>
<h2 id="12---how-to-convince-people-real-quick">12 - How to convince people real quick</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 501</p>
<p>A great way to convince people is quoting someone. That’s why testimonials and opinions of others, in other words, social proof go a long, long way. Let somebody else speak for you even if the person is not present in the moment.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you are selling something and you are asked about the product quote a relevant customer opinion. In that case, your customer is answering the question although he or she isn’t there with you.</li>
<li>If somebody wants to know if you are paying your suppliers on time, you can mention how happy your other suppliers are with you paying their bills on time.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are applying for a job, mention all the good things your past employers and colleagues say about you.</p>
<p>It’s a psychological mystery. If you tell people directly about how great you are, they will be hugely skeptical, yet they don’t have any doubts that what you tell them is true if you tell them through third person’s testimonials.</p>
<p>Speak through third persons. Quote statistics and/or people. Relate facts. Tell success stories.</p>
<h2 id="13---get-people-to-say-yes-to-you">13 - Get people to say YES to you</h2>
<p>The ability that will boost the chances of getting people to say “yes” to you, and don’t forget: If you get them to say yes to you, you’ll get them to do whatever you want them to do.</p>
<h2 id="1-give-people-reasons-to-say-yes-to-you">1. Give people reasons to say yes to you</h2>
<h2 id="2-ask-yes-questions">2. Ask “yes” questions</h2>
<p>Do you want to be happy? Do you want to be independent? Do you want to live a life free from worries?</p>
<h2 id="3-give-them-a-choice-between-two-yeses-dont-give-people-a-choice-between-yes-and-no-let">3. Give them a choice between two yeses Don’t give people a choice between yes and no. Let</h2>
<p>When you are giving the other party a choice between yes and no, you might hear an awful lot of nos. It’s much better to not ask open questions. “Do you want the red or the black?” instead of “Do you want one of these?” “Do you want to start today or on Wednesday?” instead of “Do you want to start here?” “Do you want to pay cash or credit card?”, instead of “Do you want this?” I’m not saying that this will work every single time, but your success rate will increase. It will surely work a lot better than giving people a choice between answering yes or no.</p>
<h2 id="4-expect-people-to-say-yes-to-you">4. Expect people to say yes to you</h2>
<p>Get the easy yes, yes and yes and more yeses will come.</p>
<h2 id="14---talk-less-do-more">14 - Talk less, do more</h2>
<p>You are what you do, not what you say you’ll do.</p>
<p>People who just talk about the great things they will do for their friends, their company, their community and never follow up with action lose credibility and sooner or later nobody is going to take them seriously anymore.<br>
夸夸其谈之辈很快就会露馅</p>
<p>Talk less and convince the people around you by your actions.<br>
人狠话不多说更有威慑力</p>
<p>Stop talking and start doing. NOW.</p>
<h2 id="15---respect-other-peoples-opinions">15 - Respect other people’s opinions</h2>
<p>You won’t be right all the time. And even the times you are right, it’s a lot more beneficial for you not to prove others wrong.</p>
<p>It’s impossible to alter people’s opinions after having hurt their feelings.</p>
<p>Saying things like “I’m going to prove this to you” is like saying “I’m smarter than you and I’m going to prove it” and the only thing it will cause is opposition and will make it impossible to change your counterpart’s opinion.</p>
<p>Start by admitting that you could be wrong. It changes the whole conversations. You are admitting a mistake. “I might be wrong, but let’s look at it.”</p>
<p>Show respect for the other person&rsquo;s opinion. Put yourself in their shoes and try to understand them.</p>
<p>If you want to be right and have to point out other people’s mistakes all the time soon, you will be alone, and nobody will want to be around you.</p>
<p>Use diplomacy, be smart, be subtle. Don’t prove other people wrong</p>
<h2 id="16---be-authentic-be-transparent-be-you">16 - Be authentic. Be transparent. Be you!</h2>
<p>Don’t play any roles. Let people feel that what they see is what they get.<br>
人设早晚崩塌</p>
<p>Don’t put on a mask. Stop playing roles to please others. Stop faking and allow yourself to be you.<br>
不能同意,和前面几章明显矛盾。 我无常心,众心为心</p>
<h2 id="17---communicate-effectively">17 - Communicate effectively</h2>
<p>Get your counterpart to talk about themselves. Ask questions about the others’ interests like why? Where? How?</p>
<p>In a world where everybody continually wants to talk about themselves, listening is GOLD.</p>
<h2 id="18---the-deadly-sin-in-human-relations-you-need-to-avoid">18 - The deadly sin in human relations you need to avoid</h2>
<p>As humans, we are innately selfish.</p>
<p>You are human, so you will be tempted to talk about yourself. You want to shine. You want to be admired. You want to be acknowledged. You want to impress. Anyways, you are much better off to resist this temptation.<br>
开启上帝模式,跳出三界外,不玩地位 0 和游戏,赐予他们需要的东西吧</p>
<p>Do you want the other person’s permission for something? Do you want their business? Their goodwill? If you want any of this, keep the conversation focused on them.</p>
<p>If you want to be successful, let others do the talking about themselves and listen. Only talk about yourself when you are invited, or asked to do so. If others are interested in you, they will ask. If so, talk a little bit about yourself and then turn the focus back to them.</p>
<p>Don’t be selfish. Keep the focus on them.</p>
<h2 id="19---say-thank-you">19 - Say thank you!</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 683</p>
<p>I’m a huge fan of gratitude. I think it’s one of the most powerful forces in the universe and being very grateful not only brings good things into our lives, but it also makes us notice more and more of those that are already there.</p>
<p>It’s human nature to like and respond to people who appreciate us and show us gratitude.<br>
希望别人感恩与感激也是人性</p>
<p>Be grateful to people and show it to them with kind words or little gestures and you can be assured that it will come back to you multiplied.</p>
<p>Say it with joy. Maintain eye contact. It means a lot more when you look people that you thank in the eyes. Say “Thank you, Peter,” “Thank you, Mary.” Use people’s names. It makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Let the power of gratitude change your relationships and your life for the better.</p>
<h2 id="20---admit-your-mistakes">20 - Admit your mistakes</h2>
<p>If we want to build trust with people and influence them and want to be the real thing we have to find the strength of admitting our mistakes-even if it’s difficult. Don’t waste your energy making up excuses or justifications.</p>
<p>Admitting a mistake and taking the consequences takes much more strength than denial. And it’s much healthier. Instead of losing energy denying it, it will liberate you.</p>
<p>Admit your mistakes, but avoid repeating the same ones over and over again.</p>
<h2 id="21---stop-gossiping">21 - Stop gossiping</h2>
<p>I know, sometimes it’s very tempting to hear the latest rumors from other people. The problem is that most probably the person who tells you these rumors starts spreading rumors about you, once you turn your back on them.<br>
传别人闲话给你的人,也会传你的闲话</p>
<p>Stop gossiping. Everybody wants to be with a person of integrity.</p>
<h2 id="22---stop-judging">22 - Stop judging</h2>
<p>Judging and condemning others. People don’t want to be judged. Period. People want to be liked, made to feel important, and appreciated. Not judged.</p>
<p>Don’t judge people. Once you are tempted to judge, take a look at yourself and see if you have the flaws you judge in other people.</p>
<h2 id="23---forgive-everyone">23 - Forgive everyone</h2>
<p>The antidote to this is Forgiveness! To be a forgiving person is not only good for your relationships with other people, it’s also the fast track to success and happiness. This is not about being right or wrong; it’s about you being well and not wasting energy. Forgive even if it was the other party who wronged you. You are doing it for yourself!<br>
不要去记恨人渣,别让他们持续伤害你</p>
<p>Let them go, forgive them, forget them and move on.</p>
<p>Don’t be a fool! Forgive everyone and be fun to be around!</p>
<h2 id="24---keep-your-word">24 - Keep your word</h2>
<p>Remember a good reputation built over a long time can be destroyed in seconds.</p>
<p>If you talk a lot but don’t follow up with action, people will lose trust in you.</p>
<p>Never make promises you can’t keep and over-deliver on everything you do. If you say you are going to be somewhere, be there. Mean everything you say. No wishy-washy talk. If you don’t mean it, don’t say it. Do what you say you’re going to do. Never tell a lie. If you can’t, don’t or won’t do something, tell people the truth right away. Don’t play with people’s emotions. Don’t say things only to impress. Be authentic.</p>
<p>Don’t undermine your reputation and your self-worth. Tell the truth and keep your commitments.</p>
<h2 id="25---treat-others-as-you-would-like-others-to-treat-you">25 - Treat others as you would like others to treat you.</h2>
<p>Do unto others as you would have others do unto you.</p>
<h2 id="26---remember-peoples-names">26 - Remember people’s names</h2>
<p>Remember people’s names. You’ll make people feel more important, and most importantly you build better relationships and trust.</p>
<h2 id="27---avoid-arguments">27 - Avoid arguments</h2>
<p>Do you ever really, really win an argument? Yes? I don’t think so. You might have “won” the argument, but you surely lost your “opponents” sympathy.</p>
<p>You can’t win an argument. If you lose it, you lose it; if you win it, you also lose it. Why? Because you made the other party look inferior and might even have hurt their dignity. And yes. You probably haven’t changed their opinion anyway.</p>
<p>How many times did you win an argument with your boss? Did the promotion come right away, or are you still waiting? How many times did you win an argument against a client? Where you right? Yes? Did you win? Yes? Did he buy? Probably not. If possible concentrate on things you agree on instead of focusing on things on which you differ.<br>
争论不可能赢,赢了面子输掉里子</p>
<p>If someone wants to start an argument with you, agree with them. The blue car is better than the red one? Yes! You are right. Period. No room for an argument. It’s not a sign of weakness to avoid arguments. It’s a sign of strength. Remember, you can’t win anyway. If</p>
<p>instead of wasting your time arguing with them give them the feeling of significance and win their goodwill.</p>
<p>Avoid arguments. Save your time. You can’t afford to lose time arguing, nor can you afford to take the consequences.</p>
<p>remember not many people are able to admit mistakes.</p>
<p>Could they be right? What benefit will my reaction have? What price do I have to pay if I’m right? Is it better to be quiet? Where is the opportunity here? Avoid arguments. You can’t win them.</p>
<h2 id="28---praise-and-acknowledge-people-honestly-and-sincerely">28 - Praise and acknowledge people honestly and sincerely</h2>
<p>Praise the behavior, not the person. It will create an incentive for others to act the same way.<br>
夸他们做的事情,不要去直接夸奖人,会显得不真诚</p>
<p>Make saying kind things to at least three different people a daily habit.</p>
<h2 id="29---show-everyone-kindness-and-respect">29 - Show everyone kindness and respect</h2>
<p>Show every person you meet kindness and respect. Every person has a story as compelling and complicated as your own. Just as you are extraordinary, so are they.</p>
<p>Many times in my life, people I first thought of as “What a strange person” or “He doesn&rsquo;t seem to be very bright” have become my best friends. Meet people with kindness and respect and great things can come from it.</p>
<p>Every now and then you might end up disappointed when you are kind to people, and they don’t respond to it, or maybe even take advantage of you. Don’t let this change you. It’s not your problem; it’s theirs. It’s a price worth paying for meeting all the other great people who’ll come into your life.<br>
你肯定会遇到一些傻逼,别理他们就好</p>
<p>Remember: If somebody is rude to you, it’s their problem, not yours.</p>
<p>Show everyone kindness and respect. They deserve it. Even the &ldquo;bad&rdquo; ones.</p>
<h2 id="30---dont-give-direct-orders---be-more-subtle">30 - Don’t give direct orders - be more subtle</h2>
<p>People don’t like to be given direct orders. It goes against our nature. You can convince people much more subtly by asking questions like “Did you consider this option?” or “Do you think that would work?” or “What would you think of this?”, “Maybe this one would work better?”</p>
<p>Always give people the opportunity to get things done themselves.</p>
<p>Asking questions is not only a smoother way to get results it also stimulates the creativity of the person you ask. It’s much easier for people to accept a decision or an order if they at least feel that they had their part in the process.</p>
<p>Effective leaders use the power of questions instead of giving direct orders.</p>
<h2 id="31---believe-in-peoples-potential">31 - Believe in people’s potential</h2>
<p>Remind your employees of their outstanding work in the past, give them a vision of themselves they are eager to live up to, believe in them, and they will rise to the occasion.</p>
<p>You can easily lead people and make them trust you if you have their respect and you earn that respect by believing in them and showing respect for their abilities and their work.</p>
<p>Believe in the potential of people, and you will see miracles happen.</p>
<h2 id="32---be-an-example">32 - Be an example</h2>
<p>The best way of influencing others is by being an example. Treat other people how you want to be treated. Adopt the attitude you want other people to show you. You might have heard the theory that other persons are like a mirror towards us. Observe this fact closely!</p>
<p>You need to accept that you cannot change others. What you can do is to accept them as they are and be the best example and person that you can be.<br>
你不能改变任何人,只能让他们模仿你</p>
<p>Be the example of what you want to see in the world.</p>
<h2 id="33---remain-humble">33 - Remain Humble</h2>
<p>Remain Humble<br>
做人要谦虚</p>
<p>Humble people have a clear idea of their abilities and achievements; they acknowledge their flaws and admit mistakes and limitations. They are open to new ideas even if they don’t entirely agree with them. They appreciate the value of everything and accept there are many different ways that people can contribute to this world.<br>
不要固步自封</p>
<ul>
<li>Enjoying the lowly status of being an outsider and a nobody</li>
</ul>
<p>Remain humble and enjoy the advantages of it.</p>
<h2 id="34---let-the-other-person-come-up-with-your-idea">34 - Let the other person come up with your idea</h2>
<p>No one likes being sold on something or being told something. We want to feel that the decision was ours or that the idea was ours. We want people to ask us for our opinions, our wishes, and our thoughts. So, why not use this to your advantage?</p>
<p>The best way is always to plant the idea in somebody’s mind and let them think about it and meditate on it. Frequently, you will see the same person coming up with the same idea a couple of days later defending it as if it were their own idea. (I have to admit that this happens to me from time to time).<br>
别告诉他们你的你的想法,引导他们自己想出来</p>
<p>The easiest way to let the other person feel it was their idea is ASKING. When you make an offer, ask the client what he really needs, or ask them to complete your offer to themselves. If you go on a family vacation, ask your family where they want to go and come to a consensus. If you are going out with friends, ask them what they like best. If you go on date night with your spouse ask him or her, what they’d like to do. So easy and yet so difficult, right?</p>
<p>Ask and let the other person come up with your idea.</p>
<h2 id="35---be-on-time">35 - Be on time</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The while we keep a man waiting, he reflects on our shortcomings.” True or true?</p>
<h2 id="36---focus-on-the-other-persons-strengths">36 - Focus on the other person’s strengths</h2>
<p>Our focus determines our overall perception of the world.</p>
<p>So, if we focus on other people’s strengths what will happen? Yes. Exactly. We’ll see more of their strengths! Will that improve our personal relationships? You bet it will.</p>
<ul>
<li>What are their unique strengths? • What are you most proud of thinking of them? • What do they do best? • What are their most significant personal and professional accomplishments? • What gifts do they have? • What makes them unique and compelling?</li>
</ul>
<p>Focus on the other person’s strengths and see them in an entirely new way.</p>
<h2 id="37---dont-criticize">37 - Don’t criticize.</h2>
<p>Criticism is useless. The only thing it does is put a person on the defensive and makes them try to justify themselves.</p>
<p>The thought that criticism can improve something is old and outdated. Criticism only brings resentment and can demoralize family members, friends, colleagues, and employees.<br>
批评已经不好使了,对个人企业政府都不会有用</p>
<p>We all know people we want to lecture, improve, and change, but you know what? Forget it. It’s impossible to change other people unless they are the ones who want to change. What you can do is start with yourself. Be the change you want to see in others, be the role model; be the example.<br>
再强调一次,不要尝试用任何方法改变任何人。不可能成功</p>
<p>No good will come out of criticizing others. Swallow your criticism and work on yourself instead.</p>
<h2 id="40---a-great-way-to-give-feedback">40 - A great way to give feedback</h2>
<p>with the criticism that comes after the “BUT”. The feedback will lose its effectivity and maybe even credibility. You can easily avoid this using “and” instead of “but.”</p>
<h2 id="41---let-the-other-person-save-face">41 - Let the other person save face</h2>
<h2 id="41-let-the-other-person-save-face">41-Let the other person save face</h2>
<p>When somebody makes a mistake, let them save face.</p>
<h2 id="42---make-people-feel-happy-about-what-you-are-telling-them-to-do">42 - Make people feel happy about what you are telling them to do</h2>
<p>We don’t like to be told what to do. Period. Even if it’s from people close to us.</p>
<p>A brilliant way of rejecting offers or invitations is this one: 1. Express gratitude for the invitation 2. Show your honest regret that you can’t accept the job or the event 3. Suggest a substitute who can do the job instead of you</p>
<h2 id="44---recognize-the-worth-of-every-individual">44 - Recognize the worth of every individual</h2>
<p>The most common mistakes that damage relationships are the following: • Failure to give credit for suggestions • Failure to correct unfairness • Failure to praise and encourage • Criticizing people in front of others • Failure to ask employees their opinions • Failure to inform employees of their progress • Favoritism</p>
<p>Make people feel worthy by thinking that they are important. Yes, it’s that easy. If you are convinced that other people are important, your behavior will show it.</p>
<p>Remember. People want to feel important.</p>
<p>Notice people. Everybody wants to be noticed. When you notice somebody, you are paying them a big compliment. You&rsquo;re boosting their morale showing them “I recognize you.” And what happens then? People become friendlier, more helpful and better workers.</p>
<p>Recognize the worth of every individual, and you will win allies for life.</p>
<h2 id="45---talk-about-your-own-mistakes-first">45 - Talk about your own mistakes first.</h2>
<h2 id="45-talk-about-your-own-mistakes-first">45-Talk about your own mistakes first.</h2>
<p>Admit your mistakes-even if you haven’t corrected them yet-this makes you an authentic, honest person that people want to be around-because you are of a rare breed. In the best case, you can even convince somebody to change their behavior and not make the same mistakes you made.</p>
<p>Talk about your mistakes first and praise a lot-and people will want to hear your opinion and advice.</p>
<h2 id="46---be-nice">46 - Be nice</h2>
<p>My friend Manuel is the nicest guy you can imagine. Always helping, always smiling, people like to be around him. He has an immensely powerful network that he uses to help everyone, but when he notices people taking advantage of him, he tells them very clearly that they can now leave his inner circle and if they do any more bad stuff he will use the same network to destroy them.<br>
善良必需带刺</p>
<p>Be nice but don’t let other people fool you. Even nice people say “NO” or “enough is enough” every now and then.</p>
<h2 id="47---be-positive">47 - Be positive</h2>
<p>Be an optimist. Be positive in every interaction. It’s free, and people will seek your company.</p>
<h2 id="48---praise-and-praise-a-lot">48 - Praise and praise a lot!</h2>
<h2 id="48-praise-and-praise-a-lot">48-Praise and praise a lot!</h2>
<p>When you praise, go into details. “Good job” is not enough. Tell the person exactly what he or she is doing well and why it’s so crucial for you or your company. Remember, we all want real appreciation and praise, but it has to be sincere and genuine. The principles in this book only work when they are honest and come directly from your heart. Transform people’s lives by praising them.</p>
<h2 id="49---how-to-make-a-good-impression--2nd-part">49 - How to make a good impression | (2nd part)</h2>
<p>Don’t try too hard to make a good impression, but tell everyone around you that they are making a good impression.</p>
<h2 id="50--help-others-to-like-themselves-better-boost-their-self-esteem">50- Help others to like themselves better. Boost their self-esteem</h2>
<p>Make it a habit to see the good in people, to give them sincere compliments and watch how much better your relations with others become. Help them like themselves better.</p>
<h2 id="51---make-it-look-easy">51 - Make it look easy</h2>
<p>If you tell your kids, your spouse or your employees that they are too stupid to do a certain thing, not talented enough, that they’re doing it all wrong then you killed all their aspirations right there in the beginning-if they are unfortunate enough to believe you. On the other hand, if you use encouragement, make it seem easy, tell them that nobody is born a master at his craft and that with patience and consistency they can hone their skill and the outcome will look quite different.</p>
<p>Make it look easy and see people thrive.</p>
<h2 id="52---use-positive-talk">52 - Use positive talk</h2>
<p>Science has now found out that the way we talk about ourselves or events has a profound impact on our mindset and even our reality. People who tend to talk pessimistically in the morning tend to experience their day as much worse, while people who speak positively at the start of the day tend to experience their day as much more positive, meeting with much more opportunities. It’s not rocket science. We’ve all experienced it.</p>
<p>So cut the crap. Eliminate complaining, sarcasm and teasing from your conversations and use positive talk.<br>
少废话,戒讽刺挖苦,聊点爱听的</p>
<h2 id="54---write-a-thank-you-note">54 - Write a Thank you Note</h2>
<p>Show people that they are making the world a better place and write them a thank you note or a thank you email.</p>
<h2 id="55---beware-of-people-with-false-self-esteem">55 - Beware of people with false self-esteem</h2>
<p>Someone who walks into a room showing off, bragging, looking like a peacock, probably doesn’t have high self-esteem. In fact, this behavior is the exact opposite of healthy self-esteem. If we can choose, we really don’t want to be around this kind of people. To worsen matters, people with false self-esteem will always judge and value you-and themselves-by what you achieve and by your results, not for what you really are.</p>
<p>Stick around people with higher levels of self-esteem. Mostly, they are humble and don&rsquo;t need to show off continually.</p>
<p>Become a high self-esteem person and stay away from low self-esteem people except if you can be a role model for them.</p>
<h2 id="56---put-yourself-in-other-peoples-shoes">56 - Put yourself in other people&rsquo;s shoes</h2>
<h2 id="56-put-yourself-in-other-peoples-shoes">56-Put yourself in other people&rsquo;s shoes</h2>
<p>Empathy is one of the keys to success in our relationships with other people. It’s easy to judge and condemn people, any fool can do that. It’s a lot harder to try to understand them. If you have the patience and make an effort to understand them, to find out what makes them tick you can achieve anything and surely people will love to be around you.</p>
<h2 id="58---dont-make-assumptions">58 - Don’t make assumptions</h2>
<p>Stop making assumptions and start asking questions. It will change everything.</p>
<h2 id="59---dont-take-anything-personally">59 - Don’t take anything personally</h2>
<p>Whatever people say to you-the good or the bad-is none of your business. Only YOU have to know who you are. Get over the need to be right. Remember what you want: To be right or to be in peace? Be smart. Choose peace.</p>
<p>Save yourself some suffering and don’t take anything personally.<br>
天要下雨,由他去吧</p>
<h2 id="60---stop-spending-time-with-the-wrong-people">60 - Stop spending time with the wrong people</h2>
<p>Stop spending time with the wrong people</p>
<p>if you meet somebody that just doesn’t like you, think to yourself. “Well, I guess this is just one from the other 50%” and move on. And even more important: don’t try to change yourself so that they like you or spend time with you. It’s useless.</p>
<p>Life is too short to spend time with people who don’t treat you with love and respect. Let them go and make new friends.<br>
生命短暂,远离傻逼坏逼</p>
<h2 id="62---solve-your-problems-right-away">62 - Solve your problems right away</h2>
<p>Did you ever notice that some people spend more time and energy avoiding and dancing around their problems, blaming others for them, than in trying to solve them?<br>
抱怨没用,解决问题<br>
Conclusion</p>
<p>Your attitude will be crucial. Keep a positive mindset even when things don&rsquo;t go that well. Remember, sometimes when we are working towards a goal we get tested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Master The Game</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/money-master-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/money-master-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The largest financial institutions are set up to make a profit for themselves, not their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I really want? (Vision.) 2. What is important about it? (Values.) 3. How will I get it? (Methods.) 4. What is preventing me from having it? (Obstacles.) 5. How will I know I am successful? (Measurements.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is certainly one of the ways we can turn the dreams we have into the reality we live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The largest financial institutions are set up to make a profit for themselves, not their clients.</p>
<ol>
<li>What do I really want? (Vision.) 2. What is important about it? (Values.) 3. How will I get it? (Methods.) 4. What is preventing me from having it? (Obstacles.) 5. How will I know I am successful? (Measurements.)</li>
</ol>
<p>Money is certainly one of the ways we can turn the dreams we have into the reality we live.</p>
<p>success leaves clues. People who succeed at the highest level are not lucky; they’re doing something differently than everyone else does.</p>
<p>I’ll put you in the room with these and many other superstars who get consistent results, decade after decade, in up markets and down, booms and busts. Together we will uncover the core secrets to their investment success and see how to apply them even to the smallest amount of money.</p>
<p>The idea is to know how to survive and thrive in any market condition. These real experts will explain how.<br>
Bookmark - Location 714</p>
<p>they can anticipate the road ahead. Remember this: anticipation is the ultimate power.</p>
<p>This book is committed to one primary outcome: to set you up so you have an income for life without ever having to work again. Real financial freedom! And the good news is, it can be achieved by anyone.</p>
<p>It is not realistic to finance a 30-year retirement with 30 years of work. You can’t expect to put 10% of your income aside and then finance a retirement that’s just as long.</p>
<p>No matter where you live, if you don’t have another source of income, you could end up the best-dressed greeter at Wal-Mart.</p>
<p>It’s an amazing feeling to know you’ll never run out of income.</p>
<p>We know we need to save more and invest. So why don’t we do it? What’s holding us back?</p>
<p>SECTION 1: WELCOME TO THE JUNGLE: THE JOURNEY BEGINS WITH THIS FIRST STEP</p>
<p>SECTION 2: BECOME THE INSIDER: KNOW THE RULES BEFORE YOU GET IN THE GAME</p>
<p>SECTION 3: WHAT’S THE PRICE OF YOUR DREAMS? MAKE THE GAME WINNABLE</p>
<p>SECTION 4: MAKE THE MOST IMPORTANT INVESTMENT DECISION OF YOUR LIFE</p>
<p>SECTION 5: UPSIDE WITHOUT THE DOWNSIDE: CREATE A LIFETIME INCOME PLAN</p>
<p>SECTION 6: INVEST LIKE THE .001%: THE BILLIONAIRE’S PLAYBOOK</p>
<p>SECTION 7: JUST DO IT, ENJOY IT, AND SHARE IT</p>
<p>Compound interest is such a powerful tool that Albert Einstein once called it the most important invention in all of human history.</p>
<p>200 years after Franklin’s death, a period of time that had seen stocks grow at an average compounded rate of 8%,</p>
<p>our earned income will never bridge the gap between where we are and where we really want to be. Because earned income can never compare to the power of compounding! Money is better than poverty, if only for financial reasons.</p>
<p>Before you speak, listen. Before you write, think. Before you spend, earn. Before you invest, investigate. Before you criticize, wait. Before you pray, forgive. Before you quit, try. Before you retire, save. Before you die, give.</p>
<p>You have to move from just working for money to a world where money works for you.</p>
<p>You’re already a financial trader. You might not think of it in just this way, but if you work for a living, you’re trading your time for money. Frankly, it’s just about the worst trade you can make. Why? You can always get more money, but you can’t get more time.</p>
<p>If you stop working, you stop making money. So let’s take you out of the equation and look for an alternative approach. Let’s build a money machine to take your place—and, let’s set it up in such a way that it makes money while you sleep.</p>
<p>the most important financial decision of your life. The decision? What portion of your paycheck you get to keep. How much will you pay yourself—off the top, before you spend a single dollar on your day-to-day living expenses?</p>
<p>Whatever that number is, you’ve got to stick to it. In good times and bad. No matter what. Why? Because the laws of compounding punish even one missed contribution.</p>
<p>Can anybody remember when the times were not hard and money not scarce?</p>
<p>But here’s the key to success: you have to make your savings automatic.</p>
<p>It’s time to take the first of the 7 Simple Steps to your Financial Freedom! The most important financial decision of your life needs to be made right now! It’s time for you to decide to become an investor, not just a consumer. To do this, you simply have to decide what percentage of your income you will set aside for you and your family and no one else.</p>
<p>If you don’t want to work, you have to work to earn enough money so that you won’t have to work.</p>
<p>The bottom line is, if we feel like we’re losing something, we avoid it; we won’t do it. That’s why so many people don’t save and invest. Saving sounds like you’re giving something up, you’re losing something today. But you’re not. It’s giving yourself a gift today of peace of mind, of certainty, of the large fortune in your future.</p>
<p>Obviously money meant very different things for Adolf Merckle and Chuck Feeney. What does money really mean to you? Do you use money, or does money use you? Like I’ve said from the beginning: if you don’t master money, at some level, it’s going to master you.</p>
<p>Whatever emotion you’re after, whatever vehicle you pursue—building a business, getting married, raising a family, traveling the world—whatever you think your nirvana is, I have found it’s only an attempt by your brain to meet one or more of six human needs.</p>
<p>“What’s the secret to wealth?” And he said, “Tony, you know it, and you know it well. You teach it to everyone. It’s gratitude.”</p>
<p>BECOME THE INSIDER: KNOW THE RULES BEFORE YOU GET IN THE GAME</p>
<p>You have to learn the rules of the game, and then you have to play better than anyone else.</p>
<p>Whether you are a seasoned investor or just beginning to see yourself as an investor, the jungle that Ray Dalio so vividly described holds the same dangers for all of us. But most of the danger lies in the fact that what you don’t know can hurt you.</p>
<p>Money Power Principle 1. Don’t get in the game unless you know the rules!</p>
<p>But the system isn’t set up for your broker to have endless options and complete autonomy in finding what’s best for you. And this could prove costly.</p>
<p>Risk comes from not knowing what you’re doing.</p>
<p>The core concept of successful investing is simple: Grow your savings to a point at which the interest from your investments will generate enough income to support your lifestyle without having to work.</p>
<p>There are two phases to your investing game: the accumulation phase, in which you are socking away money for growth, and the decumulation, during which you are withdrawing income.</p>
<p>The goal of the nonprofessional should not be to pick winners—neither he nor his “helpers” can do that—but should rather be to own a cross section of businesses that in aggregate are bound to do well. A low-cost S&amp;P 500 index fund will achieve this goal.</p>
<p>When you look at the results on an after-fee, after-tax basis, over reasonably long periods of time, there’s almost no chance that you end up beating the index fund.<br>
Note - Location 1705<br>
中国特色股市除外</p>
<p>From 1984 to 1998, a full 15 years, only eight out of 200 fund managers beat the Vanguard 500 Index. (The Vanguard 500, put together by founder Jack Bogle, is a mirror image of the S&amp;P 500 index.)</p>
<p>Just how badly does chasing performance hurt us? Over a 20-year period, December 31, 1993, through December 31, 2013, the S&amp;P 500 returned an average annual return of 9.28%. But the average mutual fund investor made just over 2.54%, according to Dalbar, one of the leading industry research firms. Ouch! A nearly 80% difference.</p>
<p>Because we buy high and sell low. We follow our emotions (or our broker’s recommendations) and jump from fund to fund. Always looking for an edge. But when the market falls, when we can’t take the emotional pain any longer, we sell. And when the market is up, we buy more.</p>
<p>As a famous money manager named Barton Biggs observed, “A bull market is like sex. It feels best just before it ends.”</p>
<p>The goal in investing is to get the maximum net return for a given amount of risk (and, ideally, the lowest cost).</p>
<p>Life isn’t about waiting for the storm to pass; it’s about learning to dance in the rain. It’s about removing the fear in this area of your life so you can focus on what matters most.</p>
<ul>
<li>Stocks have by far been the best place to be for long-term growth over time. • Stocks are volatile. In the pages ahead, you will learn from the “market masters” how to “smooth out the ride” by investing in and diversifying across multiple different indexes. • Don’t be sold that someone is going to beat the market. Instead, align yourself with the market! Once you put your indexing plan in place (which we will do step by step), you won’t have to spend your time trying to pick which stock to buy because the index will have done it for you. This will save you a tremendous amount of time and angst in trying to pick a winner. • Begin to think like an insider! Never again will you tolerate the “herd” mentality in your own life.</li>
</ul>
<p>MYTH 2: “OUR FEES? THEY’RE A SMALL PRICE TO PAY!”</p>
<p>The mutual fund industry is now the world’s largest skimming operation, a $7 trillion trough from which fund managers, brokers, and other insiders are steadily siphoning off an excessive slice of the nation’s household, college, and retirement savings.”</p>
<p>You put up the capital, you took all the risk, and they made money no matter what happened.<br>
Note - Location 1960<br>
基金经理</p>
<p>MYTH 3: “OUR RETURNS? WHAT YOU SEE IS WHAT YOU GET”</p>
<p>Most people are familiar with the boilerplate disclaimer that past performance doesn’t guarantee future results. Far fewer are aware of how past performance numbers themselves can be misleading.</p>
<p>So if the fund advertises a 6% return, its investors achieved closer to 3%.</p>
<p>“Follow the money. Always follow the money.”</p>
<p>MYTH 4: “I’M YOUR BROKER, AND I’M HERE TO HELP”</p>
<p>“It is difficult to get a man to understand something, when his salary depends on his not understanding it.”</p>
<p>THE CHEF DOESN’T EAT HIS OWN COOKING</p>
<p>it was found that 49% of the managers owned no shares in the fund they manage. That’s right. The chef doesn’t eat his own cooking.</p>
<p>So the obvious question is, if the people who manage the fund aren’t investing in the fund they run, why in the world would I? Good question!!! The chef doesn’t eat his own cooking if the ingredients are bad or if he knows what the kitchen really looks and smells like. These fund managers are smart—they work under the hood.</p>
<p>MYTH 6: TARGET-DATE FUNDS: “JUST SET IT AND FORGET IT”</p>
<p>MYTH 7: “I HATE ANNUITIES, AND YOU SHOULD TOO”</p>
<p>MYTH 8: “YOU GOTTA TAKE HUGE RISKS TO GET BIG REWARDS!”</p>
<p>Remember Warren Buffett’s top two rules of investing? Rule 1: don’t lose money! Rule 2: see rule 1.</p>
<p>allow you and me to participate in the gains of the stock market without risking any of our principal!</p>
<p>But here’s the truth: the ultimate thing that stops most of us from making significant progress in our lives is not somebody else’s limitations, but rather our own limiting perceptions or beliefs.</p>
<p>Everybody has a fear of failure at some level; at times we’ve all been fearful that perhaps we are not enough.</p>
<p>Money is nothing more than a reflection of your creativity, your capacity to focus, and your ability to add value and receive back.</p>
<p>I want you to know that you’re the creator of your life, not just a manager. Sometimes</p>
<p>The day you stop racing is the day you win the race.</p>
<p>You can make them more conservative or more aggressive. You’re in control, so put in numbers that fit with your lifestyle, your current reality, and your future dreams.</p>
<p>One of the most powerful ways to accelerate the pace at which you achieve your financial goals—and the most painless way I know—is to implement the Save More Tomorrow plan,</p>
<p>She had left out a huge piece of future earnings, one that many people neglect to include in their financial planning: Social Security.</p>
<p>And yet contrast is a beautiful thing. When you get around people who are playing the game of life at a higher level, you either get depressed, pissed off, or inspired.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 1. SAVE MORE AND INVEST THE DIFFERENCE</p>
<p>If everything seems under control, you’re not going fast enough.</p>
<p>The goal of these next minichapters is to get you thinking about how to make your financial dreams come true faster than you ever thought possible.</p>
<p>You can be rich by having more than you need, or by needing less than you have.</p>
<p>the best strategy to get around your belief system is to develop a new belief!</p>
<p>What if—in one fell swoop, in one single move—you could save a huge chunk of money toward your Financial Freedom, and it wouldn’t cost you a dime more?</p>
<p>You want to know the banker’s secret? Your interest payments will tack on an additional 100% or more to your loan value.</p>
<p>Prepay your next month’s principal, and you could pay off a 30-year mortgage in 15 years in many cases! Does that mean double your monthly payments? No, not even close! Here’s the key: Money Power Principle 3. Cut your mortgage payments in half! The next time you write your monthly mortgage check, write a second check for the principal-only portion of next month’s payment.</p>
<p>Take your $4 habit and boost it to $10 a day, and now you’re drinking away over $141,250 in savings over 20 years. That’s the cost of a four-year college education!</p>
<p>At the end of the day, the question to ask yourself is this: Do my expenses, big and small, bring me the thrill they once did?</p>
<p>“How do you truly become more valuable? Learn to work harder on yourself than you do on your job.</p>
<p>“All you have to do to earn more money in the same amount of time is simply become more valuable.”</p>
<p>And if you employ yourself, your raise becomes effective when you are!</p>
<p>“For things to change, you have to change. For things to get better, you have to get better.”</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 3. REDUCE FEES AND TAXES (AND INVEST THE DIFFERENCE)</p>
<p>Remember you get to spend only what you keep; if you invest with a 3% net return, it takes 24 years to double your money.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 4. GET BETTER RETURNS AND SPEED YOUR WAY TO VICTORY</p>
<p>If you’re prepared, and you know what it takes, it’s not a risk. You just have to figure out how to get there. There is always a way to get there.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 5. CHANGE YOUR LIFE—AND LIFESTYLE—FOR THE BETTER</p>
<p>My favorite things in life don’t cost any money. It’s really clear that the most precious resource we all have</p>
<p>Never test the depth of the river with both feet.</p>
<p>Asset allocation is the most important investment decision of your lifetime,</p>
<p>He told me that there are only three tools for reducing your risk and increasing your potential for financial success: 1. Security selection—stock picking; 2. Market timing—short-term bets on the direction of the market; and 3. Asset allocation—your long-term strategy for diversified investing.</p>
<p>It means dividing up your money among different classes, or types, of investments (such as stocks, bonds, commodities, or real estate) and in specific proportions that you decide in advance, according to your goals or needs, risk tolerance, and stage of life.</p>
<p>good people often fail because they do the right thing at the wrong time.</p>
<p>I don’t gamble, because winning a hundred dollars doesn’t give me great pleasure. But losing a hundred dollars pisses me off.</p>
<p>when you buy shares of an ETF, you are not buying the actual stocks, bonds, commodities, or whatever else is bundled in the fund—you are buying shares in an investment fund that owns those assets.</p>
<p>if you have your money machine in full gear, and you have the desire, there’s nothing wrong with setting aside a tiny percent of your Risk/Growth Bucket to pick some stocks and do some day trading. “Index your important money, then go have fun,” Burton Malkiel told me. “It’s better than going to the racetrack.” But, he said, limit yourself to 5% or less of your total assets or portfolio.</p>
<p>What if I put my money in the stock market at its peak, and it starts dropping? Or if I buy into a bond fund, and the interest rates begin to spike? Markets are always going to fluctuate, and we’ve learned that nobody, I mean nobody, can consistently and successfully predict when it’s going to happen. So how do we protect ourselves from all the ups and downs and really succeed?</p>
<p>“We tend to put money into the market and take it out at exactly the wrong time.”</p>
<p>Nobody could guess that the US government would do something that no government has ever done in human history—it decided to prop up the markets by “printing” $4 trillion, while telling the world that it would continue to do so indefinitely, literally until the economy recovered!</p>
<p>if you think you can time the markets, you’re wrong.</p>
<p>Far more money has been lost by investors preparing for corrections, or trying to anticipate corrections, than has been lost in corrections themselves.</p>
<p>Remember, the goal is to take emotion out of investing because emotion is what so often destroys investing success, whether it’s greed or fear.</p>
<p>You can actually make higher returns by investing regularly in a volatile stock market.</p>
<p>to be a successful investor, you need to rebalance your portfolio at regular intervals.</p>
<p>allocation is everything! So you want to diversify between your Security Bucket and your Risk/Growth Bucket. You want to diversify across asset classes, markets, and time. 2. You don’t want to hesitate to get in the market trying to have perfect timing; instead, use dollar-cost averaging and know that volatility can be your friend, providing opportunities to buy investments cheaply when the market is down. This technique will increase your portfolio’s value when the markets come back up. 3. Have a Dream Bucket that gives you emotional juice and excitement so you can experience the benefits of your investing prowess in the short term and midterm instead of just someday far in the future. 4. Use rebalancing and tax harvesting to maximize your returns and minimize losses.</p>
<p>Here is the reality: most people couldn’t stomach another 2008 without selling some or all of their investments.</p>
<p>Remember, a 66% loss would require nearly 200% gains just to get back to even—just to recoup the portion of your nest egg that it may have taken your entire life to save!</p>
<p>FREEDOM: CREATING YOUR LIFETIME INCOME PLAN</p>
<p>I have enough money to retire comfortably for the rest of my life. Problem is, I have to die next week.</p>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>No matter what anyone tells you, or sells you, there isn’t a single portfolio manager, broker, or financial advisor who can control the primary factor that will determine if our money will last.</p>
<p>you are dead, who cares?! What’s painful is if you live too long with no income—that’s when you’ll really suffer.”</p>
<p>The key to abundance is meeting limited circumstances with unlimited thoughts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023个人认为获取幸福感的最佳方式</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E8%AE%A4%E4%B8%BA%E8%8E%B7%E5%8F%96%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%84%9F%E7%9A%84%E6%9C%80%E4%BD%B3%E6%96%B9%E5%BC%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 15:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E8%AE%A4%E4%B8%BA%E8%8E%B7%E5%8F%96%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%84%9F%E7%9A%84%E6%9C%80%E4%BD%B3%E6%96%B9%E5%BC%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;个人觉得获得幸福的最佳方法是把生活从网络游戏变成单机游戏。网络游戏比如吃鸡或者王者农药，你需要比别人技术好，装备比别人牛，连皮肤都要比一比。强中自有强中手，你失意是大概率事件。但是如果我们把生活换成单机游戏呢？比如塞尔达，你只要和自己比就可以了。每一步都幸福感满满。投射到现实就是，身材要比别人好，房子要比别人大，车子要比别人豪。 天天想着当人上人，要压过别人，注定很难幸福。个人认为正确的方法是：买了房不用老搬家了，开心。 买了车不用挤地铁了，开心。买了洗碗机不用洗碗了，开心&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>个人觉得获得幸福的最佳方法是把生活从网络游戏变成单机游戏。网络游戏比如吃鸡或者王者农药，你需要比别人技术好，装备比别人牛，连皮肤都要比一比。强中自有强中手，你失意是大概率事件。但是如果我们把生活换成单机游戏呢？比如塞尔达，你只要和自己比就可以了。每一步都幸福感满满。投射到现实就是，身材要比别人好，房子要比别人大，车子要比别人豪。 天天想着当人上人，要压过别人，注定很难幸福。个人认为正确的方法是：买了房不用老搬家了，开心。 买了车不用挤地铁了，开心。买了洗碗机不用洗碗了，开心&hellip;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一定要注意身体。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%B8%80%E5%AE%9A%E8%A6%81%E6%B3%A8%E6%84%8F%E8%BA%AB%E4%BD%93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 09:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%B8%80%E5%AE%9A%E8%A6%81%E6%B3%A8%E6%84%8F%E8%BA%AB%E4%BD%93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;人在不健康的状态，不仅严重影响生活，还会变得脆弱。很多困难平时咬咬牙扛过去了，身体不健康人的心理就很容易崩溃。年轻时没人把身体当回事，等透支出问题了，才追悔莫及。&lt;br&gt;
身体有小毛病，定期体检，积极治疗。失去了健康，活着就是一种折磨。不健康，你拥有再多也意义不大。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>人在不健康的状态，不仅严重影响生活，还会变得脆弱。很多困难平时咬咬牙扛过去了，身体不健康人的心理就很容易崩溃。年轻时没人把身体当回事，等透支出问题了，才追悔莫及。<br>
身体有小毛病，定期体检，积极治疗。失去了健康，活着就是一种折磨。不健康，你拥有再多也意义不大。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>浪费时间是最大的痛苦</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B5%AA%E8%B4%B9%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E6%98%AF%E6%9C%80%E5%A4%A7%E7%9A%84%E7%97%9B%E8%8B%A6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B5%AA%E8%B4%B9%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E6%98%AF%E6%9C%80%E5%A4%A7%E7%9A%84%E7%97%9B%E8%8B%A6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time-Related Pains Most productivity-related issues cause temporal pain: people feel like they’re wasting time. These pains are caused by suboptimal processes and friction between tasks. If tedious work takes a lot of time, it keeps you from doing important and useful things instead. That leads to time mismanagement and relevant actions not being taken. By solving the time-related problem, productive tasks can be accomplished faster and sooner. When people complain about inefficiencies, tedium, or pointless work, you’re looking at a time-related problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time-Related Pains Most productivity-related issues cause temporal pain: people feel like they’re wasting time. These pains are caused by suboptimal processes and friction between tasks. If tedious work takes a lot of time, it keeps you from doing important and useful things instead. That leads to time mismanagement and relevant actions not being taken. By solving the time-related problem, productive tasks can be accomplished faster and sooner. When people complain about inefficiencies, tedium, or pointless work, you’re looking at a time-related problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reputation What parts of your skill set do you need to</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/reputation-what-parts-of-your-skill-set-do-you-need-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/reputation-what-parts-of-your-skill-set-do-you-need-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Efficiency What keeps you from being more efficient at work? Why can’t you do more of what you do? Which tasks feel like they are a drag?&lt;br&gt;
Effectiveness What limits you from doing your job the right way? Which tasks are the most pointless? What annoys you about working with competitive products? What is your experience like with each of them?&lt;br&gt;
Financials Where are you spending too much on tools? Where are you spending too much on consulting? What is your budget for software tools? What is your budget for outsourcing work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Efficiency What keeps you from being more efficient at work? Why can’t you do more of what you do? Which tasks feel like they are a drag?<br>
Effectiveness What limits you from doing your job the right way? Which tasks are the most pointless? What annoys you about working with competitive products? What is your experience like with each of them?<br>
Financials Where are you spending too much on tools? Where are you spending too much on consulting? What is your budget for software tools? What is your budget for outsourcing work?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>从一个目标中，你通常可以推断出一个阻碍他成功之路的问题</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BB%8E%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E7%9B%AE%E6%A0%87%E4%B8%AD%E4%BD%A0%E9%80%9A%E5%B8%B8%E5%8F%AF%E4%BB%A5%E6%8E%A8%E6%96%AD%E5%87%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E9%98%BB%E7%A2%8D%E4%BB%96%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 08:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BB%8E%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E7%9B%AE%E6%A0%87%E4%B8%AD%E4%BD%A0%E9%80%9A%E5%B8%B8%E5%8F%AF%E4%BB%A5%E6%8E%A8%E6%96%AD%E5%87%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E9%98%BB%E7%A2%8D%E4%BB%96%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a goal, you can usually infer a problem that is in the way of your customers&amp;rsquo; path to success. Solve that problem, and you can help everyone in the niche reach their goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From a goal, you can usually infer a problem that is in the way of your customers&rsquo; path to success. Solve that problem, and you can help everyone in the niche reach their goals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The better you define your niche market, the more confident you can be in your numbers.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-better-you-define-your-niche-market-the-more-confident-you-can-be-in-your-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 08:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-better-you-define-your-niche-market-the-more-confident-you-can-be-in-your-numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shared interests will allow you to speak to the needs of your niche audience directly. Creating content that has a lot of impact and will be read by a lot of people will be easier, as there is less competition for your audience’s attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shared interests will allow you to speak to the needs of your niche audience directly. Creating content that has a lot of impact and will be read by a lot of people will be easier, as there is less competition for your audience’s attention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>选择正确的方向会更轻松</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9%E6%AD%A3%E7%A1%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E4%BC%9A%E6%9B%B4%E8%BD%BB%E6%9D%BE/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 08:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9%E6%AD%A3%E7%A1%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E4%BC%9A%E6%9B%B4%E8%BD%BB%E6%9D%BE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bootstrapped business works best when it starts out in a niche. Most companies will do really well by just staying there. Some expand into other markets. But that initial audience is one of the most important things to carefully select when you start a business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A bootstrapped business works best when it starts out in a niche. Most companies will do really well by just staying there. Some expand into other markets. But that initial audience is one of the most important things to carefully select when you start a business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>总被领导派去做杂活怎么办？</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%80%BB%E8%A2%AB%E9%A2%86%E5%AF%BC%E6%B4%BE%E5%8E%BB%E5%81%9A%E6%9D%82%E6%B4%BB%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E5%8A%9E/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 01:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%80%BB%E8%A2%AB%E9%A2%86%E5%AF%BC%E6%B4%BE%E5%8E%BB%E5%81%9A%E6%9D%82%E6%B4%BB%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E5%8A%9E/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;先做个分类，核心 KPI 占用时间精力至少 60%以上。如果其他的杂活占用高于这个，就和领导沟通一下。不要抱怨活多，而是和领导说，担心影响核心 KPI 的完成度与质量。&lt;br&gt;
通常领导有临时的杂活给你，多半不会考虑到你的工作量，可能就是随手指派的，或者他觉得交给你还 OK，不能惯。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>先做个分类，核心 KPI 占用时间精力至少 60%以上。如果其他的杂活占用高于这个，就和领导沟通一下。不要抱怨活多，而是和领导说，担心影响核心 KPI 的完成度与质量。<br>
通常领导有临时的杂活给你，多半不会考虑到你的工作量，可能就是随手指派的，或者他觉得交给你还 OK，不能惯。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>给自己的一些建议</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%99%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 14:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%99%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;关于读书：养成一个读书习惯比读什么书更重要。我主要在 Kindle 上买书，用 iPad 阅读。目前在重读一些物理、历史、哲学相关的书。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于习惯：早上健身 30 分钟是我最重要的习惯。另外习惯有冥想、阅读、减少饮酒和咖啡。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>关于读书：养成一个读书习惯比读什么书更重要。我主要在 Kindle 上买书，用 iPad 阅读。目前在重读一些物理、历史、哲学相关的书。</p>
<p>关于习惯：早上健身 30 分钟是我最重要的习惯。另外习惯有冥想、阅读、减少饮酒和咖啡。</p>
<p>关于幸福：虽然幸福对每个人来说不同。但我认为幸福是一种没有痛苦和欲望的状态。认为外在环境和物质会带来幸福，这是最大的误区。</p>
<p>关于自由：我以前的定义是做任何想做的事情。现在定义是「免于反应的自由」，如免于愤怒的自由，免于悲伤的自由。</p>
<p>关于经济学：不再相信宏观经济学，因为无法证伪，数据太多，人们只会选我们相信的叙事。微观经济学和博弈论才是构成经济社会的基础。商业上的成功依赖对供需、劳动力与资本、博弈论等问题的理解。</p>
<p>如何成为好的创始人：考虑长期；享受过程（短期没法保证结果）；有执行力</p>
<p>关于生命的意义：生命意义是个人的，需要自己找；生命没有意义，需要自己创造；也许生命有意义，从热力学第二定律看，熵只会增加，作为生命系统，创建复杂系统，加速宇宙热寂可能是一种意义。这虽然不是一个令人满意的目标。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>自由思考比畅所欲言更重要。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E6%AF%94%E7%95%85%E6%89%80%E6%AC%B2%E8%A8%80%E6%9B%B4%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 10:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E6%AF%94%E7%95%85%E6%89%80%E6%AC%B2%E8%A8%80%E6%9B%B4%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;在思想和言论之间划一条明确的界线。在心里无所不想，但是不一定要说出来。我就鼓励自己在心里默默思考那些最无法无天的想法。你的思想是一个地下组织，绝不要把那里发生的事情一股脑说给外人听。“格斗俱乐部”的第一条规则，就是不要提到格斗俱乐部&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>在思想和言论之间划一条明确的界线。在心里无所不想，但是不一定要说出来。我就鼓励自己在心里默默思考那些最无法无天的想法。你的思想是一个地下组织，绝不要把那里发生的事情一股脑说给外人听。“格斗俱乐部”的第一条规则，就是不要提到格斗俱乐部</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如果别人告诉你应该相信什么，你就真的相信了，那么你就会和别人一样犯下同样的错误。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E6%9E%9C%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E5%91%8A%E8%AF%89%E4%BD%A0%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E7%9B%B8%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E4%BD%A0%E5%B0%B1%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E7%9B%B8%E4%BF%A1%E4%BA%86/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E6%9E%9C%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E5%91%8A%E8%AF%89%E4%BD%A0%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E7%9B%B8%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E4%BD%A0%E5%B0%B1%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E7%9B%B8%E4%BF%A1%E4%BA%86/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;也许事情并没有这么巧合，你的观点就是从别人那里听来的，别人告诉你什么，你就相信了什么，你把别人灌输的观点当作了自己的观点。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有时候，别人会对你说：“要根据社会需要，改造自己的思想 (well-adjusted) 。”这种说法隐含的意思似乎是，如果你不认同社会，那么肯定是你自己的问题。你同意这种说法吗？事实上，它不仅不对，而且会让历史倒退。如果你真的相信了它，凡是不认同社会之处，你连想都不敢想，马上就放弃自己的观点，那才会真正出问题。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>也许事情并没有这么巧合，你的观点就是从别人那里听来的，别人告诉你什么，你就相信了什么，你把别人灌输的观点当作了自己的观点。</p>
<p>有时候，别人会对你说：“要根据社会需要，改造自己的思想 (well-adjusted) 。”这种说法隐含的意思似乎是，如果你不认同社会，那么肯定是你自己的问题。你同意这种说法吗？事实上，它不仅不对，而且会让历史倒退。如果你真的相信了它，凡是不认同社会之处，你连想都不敢想，马上就放弃自己的观点，那才会真正出问题。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Five Parts of Every Business</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-five-parts-of-every-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 09:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-five-parts-of-every-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1. Creates and delivers something of value . .&lt;br&gt;
2. That other people want or need . . .&lt;br&gt;
3. At a price they’re willing to pay . . .&lt;br&gt;
4. In a way that satisfies the customer’s needs and expectations . . .&lt;br&gt;
5. So that the business brings in enough profit to make it worthwhile for the owners to continue operation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1. Creates and delivers something of value . .<br>
2. That other people want or need . . .<br>
3. At a price they’re willing to pay . . .<br>
4. In a way that satisfies the customer’s needs and expectations . . .<br>
5. So that the business brings in enough profit to make it worthwhile for the owners to continue operation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you find something broken that you can fix for a lot of people, you’ve found a gold mine.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-find-something-broken-that-you-can-fix-for-a-lot-of-people-youve-found-a-gold-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 09:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-find-something-broken-that-you-can-fix-for-a-lot-of-people-youve-found-a-gold-mine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every successful business creates something of value. The world is full of opportunities to make other people’s lives better in some way, and your job as a businessperson is to identify things that people don’t have enough of, then find a way to provide them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every successful business creates something of value. The world is full of opportunities to make other people’s lives better in some way, and your job as a businessperson is to identify things that people don’t have enough of, then find a way to provide them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>凛冬已至，一点建议</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%87%9B%E5%86%AC%E5%B7%B2%E8%87%B3%E4%B8%80%E7%82%B9%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 09:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%87%9B%E5%86%AC%E5%B7%B2%E8%87%B3%E4%B8%80%E7%82%B9%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1. 没饿饭的情况下，没有什么是绝对的钢需。&lt;br&gt;
2.绝对不要想着抄底，-18 层下面可能还有车库，这钱不是你能赚的。&lt;br&gt;
3. 不做固定资产投资，重资产持有成本很高。&lt;br&gt;
4. 不要创业，摆个地摊可以，千万不要注册公司。&lt;br&gt;
5. 不要玩虚拟经济与虚拟币。&lt;br&gt;
5. 存点应急资金。不能全是 RMB&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1. 没饿饭的情况下，没有什么是绝对的钢需。<br>
2.绝对不要想着抄底，-18 层下面可能还有车库，这钱不是你能赚的。<br>
3. 不做固定资产投资，重资产持有成本很高。<br>
4. 不要创业，摆个地摊可以，千万不要注册公司。<br>
5. 不要玩虚拟经济与虚拟币。<br>
5. 存点应急资金。不能全是 RMB</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>put all your eggs in one basket and watch the basket very carefully.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/put-all-your-eggs-in-one-basket-and-watch-the-basket-very-carefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 09:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/put-all-your-eggs-in-one-basket-and-watch-the-basket-very-carefully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mistake 98% of money managers and individuals make is they feel like they have got to be playing with a bunch of of stuff. And if you really see it, put all your eggs in one basket and watch the basket very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mistake 98% of money managers and individuals make is they feel like they have got to be playing with a bunch of of stuff. And if you really see it, put all your eggs in one basket and watch the basket very carefully.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The less he spoke, the more he heard,</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-less-he-spoke-the-more-he-heard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 09:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-less-he-spoke-the-more-he-heard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you accept how true that statement is, you realize that aligning money towards a life that lets you do what you want, when you want, with who you want, where you want, for as long as you want, has incredible return.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you accept how true that statement is, you realize that aligning money towards a life that lets you do what you want, when you want, with who you want, where you want, for as long as you want, has incredible return.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>水滴筹带给我的一点感悟</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B0%B4%E6%BB%B4%E7%AD%B9%E5%B8%A6%E7%BB%99%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E7%82%B9%E6%84%9F%E6%82%9F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 04:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B0%B4%E6%BB%B4%E7%AD%B9%E5%B8%A6%E7%BB%99%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E7%82%B9%E6%84%9F%E6%82%9F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;国内号称帮贫苦人家筹集救命钱的公司水滴筹在美国上市了。&lt;br&gt;
招股书在这里https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1823986/000119312521154899/d95574d424b4.htm#rom95574_23&lt;br&gt;
核心内容&lt;br&gt;
1. 这么一家占领道德至高点的公司，光 2020 年就赚了 144 亿，平均在每个病人身上赚 7300 块&lt;br&gt;
2. 截至 2020 年 12 月 31 日，已有超过 3.4 亿人通过水滴医疗众筹向超过 170 万名患者捐款累计超过 370 亿元人民币，平均每人捐款金额为 100RMB，平均每名患者是 2.1 万，但是很明显患者不可能拿到这么多，因为公司还要赚钱。&lt;br&gt;
3. 腾讯目前实益拥有水滴筹 22.1%的股份&lt;br&gt;
4. 2020 年腾讯通过支付手续费与广告营销费等，共在水滴筹上赚了 2.1 亿&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>国内号称帮贫苦人家筹集救命钱的公司水滴筹在美国上市了。<br>
招股书在这里https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1823986/000119312521154899/d95574d424b4.htm#rom95574_23<br>
核心内容<br>
1. 这么一家占领道德至高点的公司，光 2020 年就赚了 144 亿，平均在每个病人身上赚 7300 块<br>
2. 截至 2020 年 12 月 31 日，已有超过 3.4 亿人通过水滴医疗众筹向超过 170 万名患者捐款累计超过 370 亿元人民币，平均每人捐款金额为 100RMB，平均每名患者是 2.1 万，但是很明显患者不可能拿到这么多，因为公司还要赚钱。<br>
3. 腾讯目前实益拥有水滴筹 22.1%的股份<br>
4. 2020 年腾讯通过支付手续费与广告营销费等，共在水滴筹上赚了 2.1 亿</p>
<p>个人的一点感悟：任何公司都是以赚钱的目的的。无论他们打着多么高尚的旗号。世界本身就是及其残酷的。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>每一句话都是无数踩过的坑</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%AF%8F%E4%B8%80%E5%8F%A5%E8%AF%9D%E9%83%BD%E6%98%AF%E6%97%A0%E6%95%B0%E8%B8%A9%E8%BF%87%E7%9A%84%E5%9D%91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%AF%8F%E4%B8%80%E5%8F%A5%E8%AF%9D%E9%83%BD%E6%98%AF%E6%97%A0%E6%95%B0%E8%B8%A9%E8%BF%87%E7%9A%84%E5%9D%91/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1、很多人的正确决定都无疾而终：去问一个只 骑过自行车的人，理想汽车值不值得买？问一 个从来没从股权投资中获益的人，要不要做梅 花 LP？……做错的决定和错过的决定很多时候 都因为你去咨询的人不对。有一种出馊主意的 方式是：我是为你好。遇到不如你的人，要坚定自己的想法。遇到和你差不多的人，要怀疑自己的想法。遇到比你优秀的人，要否定自己的想法。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1、很多人的正确决定都无疾而终：去问一个只 骑过自行车的人，理想汽车值不值得买？问一 个从来没从股权投资中获益的人，要不要做梅 花 LP？……做错的决定和错过的决定很多时候 都因为你去咨询的人不对。有一种出馊主意的 方式是：我是为你好。遇到不如你的人，要坚定自己的想法。遇到和你差不多的人，要怀疑自己的想法。遇到比你优秀的人，要否定自己的想法。</p>
<p>2、人唯一真正的资产是时间。唯一重要的战 略，是如何使用自己的时问。有价值的事情不要在乎价格，没价值的事情不要浪费时间，决策是价格思维还是价值思维，结果相差悬殊。 创业就像拼乐高，时间不是花在看图纸上，时 间往往花在找零件上。创始人始终重要的三件事：找人，找钱，找方向。</p>
<p>3、如果一个创业者不从一个教训中彻底反省， 那么这个教训将会一再重复，直到你彻底学会 为止。人教人，百遍不会，事教人，一遍就会。能说服一个人的，不是说教，而是南墙。</p>
<p>4、穷人翻身的机会就是下重注。没有筹码数量就要有倍数，均匀下注不可能翻身成功。你的 重注包括金钱、时问、精力、忠诚。所谓第一 桶金就是让你上一个台阶的金额。这个社会又现实又残酷，钱都流向了那些不缺钱的人，苦都留给了能吃苦的人。</p>
<p>5、很多人生活比以前更好，但是也没有想象中 变得更快乐。人的快乐第一层由感官决定，第 二层由多巴胺决定，第三层由内啡肽决定，第一层绝大部分人都有，第三层绝大部分人都没有，真正区分人的快乐程度是由第二层多巴胺分泌多少决定的，从多巴胺的角度来讲，拥有存量是无趣的，只有获得增量才会有趣，不要吃老本，要立新功，有增量才有多巴胺，才会拥有更多的快乐。投资人跨界脱口秀也是增量。</p>
<p>6、惯蛋是一种：“如果水平相当就比谁少犯错” 的游戏。同样，创业是一种如果战略、战术 清晰就比谁更精益、谁更抠的游戏。在造车新势力中，理想在同样的事情犯错最少，这就赢了一大半。</p>
<p>7、创业者进化就要离开舒适区，进入自适区。谁痛苦谁改变，谁改变谁适应，谁适应谁受益。离开舒适区最有效的方式，是拿别人当一面镜子，来照出自己的问题。普通人喜欢听好听的话，如同小孩喜欢吃糖，甜而无益。高手喜欢听难听的话，如同大人喜欢喝茶，苦而排毒。</p>
<p>8、不要拉人上路创业，而是在创业同行路上吸引需要的人。拉人创业，你就要承诺，承诺就给人确定性，确定性就引发懒惰和作恶。</p>
<p>9、聪明的人找傻子做对手，找高手做朋友， 这是反人性的，但符合常理的。笨的人找高手做对手，找傻子做朋友，这是合乎人性，但违背常理。</p>
<p>10、人有三次生命：一次出生，一次心力涌 现，一次认知觉醒。心力、认知就是创业者的 任督二脉，只有打通之，才能真正无往而不胜。没有心力、认知成长的成功比失败更可怕，因为最终时间会把撞大运式的成功打回原形。阶层爬升很困难，跌落只需要很短时间。</p>
<p>11、人天生都是双标动物，理解别人的双标，克服自己的双标，这是一生的修炼，这是很痛苦的修心，也是区分一个人能否真正客观、诚实、有同理心的。</p>
<p>12、查理芒格认为获得幸福生活的 5 项清单：</p>
<ul>
<li>不要过度消费，不要超出承受能力</li>
<li>进行精明的投资</li>
<li>远离有毒的人和有毒的活动</li>
<li>保持终身学习</li>
<li>多做延迟满足的事情<br>
否则，你就需要拥有非常好非常好的运气！大师认为稀松平常的事情，里面每一点都不简单。大部分人最终都期待自己有非常非常好的运气，不惜花时间烧香拜佛，在进化和进公司选择了进庙。</li>
</ul>
<p>13、融来的钱都不经花，只有能从市场上赚到的钱才经花。一流的企业家永远是赚钱能力远大于融钱能力。95% 的创始人花钱能力都需要很惨痛的代价才能锻炼出来，不会花的时候抠门就很重要。很多创始人都把钱花在刀背上，甚至刀把上，就是没有花在刀刃上。</p>
<p>14、人就是这样，哪怕勉强，但只要某方面能 领先对手一丢丢，状态就会出来，甚至能够发 挥出 120%、150% 的力量。要咬紧牙关坚持领先，充分发挥“大树原理”：在森林里，越高的树，越能得到太阳光照，树木在光合作用下， 成长的越快。</p>
<p>15、企业里任何时候骑墙派、墙头草都是占大多数的，在你不行的时候、犯错的时候他们骑墙观望很正常，如果你用单一、绝对忠诚的价值观就会把他们推向你的对手方。</p>
<p>16、创业社交的潜规则，只筛选，不教育。改变别人是一种极大的内耗，改变自己则是一种成长。顺境和逆境是都是内心的映照，如果你执着了，心动了，对你来说就是逆境；如果你放下了，心不动，一切都是顺境。</p>
<p>17、人往高处走，是往更高维走，是为了获取更多的信息，而不仅仅是能力。你在更高的维度里，掌握信息的速度、密度、精确度，是完全不一样的，它会变成你的认知厚度。有了认知的厚度，去降维，去兼容，去服务你能服务的用户，这就是赚钱的逻辑。</p>
<p>18、“真正的光明绝不是没有黑暗的时问，只是永不被黑暗所掩蔽罢了。真正的英雄绝不是永没有卑下的情操，只是永不被卑下的情操所屈服罢了。”一一我非常欣赏的一段话。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you can’t decide, the answer is no.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-cant-decide-the-answer-is-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-cant-decide-the-answer-is-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should I marry this person?&lt;br&gt;
Should I take this job?&lt;br&gt;
Should I buy this house?&lt;br&gt;
Should I move to this city?&lt;br&gt;
Should I go into business with this person?&lt;br&gt;
If you cannot decide, the answer is no. And the reason is, modern society is full of options. There are tons and tons of options.&lt;br&gt;
We live on a planet of seven billion people, and we are connected to everybody on the internet. There are hundreds of thousands of careers available to you. There are so many choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Should I marry this person?<br>
Should I take this job?<br>
Should I buy this house?<br>
Should I move to this city?<br>
Should I go into business with this person?<br>
If you cannot decide, the answer is no. And the reason is, modern society is full of options. There are tons and tons of options.<br>
We live on a planet of seven billion people, and we are connected to everybody on the internet. There are hundreds of thousands of careers available to you. There are so many choices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read what you love until you love to read.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/read-what-you-love-until-you-love-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/read-what-you-love-until-you-love-to-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You almost have to read the stuff you’re reading, because you’re into it. You don’t need any other reason. There’s no mission here to accomplish. Just read because you enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You almost have to read the stuff you’re reading, because you’re into it. You don’t need any other reason. There’s no mission here to accomplish. Just read because you enjoy it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principal-Agent Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/principal-agent-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/principal-agent-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;只有确保利益绑定，才能从根本上降低代理人问题，最大限度的保护我们自己的利益。&lt;br&gt;
To me, the principal-agent problem is the single most fundamental problem in microeconomics. If you do not understand the principal-agent problem, you will not know how to navigate your way through the world. It is important if you want to build a successful company or be successful in your dealings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>只有确保利益绑定，才能从根本上降低代理人问题，最大限度的保护我们自己的利益。<br>
To me, the principal-agent problem is the single most fundamental problem in microeconomics. If you do not understand the principal-agent problem, you will not know how to navigate your way through the world. It is important if you want to build a successful company or be successful in your dealings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>问别人一个问题，就是给别人一个讲话的机会</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%97%AE%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E5%B0%B1%E6%98%AF%E7%BB%99%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E8%AE%B2%E8%AF%9D%E7%9A%84%E6%9C%BA%E4%BC%9A/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%97%AE%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E5%B0%B1%E6%98%AF%E7%BB%99%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E8%AE%B2%E8%AF%9D%E7%9A%84%E6%9C%BA%E4%BC%9A/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;当某人拒绝我们做某事的时候，我们的第一反应是向他解释为什么他要接受我们的提议。而一旦他没有选择让步，我们就会继续解释，或者提出更多的论据。我们想通过自己的解释强迫别人接受，而对方却和我们做着同样的事。这就如同两个聋人之间进行对话：‘不是的，因为 ……’ ，‘是的，因为 ……’ ，‘不是的，因为 ……’ ，‘是的，因为 ……’ 没完没了。但其实一个简单的词就可以扭转局面 —— 为什么，一个十分简单但是威力无穷的词语。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>当某人拒绝我们做某事的时候，我们的第一反应是向他解释为什么他要接受我们的提议。而一旦他没有选择让步，我们就会继续解释，或者提出更多的论据。我们想通过自己的解释强迫别人接受，而对方却和我们做着同样的事。这就如同两个聋人之间进行对话：‘不是的，因为 ……’ ，‘是的，因为 ……’ ，‘不是的，因为 ……’ ，‘是的，因为 ……’ 没完没了。但其实一个简单的词就可以扭转局面 —— 为什么，一个十分简单但是威力无穷的词语。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is what it is</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/this-is-what-it-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 04:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/this-is-what-it-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never ask if “I like it” or “I don’t like it.” I think “this is what it is” or “this is what it isn’t.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I never ask if “I like it” or “I don’t like it.” I think “this is what it is” or “this is what it isn’t.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clear thinkers appeal to their own authority.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clear-thinkers-appeal-to-their-own-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clear-thinkers-appeal-to-their-own-authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of making effective decisions boils down to dealing with reality. How do you make sure you’re dealing with reality when you’re making decisions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part of making effective decisions boils down to dealing with reality. How do you make sure you’re dealing with reality when you’re making decisions?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do you make sure you’re dealing with reality when you’re making decisions?</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-do-you-make-sure-youre-dealing-with-reality-when-youre-making-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-do-you-make-sure-youre-dealing-with-reality-when-youre-making-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By not having a strong sense of self or judgments or mind presence. The “monkey mind” will always respond with this regurgitated emotional response to what it thinks the world should be. Those desires will cloud your reality. This happens a lot of times when people are mixing politics and business.&lt;br&gt;
The number one thing clouding us from being able to see reality is we have preconceived notions of the way it should be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By not having a strong sense of self or judgments or mind presence. The “monkey mind” will always respond with this regurgitated emotional response to what it thinks the world should be. Those desires will cloud your reality. This happens a lot of times when people are mixing politics and business.<br>
The number one thing clouding us from being able to see reality is we have preconceived notions of the way it should be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hard thing is seeing the truth.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-hard-thing-is-seeing-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-hard-thing-is-seeing-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To see the truth, you have to get your ego out of the way because your ego doesn’t want to face the truth. The smaller you can make your ego, the less conditioned you can make your reactions, the less desires you can have about the outcome you want, the easier it will be to see the reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To see the truth, you have to get your ego out of the way because your ego doesn’t want to face the truth. The smaller you can make your ego, the less conditioned you can make your reactions, the less desires you can have about the outcome you want, the easier it will be to see the reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The more desire I have for something to work out a certain way, the less likely I am to see the truth.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-more-desire-i-have-for-something-to-work-out-a-certain-way-the-less-likely-i-am-to-see-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-more-desire-i-have-for-something-to-work-out-a-certain-way-the-less-likely-i-am-to-see-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem is their desire is colliding with reality and preventing them from seeing the truth, no matter how much you say it. The same thing happens when I make decisions. The more desire I have for something to work out a certain way, the less likely I am to see the truth. Especially in business, if something isn’t going well, I try to acknowledge it publicly and I try to acknowledge it publicly in front of my co-founders and friends and co-workers. Then, I’m not hiding it from anybody else. If I’m not hiding it from anybody, I’m not going to delude myself from what’s actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The problem is their desire is colliding with reality and preventing them from seeing the truth, no matter how much you say it. The same thing happens when I make decisions. The more desire I have for something to work out a certain way, the less likely I am to see the truth. Especially in business, if something isn’t going well, I try to acknowledge it publicly and I try to acknowledge it publicly in front of my co-founders and friends and co-workers. Then, I’m not hiding it from anybody else. If I’m not hiding it from anybody, I’m not going to delude myself from what’s actually going on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tension is who you think you should be. Relaxation is who you are.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/tension-is-who-you-think-you-should-be-relaxation-is-who-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/tension-is-who-you-think-you-should-be-relaxation-is-who-you-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost all biases are time-saving heuristics. For important decisions, discard memory and identity, and focus on the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost all biases are time-saving heuristics. For important decisions, discard memory and identity, and focus on the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play stupid games, win stupid prizes.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/play-stupid-games-win-stupid-prizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/play-stupid-games-win-stupid-prizes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t play zero-sum games .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Don’t play zero-sum games .</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find Work That Feels Like Play</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/find-work-that-feels-like-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/find-work-that-feels-like-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any end goal will just lead to another goal, lead to another goal. We just play games in life. When you grow up, you’re playing the school game, or you’re playing the social game. Then you’re playing the money game, and then you’re playing the status game. These games just have longer and longer and longer-lived horizons. At some point, at least I believe, these are all just games. These are games where the outcome really stops mattering once you see through the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Any end goal will just lead to another goal, lead to another goal. We just play games in life. When you grow up, you’re playing the school game, or you’re playing the social game. Then you’re playing the money game, and then you’re playing the status game. These games just have longer and longer and longer-lived horizons. At some point, at least I believe, these are all just games. These are games where the outcome really stops mattering once you see through the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply specific knowledge with leverage and eventually, you will get what you deserve.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/apply-specific-knowledge-with-leverage-and-eventually-you-will-get-what-you-deserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/apply-specific-knowledge-with-leverage-and-eventually-you-will-get-what-you-deserve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It takes time—even once you have all of these pieces in place, there is an indeterminate amount of time you have to put in. If you’re counting, you’ll run out of patience before success actually arrives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It takes time—even once you have all of these pieces in place, there is an indeterminate amount of time you have to put in. If you’re counting, you’ll run out of patience before success actually arrives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t keep count.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/dont-keep-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/dont-keep-count/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not to say it’s easy. It’s not easy. It’s actually really freaking hard. It is the hardest thing you will do. But it’s also rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is not to say it’s easy. It’s not easy. It’s actually really freaking hard. It is the hardest thing you will do. But it’s also rewarding.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One correct decision can win everything</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/one-correct-decision-can-win-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/one-correct-decision-can-win-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don’t get rich by spending your time to save money. You get rich by saving your time to make money.&lt;br&gt;
In an age of leverage, one correct decision can win everything. Without hard work, you’ll develop neither judgment nor leverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You don’t get rich by spending your time to save money. You get rich by saving your time to make money.<br>
In an age of leverage, one correct decision can win everything. Without hard work, you’ll develop neither judgment nor leverage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The direction you’re heading in matters more than how fast you move</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-direction-youre-heading-in-matters-more-than-how-fast-you-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-direction-youre-heading-in-matters-more-than-how-fast-you-move/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have to put in the time, but the judgment is more important. The direction you’re heading in matters more than how fast you move, especially with leverage. Picking the direction you’re heading in for every decision is far, far more important than how much force you apply. Just pick the right direction to start walking in, and start walking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You have to put in the time, but the judgment is more important. The direction you’re heading in matters more than how fast you move, especially with leverage. Picking the direction you’re heading in for every decision is far, far more important than how much force you apply. Just pick the right direction to start walking in, and start walking.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>遇到事了，就只能无助的哭泣，仿佛一只巨婴</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%81%87%E5%88%B0%E4%BA%8B%E4%BA%86%E5%B0%B1%E5%8F%AA%E8%83%BD%E6%97%A0%E5%8A%A9%E7%9A%84%E5%93%AD%E6%B3%A3%E4%BB%BF%E4%BD%9B%E4%B8%80%E5%8F%AA%E5%B7%A8%E5%A9%B4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 03:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%81%87%E5%88%B0%E4%BA%8B%E4%BA%86%E5%B0%B1%E5%8F%AA%E8%83%BD%E6%97%A0%E5%8A%A9%E7%9A%84%E5%93%AD%E6%B3%A3%E4%BB%BF%E4%BD%9B%E4%B8%80%E5%8F%AA%E5%B7%A8%E5%A9%B4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;读书是一种可以确保活在及格线以上的稳妥方法，即不至于变的过分的庸俗，低级，和自以为是，有中上水平的思考和内省能力。&lt;br&gt;
达到这个及格线以后，想更进一步变的更厉害，其实也非常简单，去实践。把在书里看到的东西，实践起来。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>读书是一种可以确保活在及格线以上的稳妥方法，即不至于变的过分的庸俗，低级，和自以为是，有中上水平的思考和内省能力。<br>
达到这个及格线以后，想更进一步变的更厉害，其实也非常简单，去实践。把在书里看到的东西，实践起来。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>要把脑力用在重要的事情上</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%A6%81%E6%8A%8A%E8%84%91%E5%8A%9B%E7%94%A8%E5%9C%A8%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E4%B8%8A/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 02:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%A6%81%E6%8A%8A%E8%84%91%E5%8A%9B%E7%94%A8%E5%9C%A8%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E4%B8%8A/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;大脑是个耗能极高的器官，它以 2%左右的身体重量，消耗了身体总消耗的 20%-30%的能量。 人每天大脑运行的产出是有限的，要把脑力用在重要的事情上。不要白白浪费你的生命。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>大脑是个耗能极高的器官，它以 2%左右的身体重量，消耗了身体总消耗的 20%-30%的能量。 人每天大脑运行的产出是有限的，要把脑力用在重要的事情上。不要白白浪费你的生命。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earn with your mind, not your time.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/earn-with-your-mind-not-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 08:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/earn-with-your-mind-not-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one thing you have to avoid is the risk of ruin. Avoiding ruin means stay out of jail. So, don’t do anything illegal. It’s never worth it to wear an orange jumpsuit. Stay out of total catastrophic loss. Avoiding ruin could also mean you stay out of things that could be physically dangerous or hurt your body. You have to watch your health .Stay out of things that could cause you to lose all of your capital, all of your savings. Don’t gamble everything on one go. Instead, take rationally optimistic bets with big upsides. [&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The one thing you have to avoid is the risk of ruin. Avoiding ruin means stay out of jail. So, don’t do anything illegal. It’s never worth it to wear an orange jumpsuit. Stay out of total catastrophic loss. Avoiding ruin could also mean you stay out of things that could be physically dangerous or hurt your body. You have to watch your health .Stay out of things that could cause you to lose all of your capital, all of your savings. Don’t gamble everything on one go. Instead, take rationally optimistic bets with big upsides. [</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Paid for Your Judgment</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/get-paid-for-your-judgment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 08:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/get-paid-for-your-judgment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing what kinds of jobs, careers, or fields you get into and what sort of deals you’re willing to take from your employer will give you much more free time. Then, you don’t have to worry as much about time management. I would love to be paid purely for my judgment, not for any work. I want a robot, capital, or computer to do the work, but I want to be paid for my judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Choosing what kinds of jobs, careers, or fields you get into and what sort of deals you’re willing to take from your employer will give you much more free time. Then, you don’t have to worry as much about time management. I would love to be paid purely for my judgment, not for any work. I want a robot, capital, or computer to do the work, but I want to be paid for my judgment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prioritize and Focus</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/prioritize-and-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 08:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/prioritize-and-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Value your time at an hourly rate, and ruthlessly spend to save time at that rate. You will never be worth more than you think you’re worth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Value your time at an hourly rate, and ruthlessly spend to save time at that rate. You will never be worth more than you think you’re worth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If they can train you to do it, then eventually they will train a computer to do it.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-they-can-train-you-to-do-it-then-eventually-they-will-train-a-computer-to-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 05:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-they-can-train-you-to-do-it-then-eventually-they-will-train-a-computer-to-do-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If someone can train other people how to do something, then they can replace you. If they can replace you, then they don’t have to pay you a lot. You want to know how to do something other people don’t know how to do at the time period when those skills are in demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If someone can train other people how to do something, then they can replace you. If they can replace you, then they don’t have to pay you a lot. You want to know how to do something other people don’t know how to do at the time period when those skills are in demand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There are three broad classes of leverage</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/there-are-three-broad-classes-of-leverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 05:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/there-are-three-broad-classes-of-leverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One form of leverage is labor—other humans working for you. It is the oldest form of leverage, and actually not a great one in the modern world. [1] I would argue this is the worst form of leverage that you could possibly use. Managing other people is incredibly messy. It requires tremendous leadership skills. You’re one short hop from a mutiny or getting eaten or torn apart by the mob. [78] Money is good as a form of leverage. It means every time you make a decision, you multiply it with money. [1] Capital is a trickier form of leverage to use. It’s more modern. It’s the one that people have used to get fabulously wealthy in the last century. It’s probably been the dominant form of leverage in the last century. You can see this by looking for the richest people. It’s bankers, politicians in corrupt countries who print money, essentially people who move large amounts of money around. If you look at the top of very large companies, outside of technology companies, in many, many large old companies, the CEO job is really a financial job. It scales very, very well. If you get good at managing capital, you can manage more and more capital much more easily than you can manage more and more people. The final form of leverage is brand new—the most democratic form. It is: “products with no marginal cost of replication.” This includes books, media, movies, and code. Code is probably the most powerful form of permissionless leverage. All you need is a computer—you don’t need anyone’s permission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One form of leverage is labor—other humans working for you. It is the oldest form of leverage, and actually not a great one in the modern world. [1] I would argue this is the worst form of leverage that you could possibly use. Managing other people is incredibly messy. It requires tremendous leadership skills. You’re one short hop from a mutiny or getting eaten or torn apart by the mob. [78] Money is good as a form of leverage. It means every time you make a decision, you multiply it with money. [1] Capital is a trickier form of leverage to use. It’s more modern. It’s the one that people have used to get fabulously wealthy in the last century. It’s probably been the dominant form of leverage in the last century. You can see this by looking for the richest people. It’s bankers, politicians in corrupt countries who print money, essentially people who move large amounts of money around. If you look at the top of very large companies, outside of technology companies, in many, many large old companies, the CEO job is really a financial job. It scales very, very well. If you get good at managing capital, you can manage more and more capital much more easily than you can manage more and more people. The final form of leverage is brand new—the most democratic form. It is: “products with no marginal cost of replication.” This includes books, media, movies, and code. Code is probably the most powerful form of permissionless leverage. All you need is a computer—you don’t need anyone’s permission.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The leverage for ordinary people</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-leverage-for-ordinary-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 05:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-leverage-for-ordinary-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably the most interesting thing to keep in mind about new forms of leverage is they are permissionless. They don’t require somebody else’s permission for you to use them or succeed. For labor leverage, somebody has to decide to follow you. For capital leverage, somebody has to give you money to invest or to turn into a product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Probably the most interesting thing to keep in mind about new forms of leverage is they are permissionless. They don’t require somebody else’s permission for you to use them or succeed. For labor leverage, somebody has to decide to follow you. For capital leverage, somebody has to give you money to invest or to turn into a product.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you’re looking toward the long-term goal of getting wealthy, you should ask yourself,</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-youre-looking-toward-the-long-term-goal-of-getting-wealthy-you-should-ask-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-youre-looking-toward-the-long-term-goal-of-getting-wealthy-you-should-ask-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Is this authentic to me? Is it myself that I am projecting?” And then, “Am I productizing it? Am I scaling it? Am I scaling with labor or with capital or with code or with media?” So it’s a very handy, simple mnemonic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Is this authentic to me? Is it myself that I am projecting?” And then, “Am I productizing it? Am I scaling it? Am I scaling with labor or with capital or with code or with media?” So it’s a very handy, simple mnemonic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play Long-Term Games with Long-Term People</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compound interest is a very powerful concept. Compound interest applies to more than just compounding capital. Compounding capital is just the beginning.&lt;br&gt;
Compound interest also happens in your reputation.&lt;br&gt;
If you have a sterling reputation and you keep building it for decades upon decades, people will notice.&lt;br&gt;
Your reputation will literally end up being thousands or tens of thousands of times more valuable than somebody else who was very talented but is not keeping the compound interest in reputation going.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Compound interest is a very powerful concept. Compound interest applies to more than just compounding capital. Compounding capital is just the beginning.<br>
Compound interest also happens in your reputation.<br>
If you have a sterling reputation and you keep building it for decades upon decades, people will notice.<br>
Your reputation will literally end up being thousands or tens of thousands of times more valuable than somebody else who was very talented but is not keeping the compound interest in reputation going.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m not saying don’t do the 99 percent</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/im-not-saying-dont-do-the-99-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/im-not-saying-dont-do-the-99-percent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;because it’s very hard to identify what the 1 percent is. What I’m saying is: when you find the 1 percent of your discipline which will not be wasted, which you’ll be able to invest in for the rest of your life and has meaning toyou—go all-in and forget about the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>because it’s very hard to identify what the 1 percent is. What I’m saying is: when you find the 1 percent of your discipline which will not be wasted, which you’ll be able to invest in for the rest of your life and has meaning toyou—go all-in and forget about the rest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take on Accountability</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/take-on-accountability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/take-on-accountability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embrace accountability and take business risks under your own name. Society will reward you with responsibility, equity, and leverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Embrace accountability and take business risks under your own name. Society will reward you with responsibility, equity, and leverage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clear accountability is important.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clear-accountability-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/clear-accountability-is-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clear accountability is important. Without accountability, you don’t have incentives. Without accountability, you can’t build credibility.&lt;br&gt;
But you take risks. You risk failure.&lt;br&gt;
You risk humiliation.&lt;br&gt;
You risk failure under your own name.&lt;br&gt;
如果你说同学们帮我擦黑板，那么就不会有人擦&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Clear accountability is important. Without accountability, you don’t have incentives. Without accountability, you can’t build credibility.<br>
But you take risks. You risk failure.<br>
You risk humiliation.<br>
You risk failure under your own name.<br>
如果你说同学们帮我擦黑板，那么就不会有人擦</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realize that in modern society, the downside risk is not that large.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/realize-that-in-modern-society-the-downside-risk-is-not-that-large/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/realize-that-in-modern-society-the-downside-risk-is-not-that-large/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s not really that much to fear in terms of failure, and so people should take on a lot more accountability than they do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s not really that much to fear in terms of failure, and so people should take on a lot more accountability than they do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the real wealth is created by starting your own companies or even by investing.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-real-wealth-is-created-by-starting-your-own-companies-or-even-by-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-real-wealth-is-created-by-starting-your-own-companies-or-even-by-investing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an investment firm, they’re buying equity. These are the routes to wealth. It doesn’t come through the hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an investment firm, they’re buying equity. These are the routes to wealth. It doesn’t come through the hours.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find a Position of Leverage</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/find-a-position-of-leverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/find-a-position-of-leverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I only really want to do things for their own sake. That is one definition of art. Whether it’s business, exercise, romance, friendship, whatever, I think the meaning of life is to do things for their own sake. Ironically, when you do things for their own sake, you create your best work. Even if you’re just trying to make money, you will actually be the most successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I only really want to do things for their own sake. That is one definition of art. Whether it’s business, exercise, romance, friendship, whatever, I think the meaning of life is to do things for their own sake. Ironically, when you do things for their own sake, you create your best work. Even if you’re just trying to make money, you will actually be the most successful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The limits of my language are the limits of my world.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-limits-of-my-language-are-the-limits-of-my-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 15:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/the-limits-of-my-language-are-the-limits-of-my-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mental models are concepts that represent your understanding of how something in the world works. Think of driving a car: What do you expect when you press down on the right-side pedal? If the car slows down, you’ll be surprised—that pedal is supposed to be the accelerator. The accuracy of your model of the world determines your expectations, decisions, behavior, and—in the long run—your results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mental models are concepts that represent your understanding of how something in the world works. Think of driving a car: What do you expect when you press down on the right-side pedal? If the car slows down, you’ll be surprised—that pedal is supposed to be the accelerator. The accuracy of your model of the world determines your expectations, decisions, behavior, and—in the long run—your results.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Go to Business School?</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/should-you-go-to-business-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 15:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/should-you-go-to-business-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between&lt;br&gt;
(A) what an MBA does to help you prove your abilities to others .&lt;br&gt;
(B) what getting an MBA actually does to improve your abilities. They are two different things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a difference between<br>
(A) what an MBA does to help you prove your abilities to others .<br>
(B) what getting an MBA actually does to improve your abilities. They are two different things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>绝不要用短期的解决方案来应对长期问题。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%9D%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%94%A8%E7%9F%AD%E6%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%A7%A3%E5%86%B3%E6%96%B9%E6%A1%88%E6%9D%A5%E5%BA%94%E5%AF%B9%E9%95%BF%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 16:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%9D%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%94%A8%E7%9F%AD%E6%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%A7%A3%E5%86%B3%E6%96%B9%E6%A1%88%E6%9D%A5%E5%BA%94%E5%AF%B9%E9%95%BF%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我绝不能让别人认为我很吝啬。于是我经常邀请朋友去餐厅吃饭；我还需要一辆大轿车来展现身份；此外，我还必须支付一些其他费用 —— 税收。最终，我只得求助于这一伟大的发明：信用卡。有了信用卡，我就不用自己付钱了，信用卡公司的人会帮我付款，至少我暂时先不用付钱了 …… 之后我就听到有人说：“他真是个人生赢家，他过的是头等生活。”我过起了头等生活：不喝气泡酒 —— 只喝香槟酒；不吃牛排 —— 只吃上等里脊。我想像一个富人一样，生活在未来世界。而很快，过去以账单、催债信和高贷款利率等方式不断地打扰我。作为一个业绩优异、收入颇丰的销售人员，我总是能够获得新的信用卡。于是我开始进行交替还款，也就是说，我得到一张新的信用卡，然后用新信用卡去还旧信用卡的账单。就这样，我将自己卷入了一个螺旋式下降的财务状态中。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>我绝不能让别人认为我很吝啬。于是我经常邀请朋友去餐厅吃饭；我还需要一辆大轿车来展现身份；此外，我还必须支付一些其他费用 —— 税收。最终，我只得求助于这一伟大的发明：信用卡。有了信用卡，我就不用自己付钱了，信用卡公司的人会帮我付款，至少我暂时先不用付钱了 …… 之后我就听到有人说：“他真是个人生赢家，他过的是头等生活。”我过起了头等生活：不喝气泡酒 —— 只喝香槟酒；不吃牛排 —— 只吃上等里脊。我想像一个富人一样，生活在未来世界。而很快，过去以账单、催债信和高贷款利率等方式不断地打扰我。作为一个业绩优异、收入颇丰的销售人员，我总是能够获得新的信用卡。于是我开始进行交替还款，也就是说，我得到一张新的信用卡，然后用新信用卡去还旧信用卡的账单。就这样，我将自己卷入了一个螺旋式下降的财务状态中。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>整天工作的人，没有时间来赚钱。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%95%B4%E5%A4%A9%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%BA%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E6%9D%A5%E8%B5%9A%E9%92%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 16:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%95%B4%E5%A4%A9%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%BA%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E6%9D%A5%E8%B5%9A%E9%92%B1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;你越努力工作，你老板换豪车豪宅的机会越大。&lt;br&gt;
你今天的收入就是你昨天所做之决定的结果，如果不理解这一点，你就不能说：“现在我要另做选择。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>你越努力工作，你老板换豪车豪宅的机会越大。<br>
你今天的收入就是你昨天所做之决定的结果，如果不理解这一点，你就不能说：“现在我要另做选择。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>永远不要让别人替你承担责任的情况出现。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B0%B8%E8%BF%9C%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E8%AE%A9%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E6%9B%BF%E4%BD%A0%E6%89%BF%E6%8B%85%E8%B4%A3%E4%BB%BB%E7%9A%84%E6%83%85%E5%86%B5%E5%87%BA%E7%8E%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B0%B8%E8%BF%9C%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E8%AE%A9%E5%88%AB%E4%BA%BA%E6%9B%BF%E4%BD%A0%E6%89%BF%E6%8B%85%E8%B4%A3%E4%BB%BB%E7%9A%84%E6%83%85%E5%86%B5%E5%87%BA%E7%8E%B0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;•“ 将来我也会为现在拥有的一切感到满足。”&lt;br&gt;
•“ 假如我能全力以赴，我就会成为最优秀的。”&lt;br&gt;
这两句话的背后，通常都隐藏着自我欺骗、恐惧和缺乏自我价值感。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>•“ 将来我也会为现在拥有的一切感到满足。”<br>
•“ 假如我能全力以赴，我就会成为最优秀的。”<br>
这两句话的背后，通常都隐藏着自我欺骗、恐惧和缺乏自我价值感。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>没有哪个奇迹的发生不需要冒险</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E5%93%AA%E4%B8%AA%E5%A5%87%E8%BF%B9%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%8D%E9%9C%80%E8%A6%81%E5%86%92%E9%99%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E5%93%AA%E4%B8%AA%E5%A5%87%E8%BF%B9%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%8D%E9%9C%80%E8%A6%81%E5%86%92%E9%99%A9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;• 我们常常忘记，顺着我们目前为止走过的道路继续前行，同样有风险。这条路给我们一种熟悉感，但也不会更安全。&lt;br&gt;
• 生活就是一场比赛。不去冒险的人不可能获得成功。&lt;br&gt;
• 在这个星球上，没有“必胜”，只有“机会”。&lt;br&gt;
• 立即采取行动！因为你永远不能为成功做好完美的准备。&lt;br&gt;
•世上唯一从来不犯错的人，是从来不做任何事的人。（西奥多 · 罗斯福）&lt;br&gt;
• 不确定性带来的痛苦，比确定的痛苦要强烈得多。&lt;br&gt;
• 每一次行动计划都有风险，都需要付出&lt;br&gt;
代价。但比起无所事事的舒适，它们的长期风险和付出的代价要小得多。（约翰 · 费茨杰拉德 · 肯尼迪）&lt;br&gt;
• 如果你害怕失去，你永远都不会获得。&lt;br&gt;
• 去冒险吧，你不可能从地面摔下去的。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>• 我们常常忘记，顺着我们目前为止走过的道路继续前行，同样有风险。这条路给我们一种熟悉感，但也不会更安全。<br>
• 生活就是一场比赛。不去冒险的人不可能获得成功。<br>
• 在这个星球上，没有“必胜”，只有“机会”。<br>
• 立即采取行动！因为你永远不能为成功做好完美的准备。<br>
•世上唯一从来不犯错的人，是从来不做任何事的人。（西奥多 · 罗斯福）<br>
• 不确定性带来的痛苦，比确定的痛苦要强烈得多。<br>
• 每一次行动计划都有风险，都需要付出<br>
代价。但比起无所事事的舒适，它们的长期风险和付出的代价要小得多。（约翰 · 费茨杰拉德 · 肯尼迪）<br>
• 如果你害怕失去，你永远都不会获得。<br>
• 去冒险吧，你不可能从地面摔下去的。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>给你责任的人同时也给你了权力。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%99%E4%BD%A0%E8%B4%A3%E4%BB%BB%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%BA%E5%90%8C%E6%97%B6%E4%B9%9F%E7%BB%99%E4%BD%A0%E4%BA%86%E6%9D%83%E5%8A%9B/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%BB%99%E4%BD%A0%E8%B4%A3%E4%BB%BB%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%BA%E5%90%8C%E6%97%B6%E4%B9%9F%E7%BB%99%E4%BD%A0%E4%BA%86%E6%9D%83%E5%8A%9B/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;大多数人都会推卸责任。当人们不想承担责任时，我们总是听到他们用这 3 个理由来搪塞责任：&lt;br&gt;
1 ．“是基因的错。”&lt;br&gt;
2 ．“是父母的错。”&lt;br&gt;
3 ．“是客观环境的错。”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>大多数人都会推卸责任。当人们不想承担责任时，我们总是听到他们用这 3 个理由来搪塞责任：<br>
1 ．“是基因的错。”<br>
2 ．“是父母的错。”<br>
3 ．“是客观环境的错。”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life’s tough. It’s tougher if you’re stupid.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/lifes-tough-its-tougher-if-youre-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/lifes-tough-its-tougher-if-youre-stupid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;everyone has these unfounded fears, and they’re normal. Don’t let them hold you back from pursuing what’s important to you. Businesses are created, operated, and improved by ordinary people just like you; there’s no magic or secret knowledge involved. All you need to do is learn a few simple concepts that will change the way you think about how businesses work and allow you to identify promising opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>everyone has these unfounded fears, and they’re normal. Don’t let them hold you back from pursuing what’s important to you. Businesses are created, operated, and improved by ordinary people just like you; there’s no magic or secret knowledge involved. All you need to do is learn a few simple concepts that will change the way you think about how businesses work and allow you to identify promising opportunities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Experience Necessary</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/no-experience-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/no-experience-necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This isn’t rocket science—we’ve chosen one of the world’s most simple professions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This isn’t rocket science—we’ve chosen one of the world’s most simple professions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>他们总是有那么多紧急的事情要做，以至于没有时间来关注重要的事情。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BB%96%E4%BB%AC%E6%80%BB%E6%98%AF%E6%9C%89%E9%82%A3%E4%B9%88%E5%A4%9A%E7%B4%A7%E6%80%A5%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E8%A6%81%E5%81%9A/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BB%96%E4%BB%AC%E6%80%BB%E6%98%AF%E6%9C%89%E9%82%A3%E4%B9%88%E5%A4%9A%E7%B4%A7%E6%80%A5%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E8%A6%81%E5%81%9A/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;困难总是在不断地出现。尽管如此，你每天还是要不间断地去做对你的未来意义重大的事情。你为此花费的时间不会超过 10 分钟，但是就是这 10 分钟会让一切变得不同。大多数人总是在现有的水平上停滞不前，就是因为他们没有拿出这 10 分钟。他们总是期望情况能向有利于自己的方向转变，但是他们忽视了一点，那就是他们首先必须改变自己。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>困难总是在不断地出现。尽管如此，你每天还是要不间断地去做对你的未来意义重大的事情。你为此花费的时间不会超过 10 分钟，但是就是这 10 分钟会让一切变得不同。大多数人总是在现有的水平上停滞不前，就是因为他们没有拿出这 10 分钟。他们总是期望情况能向有利于自己的方向转变，但是他们忽视了一点，那就是他们首先必须改变自己。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>第一份工作的建议</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%BD%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%BD%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E8%AE%AE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;第一，无论在什么时候都不能把希望只寄托在一份工作上，它持续的时间不会像你设想的那么长，所以你要立即寻找另一份替代的工作。&lt;br&gt;
第二，你肯定会遇到一些困难，这些困难是你现在还难以预料的。到那时候就能看出来&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>第一，无论在什么时候都不能把希望只寄托在一份工作上，它持续的时间不会像你设想的那么长，所以你要立即寻找另一份替代的工作。<br>
第二，你肯定会遇到一些困难，这些困难是你现在还难以预料的。到那时候就能看出来</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>72 小时定律</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/72-%E5%B0%8F%E6%97%B6%E5%AE%9A%E5%BE%8B/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/72-%E5%B0%8F%E6%97%B6%E5%AE%9A%E5%BE%8B/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;当你决定做一件事情的时候，你必须在 72 小时之内完成，否则你很可能永远不会再做了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>当你决定做一件事情的时候，你必须在 72 小时之内完成，否则你很可能永远不会再做了。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>知道如何去实现并不是目前最重要的事情</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%9F%A5%E9%81%93%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%8E%BB%E5%AE%9E%E7%8E%B0%E5%B9%B6%E4%B8%8D%E6%98%AF%E7%9B%AE%E5%89%8D%E6%9C%80%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 14:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%9F%A5%E9%81%93%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%8E%BB%E5%AE%9E%E7%8E%B0%E5%B9%B6%E4%B8%8D%E6%98%AF%E7%9B%AE%E5%89%8D%E6%9C%80%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;最重要的是，你真的有这样的愿望，否则你一遇到困难就会放弃了。我总是往事情的消极面去想，我一定要改掉这个习惯。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>最重要的是，你真的有这样的愿望，否则你一遇到困难就会放弃了。我总是往事情的消极面去想，我一定要改掉这个习惯。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>大多数人并不清楚自己想要的是什么，他们只知道，自己想得到更多的东西</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%A7%E5%A4%9A%E6%95%B0%E4%BA%BA%E5%B9%B6%E4%B8%8D%E6%B8%85%E6%A5%9A%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%83%B3%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E6%98%AF%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E4%BB%96%E4%BB%AC%E5%8F%AA%E7%9F%A5%E9%81%93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 05:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%A7%E5%A4%9A%E6%95%B0%E4%BA%BA%E5%B9%B6%E4%B8%8D%E6%B8%85%E6%A5%9A%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%83%B3%E8%A6%81%E7%9A%84%E6%98%AF%E4%BB%80%E4%B9%88%E4%BB%96%E4%BB%AC%E5%8F%AA%E7%9F%A5%E9%81%93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;你可以把自己的生活想象成一家很大的邮购公司。如果你给一家邮购公司写信说‘请给我寄一些好东西来’，你肯定什么都得不到。我们的愿望也是一样。我们必须确切地知道自己心里渴望的是什么才行。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>你可以把自己的生活想象成一家很大的邮购公司。如果你给一家邮购公司写信说‘请给我寄一些好东西来’，你肯定什么都得不到。我们的愿望也是一样。我们必须确切地知道自己心里渴望的是什么才行。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>人生而孤独</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BA%BA%E7%94%9F%E8%80%8C%E5%AD%A4%E7%8B%AC/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 04:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E4%BA%BA%E7%94%9F%E8%80%8C%E5%AD%A4%E7%8B%AC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;而现实是，生活就是一场单人游戏。人独自出生，独自死亡，独自解读人世间的一切。你的记忆只属于你一个人。你出生前无人在意，你离开人世后也无人在意，你存在于人世间只是短短几十年，人生就是一场单人游戏。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>而现实是，生活就是一场单人游戏。人独自出生，独自死亡，独自解读人世间的一切。你的记忆只属于你一个人。你出生前无人在意，你离开人世后也无人在意，你存在于人世间只是短短几十年，人生就是一场单人游戏。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you stay away from risks, you will also stay away from the benefits.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-stay-away-from-risks-you-will-also-stay-away-from-the-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/if-you-stay-away-from-risks-you-will-also-stay-away-from-the-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a risk. Same with crypto. Early on, I took a risk. But when you put your name out there, you take a risk with certain things. You also get to reap the rewards. You get the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I took a risk. Same with crypto. Early on, I took a risk. But when you put your name out there, you take a risk with certain things. You also get to reap the rewards. You get the benefits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>玩世不恭很容易，随波逐流也很容易。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%8E%A9%E4%B8%96%E4%B8%8D%E6%81%AD%E5%BE%88%E5%AE%B9%E6%98%93%E9%9A%8F%E6%B3%A2%E9%80%90%E6%B5%81%E4%B9%9F%E5%BE%88%E5%AE%B9%E6%98%93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%8E%A9%E4%B8%96%E4%B8%8D%E6%81%AD%E5%BE%88%E5%AE%B9%E6%98%93%E9%9A%8F%E6%B3%A2%E9%80%90%E6%B5%81%E4%B9%9F%E5%BE%88%E5%AE%B9%E6%98%93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;非常聪明的人往往都是特立独行的，他们坚持独立思考、亲力亲为，以厘清事情的来龙去脉。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>非常聪明的人往往都是特立独行的，他们坚持独立思考、亲力亲为，以厘清事情的来龙去脉。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People seem to think you can create wealth—make money through work. It’s probably not going to work.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/people-seem-to-think-you-can-create-wealth-make-money-through-work-its-probably-not-going-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/people-seem-to-think-you-can-create-wealth-make-money-through-work-its-probably-not-going-to-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without ownership, your inputs are very closely tied to your outputs. In almost any salaried job, even one paying a lot per hour like a lawyer or a doctor, you’re still putting in the hours, and every hour you get paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Without ownership, your inputs are very closely tied to your outputs. In almost any salaried job, even one paying a lot per hour like a lawyer or a doctor, you’re still putting in the hours, and every hour you get paid.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s go to the stock market!</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/lets-go-to-the-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/lets-go-to-the-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Owning equity in a company basically means you own the upside. When you own debt, you own guaranteed revenue streams and you own the downside. You want to own equity. If you don’t own equity in a business, your odds of making money are very slim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Owning equity in a company basically means you own the upside. When you own debt, you own guaranteed revenue streams and you own the downside. You want to own equity. If you don’t own equity in a business, your odds of making money are very slim.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t work for the boss. You must be your own boss.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/dont-work-for-the-boss-you-must-be-your-own-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 10:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/dont-work-for-the-boss-you-must-be-your-own-boss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Essentially, you’re working for somebody else, and that person is taking on the risk and has the accountability, the intellectual property, and the brand. They’re not going to pay you enough. They’re going to pay you the bare minimum they have to, to get you to do their job. That can be a high bare minimum, but it’s still not going to be true wealth where you’re retired but still earning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Essentially, you’re working for somebody else, and that person is taking on the risk and has the accountability, the intellectual property, and the brand. They’re not going to pay you enough. They’re going to pay you the bare minimum they have to, to get you to do their job. That can be a high bare minimum, but it’s still not going to be true wealth where you’re retired but still earning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>大自然的法则是春播秋收，极少有事情是立竿见影的</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%A7%E8%87%AA%E7%84%B6%E7%9A%84%E6%B3%95%E5%88%99%E6%98%AF%E6%98%A5%E6%92%AD%E7%A7%8B%E6%94%B6%E6%9E%81%E5%B0%91%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E6%98%AF%E7%AB%8B%E7%AB%BF%E8%A7%81%E5%BD%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 09:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%A7%E8%87%AA%E7%84%B6%E7%9A%84%E6%B3%95%E5%88%99%E6%98%AF%E6%98%A5%E6%92%AD%E7%A7%8B%E6%94%B6%E6%9E%81%E5%B0%91%E6%9C%89%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E6%98%AF%E7%AB%8B%E7%AB%BF%E8%A7%81%E5%BD%B1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;时间的投入是必需的，所以我认为，你需要做的就是拥有专长，有责任感，有影响力，利用杠杆效应，获得独步天下的技能组合，在自己的专业领域做到首屈一指。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>时间的投入是必需的，所以我认为，你需要做的就是拥有专长，有责任感，有影响力，利用杠杆效应，获得独步天下的技能组合，在自己的专业领域做到首屈一指。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specific knowledge cannot be taught, but it can be learned.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/specific-knowledge-cannot-be-taught-but-it-can-be-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 16:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/specific-knowledge-cannot-be-taught-but-it-can-be-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have to do it by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You have to do it by yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>避免万元陷阱</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%81%BF%E5%85%8D%E4%B8%87%E5%85%83%E9%99%B7%E9%98%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 13:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E9%81%BF%E5%85%8D%E4%B8%87%E5%85%83%E9%99%B7%E9%98%B1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;不要指望能够以很低的价格买入。（不要指望花 100 买 10000，应该直接出价 9900）&lt;br&gt;
两个抢劫犯经过一个绞刑架，一个感叹道：如果绞刑架没有该多好啊。另一个说，你傻啊，没有它别人就会来抢我们了。&lt;br&gt;
尽快传递“势在必得”的信号。（破釜沉舟，告诉别人我就是倾家荡产也要把它拿到）&lt;br&gt;
只争馒头不争气，没了馒头终断气。（务实，不要意气用事）&lt;br&gt;
高瞻远瞩,深谋远虑。（三思而后行，要能想到这是一个陷阱）&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>不要指望能够以很低的价格买入。（不要指望花 100 买 10000，应该直接出价 9900）<br>
两个抢劫犯经过一个绞刑架，一个感叹道：如果绞刑架没有该多好啊。另一个说，你傻啊，没有它别人就会来抢我们了。<br>
尽快传递“势在必得”的信号。（破釜沉舟，告诉别人我就是倾家荡产也要把它拿到）<br>
只争馒头不争气，没了馒头终断气。（务实，不要意气用事）<br>
高瞻远瞩,深谋远虑。（三思而后行，要能想到这是一个陷阱）</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>太过迫切地想弥补损失，以至于忘记了自己承担的风险。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%AA%E8%BF%87%E8%BF%AB%E5%88%87%E5%9C%B0%E6%83%B3%E5%BC%A5%E8%A1%A5%E6%8D%9F%E5%A4%B1%E4%BB%A5%E8%87%B3%E4%BA%8E%E5%BF%98%E8%AE%B0%E4%BA%86%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%89%BF%E6%8B%85%E7%9A%84/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 13:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A4%AA%E8%BF%87%E8%BF%AB%E5%88%87%E5%9C%B0%E6%83%B3%E5%BC%A5%E8%A1%A5%E6%8D%9F%E5%A4%B1%E4%BB%A5%E8%87%B3%E4%BA%8E%E5%BF%98%E8%AE%B0%E4%BA%86%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%89%BF%E6%8B%85%E7%9A%84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;某个潜在损失越重要，我们对损失的厌恶也就越强烈。换句话说，所处情境越危险，我们越容易很快作出非理性的决定。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>某个潜在损失越重要，我们对损失的厌恶也就越强烈。换句话说，所处情境越危险，我们越容易很快作出非理性的决定。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>既然事情已经发生，请坦然面对与接受</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%97%A2%E7%84%B6%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E5%B7%B2%E7%BB%8F%E5%8F%91%E7%94%9F%E8%AF%B7%E5%9D%A6%E7%84%B6%E9%9D%A2%E5%AF%B9%E4%B8%8E%E6%8E%A5%E5%8F%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 11:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%97%A2%E7%84%B6%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E5%B7%B2%E7%BB%8F%E5%8F%91%E7%94%9F%E8%AF%B7%E5%9D%A6%E7%84%B6%E9%9D%A2%E5%AF%B9%E4%B8%8E%E6%8E%A5%E5%8F%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;每个人都发犯错，重要的是意识到错误并且止损。并且承担后果。&lt;br&gt;
把注意力放在以后，不要犯同样的错.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有沉默成本的地方就会有万元陷阱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can fail, you have to admit failure and accept it&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>每个人都发犯错，重要的是意识到错误并且止损。并且承担后果。<br>
把注意力放在以后，不要犯同样的错.</p>
<p>有沉默成本的地方就会有万元陷阱。</p>
<p>Everyone can fail, you have to admit failure and accept it</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>学校教的东西只能让你用来出售时间</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E6%95%99%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%9C%E8%A5%BF%E5%8F%AA%E8%83%BD%E8%AE%A9%E4%BD%A0%E7%94%A8%E6%9D%A5%E5%87%BA%E5%94%AE%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E6%95%99%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%9C%E8%A5%BF%E5%8F%AA%E8%83%BD%E8%AE%A9%E4%BD%A0%E7%94%A8%E6%9D%A5%E5%87%BA%E5%94%AE%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;大家都能学会的东西是不可能让你致富的。凡是可以批量化培训的技能都是能够被雇佣的技能。只有你自己学到的东西，才是属于你独有的能力，才有可能让你创业成功。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>大家都能学会的东西是不可能让你致富的。凡是可以批量化培训的技能都是能够被雇佣的技能。只有你自己学到的东西，才是属于你独有的能力，才有可能让你创业成功。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>而要追求自己真正感兴趣的事情</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%80%8C%E8%A6%81%E8%BF%BD%E6%B1%82%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9C%9F%E6%AD%A3%E6%84%9F%E5%85%B4%E8%B6%A3%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%80%8C%E8%A6%81%E8%BF%BD%E6%B1%82%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9C%9F%E6%AD%A3%E6%84%9F%E5%85%B4%E8%B6%A3%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;对一件事情的欲望越小，顾虑就越少，执念就越少，反而越会顺其自然，遵循内心。你会以自己擅长的方式，始终不渝地做下去，工作质量也会因此提高。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>对一件事情的欲望越小，顾虑就越少，执念就越少，反而越会顺其自然，遵循内心。你会以自己擅长的方式，始终不渝地做下去，工作质量也会因此提高。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>越觉得自己无所不知，规避和处置风险的方法越少。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%B6%8A%E8%A7%89%E5%BE%97%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%97%A0%E6%89%80%E4%B8%8D%E7%9F%A5%E8%A7%84%E9%81%BF%E5%92%8C%E5%A4%84%E7%BD%AE%E9%A3%8E%E9%99%A9%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95%E8%B6%8A%E5%B0%91/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%B6%8A%E8%A7%89%E5%BE%97%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%97%A0%E6%89%80%E4%B8%8D%E7%9F%A5%E8%A7%84%E9%81%BF%E5%92%8C%E5%A4%84%E7%BD%AE%E9%A3%8E%E9%99%A9%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95%E8%B6%8A%E5%B0%91/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;决策就是一切。事实上，一个决策正确率为 80% 的人比正确率为 70% 的人在市场上的价值和获得的回报要高出数百倍。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>决策就是一切。事实上，一个决策正确率为 80% 的人比正确率为 70% 的人在市场上的价值和获得的回报要高出数百倍。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pick an industry where you can play long-term games with long-term people.</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/pick-an-industry-where-you-can-play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/pick-an-industry-where-you-can-play-long-term-games-with-long-term-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pick business partners with high intelligence, energy, and, above all, integrity. ↓ Don’t partner with cynics and pessimists. Their beliefs are self-fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pick business partners with high intelligence, energy, and, above all, integrity. ↓ Don’t partner with cynics and pessimists. Their beliefs are self-fulfilling.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>在前进的过程中，方向比速度更重要，特别是运用了杠杆以后。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%9C%A8%E5%89%8D%E8%BF%9B%E7%9A%84%E8%BF%87%E7%A8%8B%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E6%AF%94%E9%80%9F%E5%BA%A6%E6%9B%B4%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%89%B9%E5%88%AB%E6%98%AF%E8%BF%90%E7%94%A8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%9C%A8%E5%89%8D%E8%BF%9B%E7%9A%84%E8%BF%87%E7%A8%8B%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E6%AF%94%E9%80%9F%E5%BA%A6%E6%9B%B4%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%89%B9%E5%88%AB%E6%98%AF%E8%BF%90%E7%94%A8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;如果有人用词花哨，动辄谈论宏大而复杂的概念，那么他们很有可能并不了解自己所谈论的东西。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>如果有人用词花哨，动辄谈论宏大而复杂的概念，那么他们很有可能并不了解自己所谈论的东西。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何确保自己是在直面现实问题？</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E7%A1%AE%E4%BF%9D%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%98%AF%E5%9C%A8%E7%9B%B4%E9%9D%A2%E7%8E%B0%E5%AE%9E%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E7%A1%AE%E4%BF%9D%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E6%98%AF%E5%9C%A8%E7%9B%B4%E9%9D%A2%E7%8E%B0%E5%AE%9E%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;要直面现实，就要放下自我，消除自我意识，忘记自我判断，平复自我情绪。人虽然是高级动物，但情绪化的自我意识的存在会带来反刍式思维，让一些欲望蒙蔽我们的双眼，让我们看不清现实，从而让我们对“世界应该怎样”妄下判断。这种情况经常发生，尤其是在把政治诉求和商业问题搅在一起时。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>要直面现实，就要放下自我，消除自我意识，忘记自我判断，平复自我情绪。人虽然是高级动物，但情绪化的自我意识的存在会带来反刍式思维，让一些欲望蒙蔽我们的双眼，让我们看不清现实，从而让我们对“世界应该怎样”妄下判断。这种情况经常发生，尤其是在把政治诉求和商业问题搅在一起时。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何确定一个人是否值得信赖？</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E7%A1%AE%E5%AE%9A%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E6%98%AF%E5%90%A6%E5%80%BC%E5%BE%97%E4%BF%A1%E8%B5%96/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E7%A1%AE%E5%AE%9A%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E6%98%AF%E5%90%A6%E5%80%BC%E5%BE%97%E4%BF%A1%E8%B5%96/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;如果一个人大谈特谈自己有多诚实，那么他很可能是不诚实的。这只是我学到的一个小小的警示信号。当一个人不断宣扬自己的价值观，或者自我吹嘘时，那就意味着他在掩饰什么&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>如果一个人大谈特谈自己有多诚实，那么他很可能是不诚实的。这只是我学到的一个小小的警示信号。当一个人不断宣扬自己的价值观，或者自我吹嘘时，那就意味着他在掩饰什么</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何达到退休状态？</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E8%BE%BE%E5%88%B0%E9%80%80%E4%BC%91%E7%8A%B6%E6%80%81/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E8%BE%BE%E5%88%B0%E9%80%80%E4%BC%91%E7%8A%B6%E6%80%81/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;第一种方法是存钱。只要存款够多，被动收入（不用动一根手指）就能满足开销。第二种方法是把开销降为零 —— 出家修行。第三种方法是做自己热爱的事情，完全乐在其中，有钱没钱无所谓。所以，实现退休状态有很多种方法。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>第一种方法是存钱。只要存款够多，被动收入（不用动一根手指）就能满足开销。第二种方法是把开销降为零 —— 出家修行。第三种方法是做自己热爱的事情，完全乐在其中，有钱没钱无所谓。所以，实现退休状态有很多种方法。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>对美好现实的渴求蒙蔽了对真实世界的认知。所谓痛苦，就是无法继续无视事实。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%AF%B9%E7%BE%8E%E5%A5%BD%E7%8E%B0%E5%AE%9E%E7%9A%84%E6%B8%B4%E6%B1%82%E8%92%99%E8%94%BD%E4%BA%86%E5%AF%B9%E7%9C%9F%E5%AE%9E%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C%E7%9A%84%E8%AE%A4%E7%9F%A5%E6%89%80%E8%B0%93/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E5%AF%B9%E7%BE%8E%E5%A5%BD%E7%8E%B0%E5%AE%9E%E7%9A%84%E6%B8%B4%E6%B1%82%E8%92%99%E8%94%BD%E4%BA%86%E5%AF%B9%E7%9C%9F%E5%AE%9E%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C%E7%9A%84%E8%AE%A4%E7%9F%A5%E6%89%80%E8%B0%93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;难点在于看清真相。要看清真相，就必须摆脱自我，因为自我不想面对真相。自我越弱小，对自己反应的限制越少，对自己想要的结果的执念越低，就越容易看清现实。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>难点在于看清真相。要看清真相，就必须摆脱自我，因为自我不想面对真相。自我越弱小，对自己反应的限制越少，对自己想要的结果的执念越低，就越容易看清现实。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>没有思考，你就不会有出色的商业创意，也不可能做出正确的判断。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E4%BD%A0%E5%B0%B1%E4%B8%8D%E4%BC%9A%E6%9C%89%E5%87%BA%E8%89%B2%E7%9A%84%E5%95%86%E4%B8%9A%E5%88%9B%E6%84%8F%E4%B9%9F%E4%B8%8D%E5%8F%AF%E8%83%BD/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E4%BD%A0%E5%B0%B1%E4%B8%8D%E4%BC%9A%E6%9C%89%E5%87%BA%E8%89%B2%E7%9A%84%E5%95%86%E4%B8%9A%E5%88%9B%E6%84%8F%E4%B9%9F%E4%B8%8D%E5%8F%AF%E8%83%BD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;悠闲的大脑才能产生伟大的创意。一个倍感压力、案牍劳形、四处奔波、焦头烂额的人，是没有办法思考的。所以，一定要为思考挤出时间。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>悠闲的大脑才能产生伟大的创意。一个倍感压力、案牍劳形、四处奔波、焦头烂额的人，是没有办法思考的。所以，一定要为思考挤出时间。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>要做到诚实，就要在发表观点时抛开自己的身份。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%A6%81%E5%81%9A%E5%88%B0%E8%AF%9A%E5%AE%9E%E5%B0%B1%E8%A6%81%E5%9C%A8%E5%8F%91%E8%A1%A8%E8%A7%82%E7%82%B9%E6%97%B6%E6%8A%9B%E5%BC%80%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9A%84%E8%BA%AB%E4%BB%BD/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E8%A6%81%E5%81%9A%E5%88%B0%E8%AF%9A%E5%AE%9E%E5%B0%B1%E8%A6%81%E5%9C%A8%E5%8F%91%E8%A1%A8%E8%A7%82%E7%82%B9%E6%97%B6%E6%8A%9B%E5%BC%80%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9A%84%E8%BA%AB%E4%BB%BD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我们每个人都有一些离经叛道的信仰，这些信仰不被社会接受。但是，我们的身份和所在的族群越是排斥这样的信仰，它就越有可能是符合现实的。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>我们每个人都有一些离经叛道的信仰，这些信仰不被社会接受。但是，我们的身份和所在的族群越是排斥这样的信仰，它就越有可能是符合现实的。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>神书《纳瓦尔宝典：财富和幸福指南》</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%A5%9E%E4%B9%A6%E7%BA%B3%E7%93%A6%E5%B0%94%E5%AE%9D%E5%85%B8%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 12:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%A5%9E%E4%B9%A6%E7%BA%B3%E7%93%A6%E5%B0%94%E5%AE%9D%E5%85%B8%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1人应该寻求财富而不是金钱或地位&#34;&gt;1、人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人不应该通过繁重的工作获得财富。&lt;br&gt;
每周花 80 小时在餐馆工作，无法使你变得更富有。&lt;br&gt;
辛勤的劳作是无法避免的，但应该以正确的方式努力。&lt;br&gt;
人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位。&lt;br&gt;
如果你认为财富不重要，财富就会远离你。&lt;br&gt;
财富就是睡觉时仍在赚钱的资产。&lt;br&gt;
没有财富性资产，你睡觉的时候，就没有任何收入；你退休的时候，就不能继续挣钱了。&lt;br&gt;
总之，没有财富，你就无法做到非线性赚钱。&lt;br&gt;
一般来说，财富是通过创办自己的公司或者投资来创造的。&lt;br&gt;
它们都不是通过投入大量时间来实现的，大富豪和你一样，每天也只有 24 小时。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="1人应该寻求财富而不是金钱或地位">1、人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位</h2>
<p>人不应该通过繁重的工作获得财富。<br>
每周花 80 小时在餐馆工作，无法使你变得更富有。<br>
辛勤的劳作是无法避免的，但应该以正确的方式努力。<br>
人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位。<br>
如果你认为财富不重要，财富就会远离你。<br>
财富就是睡觉时仍在赚钱的资产。<br>
没有财富性资产，你睡觉的时候，就没有任何收入；你退休的时候，就不能继续挣钱了。<br>
总之，没有财富，你就无法做到非线性赚钱。<br>
一般来说，财富是通过创办自己的公司或者投资来创造的。<br>
它们都不是通过投入大量时间来实现的，大富豪和你一样，每天也只有 24 小时。</p>
<h2 id="2获得财富的关键">2、获得财富的关键</h2>
<p>要获得财富，可以向社会大众提供有价值的东西——尤其是他们不知道如何获得的。<br>
而且要大规模地供应。<br>
互联网已经极大地拓宽了职业生涯的可能性，多数人对此仍没有清晰的认识。<br>
学会营销，学会创造。<br>
如果这两件都会，没有什么可以阻挡你成功。</p>
<h2 id="3用特殊知识武装你自己">3、用特殊知识武装你自己</h2>
<p>特殊知识是不可以通过培训获得的知识。<br>
如果能通过训练获得，那其他人也可以获得，然后取代你。<br>
特殊知识通常是技术含量高和创造性的。<br>
不可能被外包或自动化的。<br>
（如洞察力） 在真正的好奇心和热情驱使下，将能发现特殊的知识。<br>
创造特殊知识的过程，对你而言，感觉像是在玩，而对别人来说像是工作。<br>
通常，特殊知识在知识的边界，也就是那些现在才弄明白或者真的很难弄明白的东西。<br>
如果你没有百分之百的投入，别人百分之百投入了就会胜过你。<br>
并且他们不只是强你一点点，会比你强很多，因为在思想领域的想法，复利会起作用，杠杆也会起作用。<br>
特殊知识可能是以下这些： 销售技巧。<br>
有音乐天赋。<br>
执着的性格：这意味你能用心研究事物。<br>
热爱科幻：这意味你可以快速吸收很多知识。<br>
玩了很多游戏：这会对游戏理论比较了解。<br>
八卦：这可能帮助你成为非常有趣的记者。<br>
特殊知识是这样一种奇怪组合，来自你的 DNA，你独特的成长环境，和你对这些知识的回应。<br>
这些几乎是融入你的个性和身份的，然后你可以不断磨练它。<br>
学习微观经济学、博弈论、心理学、洗脑术、伦理学、数学和计算机科学。</p>
<h2 id="4用杠杆武装你自己">4、用杠杆武装你自己</h2>
<p>商业杠杆主要有资本、人力、复制成本极低的产品（代码和媒体）。<br>
资本就是指钱。<br>
为了融资，就需要用你特殊的知识，配合你的责任感，展示出你良好的判断力。<br>
人力就是指为你干活的人。<br>
它是最古老和争夺最激烈的杠杆。<br>
人力杠杆会让你父母感到有面子，但不要浪费生命去追求这点。<br>
资本和劳动力是需要获得许可才能使用的杠杆。<br>
人人都在追逐资本，但总得有掏钱的人。<br>
人人都想要去领导其他人，但总得有人做手下。<br>
代码和媒体是无需许可就能用的杠杆，它是新富豪背后的杠杆。<br>
你可以创建软件和媒体，它们能在你睡眠时仍为你干活。<br>
一大群机器人供免费使用——为了节约空间和热效能，它们被打包放进数据中心，去使用它们吧！ 运用特殊知识，配合杠杆，最终会得到你应该得到的。</p>
<h2 id="5一句话产品化你自己">5、一句话：产品化你自己</h2>
<p>这是什么意思呢？“产品化”和“你自己”。<br>
“你自己”有特殊性，“产品化”有杠杆性。<br>
“我在产品化它吗？我可以规模化它？我可以通过人力杠杆、或资本、或代码、或媒体放大它？”所以，这种说法非常方便记忆。<br>
如果你想更富有，你要弄清楚你可以为社会提供哪一样东西，社会还不知道如何得到的，但又是社会想要的，对你来说提供这样东西是自然而然的，它在你的技能范围内，在你的能力范围内。<br>
接着，就是想办法扩大规模，因为只生产一个是远远不够的。<br>
你可能需要生产数千份，或者数万份，或者数百万份，或者数十亿份，这样每个人都可以拥有一个。<br>
史蒂夫·乔布斯（当然包括他的团队）想清楚了社会需要智能手机。<br>
这种智能手机拥有当时手机的所有功能，同时也有更多其它的新功能，并且更容易使用。<br>
因而，他们想出了怎么制造智能手机，再接着就是想清楚怎么大规模生产智能手机。<br>
你要成为能规模化提供这些产品或服务的人。<br>
这才是如何赚钱的真正难题。</p>
<h2 id="6注意你的人品">6、注意你的人品</h2>
<p>在我的生活中，认识一些极度成功、非常受欢迎、非常聪明的人。<br>
然而，我看到他们做了一两件对其他人不太好的事情。<br>
我会说，“嘿，我认为你不应该对别人做这样的事。<br>
因为这最后会伤到你自己。<br>
” 从内心深处我们都知道自己是谁。<br>
你不可能对自己隐藏任何事。<br>
你做得对不对，你是很清楚的，如果你有太多的道德瑕疵，你将不会尊重你自己。<br>
这个世界最糟糕的结果是没有自尊。<br>
如果你都不爱你自己，谁会爱你？ 如果我看到有人做这种事，第一次我会提醒他们，不过通常他们不会改，然后我就和他们保持距离。<br>
我把他们从我的生活切割出去。<br>
如果有人总说他们自己是多么的诚实，他们很有可能是不诚实的。<br>
这只是一些我学到的有效指标。<br>
当有人花很多时间在谈论他们的价值观或谈论他们自己时，意味着他们在掩盖某些事。<br>
我在心里说：“想靠近我的，你的价值观必须要比我更好。<br>
”</p>
<h2 id="7聪明人真的了解一件事">7、聪明人真的了解一件事</h2>
<p>如果有人使用很多复杂的词汇和很多大概念，他们很有可能不知道他们自己在谈论什么。<br>
我认为最聪明的人能把事情向小孩子讲明白。<br>
如果你无法向小孩子讲明白，那么你并不是真的知道。<br>
真正聪明的思考者是思维清晰的思考者，他们理解非常非常基本的基础知识。</p>
<h2 id="8跳出自己看真相">8、跳出自己看真相</h2>
<p>想象我的某位朋友正在经历某些困难的事，如分手、事业、生意失败或健康问题，当他需要我的建议时，往往只需几分钟，我就能准确告诉他，“噢，那个女孩，忘掉她吧，反正她对你不好。<br>
你将会更快乐。<br>
相信我。<br>
你将来会找到更合适的。<br>
” 但他自己就很难看明白这点。<br>
因为他正处于痛苦和折磨中，他的愿望与现实是有冲突的，从而阻止了他看清真相。<br>
同样的事会发生在我们做决定的时候。<br>
为了看清真相，你必须要放下自我，因为自我并不想面对真相。</p>
<h2 id="9真正重要的是闲暇时间">9、真正重要的是闲暇时间</h2>
<p>只有在你感到无聊之后，才会有伟大的想法。<br>
好的想法从不会在你充满压力、忙碌、四处奔波或仓促的时候出现。<br>
如果你的日程表每周没有一两天是不用一直开会、不用一直在忙的，你就无法去思考。<br>
你也不会有和你生意相关的好想法。<br>
你也不可能做出好的判断。<br>
我鼓励每周至少拿出一天（更好的是有两天，因为预备两天的话，你肯定能抽出一天），这样你就有时间去思考了。<br>
珍惜你的时间，它是你的全部。<br>
它比你的金钱更重要。<br>
它比你的朋友更重要。<br>
它比任何东西都重要。<br>
你的时间就是你的一切。<br>
不要浪费你的时间。</p>
<h2 id="10读书能让你成功">10、读书能让你成功</h2>
<p>每天花一小时阅读科学、数学和哲学，很有可能在七年内让你登上人类成功的高层梯队。<br>
我花了很多时间看书。<br>
我唯一真正的朋友是书。<br>
书是伟大的朋友，因为过去几千年来最好的思想家会告诉你他们的智慧。<br>
任何一本能存活两千多年的书，都是经过很多人筛选的，也更有可能是正确的，我想重新读这些书。<br>
事实是，我读书不是为了自我提升。<br>
我阅读是出于好奇和兴趣。<br>
最好的书就是你会着迷的那本。</p>
<h2 id="11为自己的目标做事">11、为自己的目标做事</h2>
<p>我只是真正想为自己的目标而做事。<br>
无论是生意、健身、恋爱、友谊，还是其它的，我认为生命的意义是为自己的目标而做事。<br>
当你为自己而做事时，你能创造出你最好的作品。<br>
即使你做这些是为了赚钱，但实际上你也将会是最成功的。<br>
追随你真正的好奇心，而不是时下的热点事物。<br>
如果你的好奇心把你带到一个社会最终也会去的地方，你将会获得丰厚的报酬。<br>
当你约会的时候，有某个瞬间认识到这段关系不会通往婚姻时，你或许应该继续前行了。<br>
当你在学习某些东西时，例如地理或历史课，你意识到你永远也不会用到这些信息，就放弃这门课程。<br>
这是在浪费时间。<br>
这是在浪费脑力。</p>
<h2 id="12成为一个整体上更好的决策者">12、成为一个整体上更好的决策者</h2>
<p>成为一个整体上更好的决策者。<br>
决策是一切。<br>
是的。<br>
决策是一切。<br>
事实上，有人在 80%的时间而不是 70%的时间都能够做出正确的决策，他在市场中的价值和报酬将高出数百倍。<br>
我认为人们很难去理解杠杆的一个基本事实。<br>
如果我掌管着 10 亿美元，且我经常比其他人多 10%的正确率，我的决策能在一次判断上带来一亿美元的价值。<br>
拥有现代技术和庞大的劳动力以及资本，我们的决策能被杠杆放大的倍率越来越高。<br>
如果我面对一个困难的选择，像下面这些问题： 我应该和这个人结婚吗？ 我应该做这个工作吗？ 我应该买这间房子吗？ 我应该搬到这个城市吗？ 我应该和这个人合伙做生意吗？ 如果你无法下决定，就回答否。<br>
原因是，现代社会充满了选择。<br>
有非常多的选择。<br>
我们生活在一个有 70 亿人的星球，我们可以通过互联网联系到每个人。<br>
有数十万种职业供你选择。<br>
有如此多的选择。<br>
当你选择某些事物时，你会被锁定一段很长的时间。<br>
创业可能需要花费 10 年。<br>
你开始一段感情可能需要 5 年或者更多。<br>
你搬到一个城市可能会待上 10 到 20 年。<br>
这些都是有非常非常长期影响的决定。<br>
只有在我们十分确定的时候才会说”是“。<br>
你从不可能做到绝对确定，但你要做到非常肯定。<br>
如果你有两个选择，并且是相对均等的选择，那么就选择在短期内更困难和更痛苦的那条路。<br>
实际情况是，其中一条路要承受短期的痛苦。<br>
另一条路是在未来在更远的地方才会感到痛苦。<br>
然而，你的大脑想要避免冲突而试图去避开短期的痛苦。<br>
按照定义，如果两个选择是差不多的，其中一个有短期痛苦，那么这个选择就和长期收益有关。<br>
根据复利法则，长期收益是你想要得到的。<br>
你的大脑过于看重短期的幸福，而试图去避免短期的痛苦。<br>
咖啡因是另外一种用长期后果换取短期利益的东西。<br>
本质上，你必须透过你的生活，用好的习惯去替换你不经意养成的坏习惯，承诺成为一个更快乐的人。</p>
<h2 id="13关于幸福">13、关于幸福</h2>
<p>孔子说，人有两次生命，第二次生命始于你意识到生命只有一次之时。<br>
那你第二次生命是在什么时候、怎样开始的呢？（孔子说：我没有说过这样的话。<br>
） 我读过布莱斯·帕斯卡（Blaise Pascal）的一句话。<br>
大概意思是：“人类的全部不幸是因为他们不能安静地待在他们的房间里。<br>
”如果你坐上 30 分钟并感觉到快乐，你就是成功的。<br>
这是非常强的境界，不过很少人能做到。<br>
你要学习的核心技能是，在大多数情况下做到随遇而安、顺势而为。<br>
你可以从生活中得到几乎任何你想要的东西，只要它是你最想得到的东西。<br>
处理冲突的第一规则是：不要和那些经常发生冲突的人在一起。<br>
我对不能持久或难以持续的事物不感兴趣，包括问题多多的关系。</p>
<h2 id="14人生的头等大事">14、人生的头等大事</h2>
<p>我人生的头等大事，高于我的幸福，高于我的家庭，高于我的工作，就是我自己的健康。<br>
首先是我的身体健康。<br>
第二，是我的心理健康。<br>
第三，是我的精神健康。<br>
然后，是我家人的健康。<br>
然后，是我家庭的幸福。<br>
在那之后，我就可以去世界其它地方做任何我需要做的事情了。<br>
基本上，每当你把好习惯推荐给别人时，他们都会为自己找一个借口，通常最普遍的借口就是“我没有时间”。<br>
你听到这个，就知道他是在说“这不是高优先级事项”。<br>
如果某些事是你的头等大事，你就会去做。<br>
这就是生活运转的方式。<br>
如果你有 10 到 15 个优先级很含糊而又不着急的事项，你最终不会做它们之中的任何一个。<br>
我所做的就是决定我人生中的头等大事，高于我的幸福，高于我的家庭，高于我的工作，那就是我的健康。<br>
我的身体健康成为了我的头等大事，那样我就永远也不能说我没有时间。<br>
早晨，我锻炼身体，不管需要多长时间，我都会坚持锻炼。<br>
未锻炼完，我不会开始一天的工作。<br>
我不在乎世界是否正在崩溃和融化，它可以再等 30 分钟，直到我锻炼完。<br>
就像生活中的其它事情一样，如果你愿意做出短期的牺牲，你就会有长期的好处。<br>
“容易的选择，艰难的生活。<br>
艰难的选择，轻松的生活。<br>
”</p>
<h2 id="15不和自己的想法斗争">15、不和自己的想法斗争</h2>
<p>不要把自己看得太重。<br>
你只是一只有计划的猴子而已。<br>
不做任何决定，不下任何判断，只是接受一切。<br>
如果我一边走一边这样做十到十五分钟，我会进入一种非常平静、感恩的状态。<br>
无选择的意识对我很有用。<br>
我学到的另一个方法是，坐在那里，闭上眼睛，每天至少一个小时。<br>
你向任何发生的事情屈服——不做任何努力。<br>
你不为做某些事情而努力，也不为反对某些事情而努力。<br>
如果有想法在你的脑海流动，你就随这些想法流动。<br>
“如果想法来了，想法来了。<br>
我不和它们做斗争。<br>
我也不会去拥抱它们。<br>
我不会去想它们。<br>
我不会去拒绝它们。<br>
我就只是闭着眼睛在那里坐上一个小时，什么也不做。<br>
” 这是一种快乐、幸福和平静的状态。<br>
一旦你拥有它，你就不想放弃它。<br>
如果你每天早上只需坐着闭上眼睛，就能获得一个小时幸福的自由时光，那是超值的。<br>
它将改变你的生活。<br>
你所要做的就是坐在那里，什么也不要做。<br>
就只是坐下来。<br>
闭上你的眼睛说：“我只是想让自己休息一个小时。这是我远离生活的一个小时，这个小时我什么也不做”</p>
<h2 id="16让意识和心灵协调相处">16、让意识和心灵协调相处</h2>
<p>佛教徒谈论意识与自我，他们真的是把你的大脑当做一个多层次的机制：内核级的操作系统在运行，然后，还有一些应用程序在上面运行。<br>
我正在回到我意识层的操作系统，它总是平静的，总是平和的，通常是快乐和满足的。<br>
我试着保持在这样的状态下，而不是激活猴心（指意识层面之下的难以控制的心灵）。<br>
猴心总是担心、害怕和焦虑，它有不可思议的作用，但我尽量不激活它，直到我需要它。<br>
如果我 24 个小时不间断地运行它，我就会浪费能量，而猴心就会成了我，我比我的猴心更重要。<br>
心灵本身就是一种肌肉——它可以被训练和调节，但它已经被社会胡乱地调教成了我们无法控制的样子。<br>
如果你带着意识和意图去审视你的心智，我想你可以把自己的思想、情绪、思想和反应都提取出来，然后你就可以开始重新设置了。<br>
你可以按照自己的意愿来重写这个程序。</p>
<h2 id="17如何定义智慧">17、如何定义智慧？</h2>
<p>一个人理解他所作所为的的长期后果。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
