<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Journal on xgDebug&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/tags/reading-journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Journal on xgDebug&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>xgDebug&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://www.xgdebug.com/images/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/images/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.136.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 21:35:24 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.xgdebug.com/tags/reading-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Just Keep Buying</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/etf/just-keep-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 21:35:24 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/etf/just-keep-buying/</guid>
      <description>After you stop working your 9 to 5, your money can keep working for you.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After you stop working your 9 to 5, your money can keep working for you.<br>
停下你的朝九晚五工作后，你的钱可以继续为你工作。</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="build-up-financial-capital-to-replace-human-capital.jpg" alt="build up financial capital to replace human capital"  />
</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules">Conclusion: The Just Keep Buying Rules</h2>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 281 · Location 4366</strong><br>
Saving is for the Poor, Investing is for the Rich Find where you are in your financial journey before deciding where to focus your time and energy. If your expected savings are greater than your expected investment income, focus on savings; otherwise focus on investing. If they are similar, focus on both. (Ch. 1)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 281 · Location 4370</strong><br>
Save What You Can Your income and spending are rarely fixed, so your savings rate shouldn’t be fixed either. Save what you can to reduce your financial stress. (Ch. 2)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 281 · Location 4373</strong><br>
Focus on Income, Not Spending Cutting spending has its limits, but growing your income doesn’t. Find small ways to grow your income today that can turn into big ways to grow it tomorrow. (Ch. 3)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 281 · Location 4376</strong><br>
Use The 2x Rule to Eliminate Spending Guilt If you ever feel guilty about splurging on yourself, invest the same amount of money into income-producing assets or donate to a good cause. This is the easiest way to have worry-free spending. (Ch. 4)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 282 · Location 4379</strong><br>
Save at Least 50% of Your Future Raises and Bonuses A little lifestyle creep is okay, but keep it below 50% of your future raises if you want to stay on track. (Ch. 5)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 282 · Location 4382</strong><br>
Debt Isn’t Good or Bad, It Depends on How You Use It Debt can be harmful in some scenarios and helpful in others. Use debt only when it can be most beneficial for your finances. (Ch. 6)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 282 · Location 4385</strong><br>
Only Buy a Home When the Time Is Right Buying a home will probably be the biggest financial decision you ever make. As a result, you should only do it when it fits into both your finances and your current lifestyle. (Ch.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 282 · Location 4388</strong><br>
When Saving for a Big Purchase, Use Cash Though bonds and stocks may earn you more while you wait, when saving for a wedding, home, or other big purchase, cash is the way to go. (Ch. 8)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 282 · Location 4391</strong><br>
Retirement is About More Than Money Before you decide what to retire from, make sure you know what you want to retire to. (Ch. 9)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 283 · Location 4394</strong><br>
Invest to Replace Your Waning Human Capital with Financial Capital You won’t be able to work forever, so replace your human capital with financial capital before it’s too late. Investing is the best way to accomplish this. (Ch. 10)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 283 · Location 4397</strong><br>
Think Like an Owner and Buy Income-Producing Assets To really grow your income, think like an owner and use your money to buy income-producing assets. (Ch. 11)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 283 · Location 4400</strong><br>
Don’t Buy Individual Stocks Buying individual stocks and expecting to outperform is like flipping a coin. You might succeed, but even if you do, how do you know it wasn’t just luck? (Ch. 12)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 283 · Location 4402</strong><br>
Buy Quickly, Sell Slowly Since most markets are expected to rise over time, buying quickly and selling slowly is the optimal way to maximize your wealth. If you don’t feel comfortable with this, then what you are buying/ selling might be too risky for you. (Ch. 13, 18)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 283 · Location 4406</strong><br>
Invest As Often As You Can If you think you can time the market by saving up cash, think again. Even God couldn’t beat dollar-cost averaging. (Ch. 14)
Note - Page 283 · Location 4409
绝对不可能</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 284 · Location 4409</strong><br>
Investing Isn’t About the Cards You Are Dealt, but How You Play Your Hand You will experience periods of good and bad luck throughout your investing career. However, the most important thing is how you behave over the long term. (Ch. 15)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 284 · Location 4412</strong><br>
Don’t Fear Volatility When It Inevitably Comes Markets won’t give you a free ride without some bumps along the way. Don’t forget that you have to experience some downside if you want to earn your upside. (Ch. 16)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 284 · Location 4415</strong><br>
Market Crashes Are (Usually) Buying Opportunities Future returns are usually the highest following major crashes. Don’t be afraid to take advantage of these crashes when they periodically occur. (Ch. 17)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 284 · Location 4418</strong><br>
Fund the Life You Need Before You Risk it for the Life You Want Though this book is called Just Keep Buying, sometimes it’s okay to sell. After all, what’s the point of building your wealth if you don’t do anything with it? (Ch. 18)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 284 · Location 4421</strong><br>
Don’t Max Out Your 401( k) Without Considerable Thought The annual benefit of a 401( k) can be less than you think. Before you lock up your money for multiple decades, consider what else you might need it for instead. (Ch. 19)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 285 · Location 4424</strong><br>
You’ll Never Feel Rich and That’s Okay No matter how successful you get with your money, there will always be someone with more. If you win the financial game, make sure you don’t lose yourself in the process. (Ch. 20)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 285 · Location 4428</strong><br>
Time is Your Most Important Asset You can always earn more money, but nothing can buy you more time. (Ch. 21)</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 9 · Location 118</strong><br>
To build wealth it didn’t matter when you bought U.S. stocks, just that you bought them and kept buying them. It didn’t matter if valuations were high or low. It didn’t matter if you were in a bull market or a bear market. All that mattered was that you kept buying.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 10 · Location 124</strong><br>
When I say income-producing assets, I mean those assets that you expect to generate income for you far into the future, even if that income isn’t paid directly to you. This includes stocks, bonds, real estate, and much more. However, the specifics of the strategy are not critically important.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - Page 10 · Location 127</strong><br>
It’s not about when to buy, how much to buy, or what to buy—just to keep buying.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 1. Where Should You Start? &gt; Page 13 · Location 171</strong><br>
saving is for the poor and investing is for the rich</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 1. Where Should You Start? &gt; Page 15 · Location 207</strong><br>
First, figure out how much you expect to comfortably save in the next year.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 1. Where Should You Start? &gt; Page 15 · Location 210</strong><br>
Next, determine how much you expect your investments to grow in the next year (in dollar terms).</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 1. Where Should You Start? &gt; Page 15 · Location 213</strong><br>
Finally, compare the two numbers. Which is higher, your expected savings or your expected investment growth?</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 1. Where Should You Start? &gt; Page 15 · Location 215</strong><br>
If your expected savings are higher, then you need to focus more on saving money and adding to your investments. However, if your expected investment growth is higher, then spend more time thinking about how to invest what you already have. If the numbers are close to each other, then you should spend time on both.</p>
<h2 id="i-saving">I. Saving</h2>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 36 · Location 526</strong><br>
This is why it is so much easier for higher income households to save money—they don’t spend on necessities at the same rate, relative to their income, as lower income households.
Note - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 36 · Location 528
储蓄率</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 37 · Location 546</strong><br>
“Why Do People Stay Poor?”</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 37 · Location 550</strong><br>
“[ We] find that, if the program pushes individuals above a threshold level of initial assets, then they escape poverty, but, if it does not, they slide back into poverty… Our findings imply that large one-off transfers that enable people to take on more productive occupations can help alleviate persistent poverty.” 18</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 38 · Location 554</strong><br>
many poor people stay poor not because of their talent/ motivation, but because they are in low-paying jobs that they must work to survive.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 38 · Location 560</strong><br>
This is why the biggest lie in personal finance is that you can be rich if you just cut your spending.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 39 · Location 577</strong><br>
If you want to save more, the main point is to tighten up where you can, then focus on increasing your income.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 39 · Location 587</strong><br>
Sell Your Time/ Expertise Sell a Skill/ Service Teach People Sell a Product Climb the Corporate Ladder</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 40 · Location 603</strong><br>
Selling Your Time Summary Pros: Easy to do. Low startup cost. Cons: Time is limited. Doesn’t scale.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 41 · Location 618</strong><br>
Selling a Skill/ Service Summary Pros: Higher pay. Able to build a brand. Cons: Need to invest time to develop marketable skill/ service. Doesn’t scale easily.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 42 · Location 633</strong><br>
Teaching People Summary Pros: Easily scalable. Cons: Lots of competition. Attracting students can be an ongoing battle.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 42 · Location 639</strong><br>
The best way to do this is to identify a problem and then build a product to solve it. The problem could be emotional, mental, physical, or financial in nature. Whatever you decide on, solving a problem through a product helps you create scalable value.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 43 · Location 647</strong><br>
Selling a Product Summary Pros: Scalable. Cons: Lots of upfront investment and constant marketing.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 44 · Location 671</strong><br>
Climbing the Corporate Ladder Summary Pros: Gain skills and experience. Less risk around income growth. Cons: You don’t control your time or what you do.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 3. How To Save More &gt; Page 44 · Location 676</strong><br>
Regardless of how you try to increase your income in the future, all of the methods above should be viewed as temporary measures. I say temporary because, ultimately, your extra income should be used to acquire more income-producing assets. That’s how you really give your savings a boost.</p>
<h2 id="ii-investing">II. Investing</h2>
<p>Bookmark - 10. Why Should You Invest? &gt; Page 114 · Location 1803</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 10. Why Should You Invest? &gt; Page 115 · Location 1827</strong><br>
why you should invest: To save for your future self. To preserve your money against inflation. To replace your human capital with financial capital.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 10. Why Should You Invest? &gt; Page 118 · Location 1871</strong><br>
with an inflation rate of 5% annually, purchasing power is halved every 14 years.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 127 · Location 2020</strong><br>
It is this highly volatile nature of stocks that makes them difficult to hold during turbulent times. Seeing a decade’s worth of growth disappear in a matter of days can be gut-wrenching even for the most seasoned investors.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 127 · Location 2023</strong><br>
The best way to combat such emotional volatility is to focus on the long term. While this does not guarantee returns, the evidence of history suggests that, with enough time, stocks tend to make up for their periodic losses. Time is an equity investor’s friend.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 128 · Location 2041</strong><br>
Stocks Summary Average compounded annual return: 8%–10%. Pros: High historic returns. Easy to own and trade. Low maintenance (someone else runs the business). Cons: High volatility. Valuations can change quickly based on sentiment rather than fundamentals.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 130 · Location 2076</strong><br>
Why You Should/ Shouldn’t Invest in Bonds I recommend bonds because of these characteristics: Bonds tend to rise when stocks (and other risky assets) fall. Bonds have a more consistent income stream than other assets. Bonds can provide liquidity to rebalance your portfolio or cover liabilities.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 133 · Location 2113</strong><br>
Bonds Summary Average compounded annual return: 2%–4% (can approach 0% in a low-rate environment). Pros: Lower volatility. Good for rebalancing. Safety of principal. Cons: Low returns, especially after inflation. Not great for income in a low-yield environment.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 136 · Location 2156</strong><br>
Investment Property Summary Average compounded annual return: 12%–15% (dependent on local rental conditions). Pros: Higher returns than other more traditional asset classes, especially when using leverage. Cons: Managing the property and tenants can be a headache. Hard to diversify.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 138 · Location 2199</strong><br>
REITs Summary Average compounded annual return: 10%–12%. Pros: Real estate exposure that you don’t have to manage. Less correlated with stocks during good times. Cons: Volatility greater than or equal to stocks. Less liquidity for non-traded REITs. Highly correlated with stocks and other risk assets during stock market crashes.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 142 · Location 2278</strong><br>
Small Business Summary Average compounded annual return: 20%–25%, but expect lots of losers. Pros: Can have extremely outsized returns. The more involved you are, the more future opportunities you will see. Cons: Huge time commitment. Lots of failures can be discouraging.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 147 · Location 2351</strong><br>
What About Gold, Crypto, Art, Etc? A handful of asset classes did not make the above list for the simple reason that they don’t produce income. Gold, cryptocurrency, commodities, art, and wine have no reliable income stream associated with their ownership, so I have not included them in my list of income-producing assets. Of course, this does not mean that you can’t make money with these assets. What it does mean is that their valuations are based solely on perception—what someone else is willing to pay for them. Without underlying cash flows, perception is everything.
Note - 11. What Should You Invest In? &gt; Page 147 · Location 2357
没有现金流</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 12. Why You Shouldn’t Buy Individual Stocks &gt; Page 150 · Location 2456</strong><br>
Why You Shouldn’t Buy Individual Stocks</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 12. Why You Shouldn’t Buy Individual Stocks &gt; Page 151 · Location 2487</strong><br>
The mental turmoil. The fear of missing out. The elation, triumph, pain, and regret. It was all perfectly packaged into a single two-hour window. Battling emotions is just the tip of the stock picking iceberg. I know because I used to pick stocks years ago as well. In addition to the emotional difficulties, you also have to deal with periods of underperformance and the possibility that you don’t actually have any stock picking skill.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 12. Why You Shouldn’t Buy Individual Stocks &gt; Page 157 · Location 2576</strong><br>
“The very best way to learn about the dangers of individual stock investing is to familiarize yourself with the basics of finance and the empirical literature. But if you can’t do that, then, sure, what you have to do is put 5% or 10% of your money into individual stocks. And make sure you rigorously calculate your return, your annualized return, and then ask yourself, ‘Could I have done better just by buying a total stock market index fund?’” 82</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 161 · Location 2649</strong><br>
Most stock markets go up most of the time. This is true despite the chaotic and sometimes destructive course of human history. As Warren Buffett so eloquently stated: “In the 20th century, the United States endured two world wars and other traumatic and expensive military conflicts; the Depression; a dozen or so recessions and financial panics; oil shocks; a flu epidemic; and the resignation of a disgraced president. Yet the Dow rose from 66 to 11,497.”</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 161 · Location 2658</strong><br>
Given this empirical evidence, it suggests that you should invest your money as soon as possible. Why is this? Because most markets going up most of the time means that every day you end up waiting to invest usually means higher prices you will have to pay in the future. So, instead of waiting for the best time to get invested, you should just take the plunge and invest what you can now.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 161 · Location 2664</strong><br>
Imagine you have been gifted $ 1 million and you want to grow it as much as possible over the next 100 years. However, you can only undertake one of two possible investment strategies. You must either: Invest all your cash now, or Invest 1% of your cash each year for the next 100 years. Which would you prefer? If we assume that the assets you are investing in will increase in value over time (otherwise why would you be investing?), then it should be clear that buying now will be better than buying over the course of 100 years. Waiting a century to get invested means buying at ever higher prices while your uninvested cash also loses value to inflation.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 162 · Location 2676</strong><br>
“The best time to start was yesterday. The next best time is today.”</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 163 · Location 2684</strong><br>
Why Better Prices in the Future are Likely (And Why You Shouldn’t Wait for Them)</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 176 · Location 2909</strong><br>
If you think that the market is overvalued and due for a major pullback, you may need to wait years, if ever, before you are vindicated. Consider this before you use valuation as an excuse to stay in cash.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 176 · Location 2911</strong><br>
Final Summary When deciding between investing all your money now or over time, it is almost always better to invest it now. This is true across all asset classes, time periods, and nearly all valuation regimes. Generally, the longer you wait to deploy your capital, the worse off you will be.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 177 · Location 2915</strong><br>
I say generally because the only time when you are better off by averaging-in over time is while the market is crashing. However, it is precisely when the market is crashing that you will be the least enthusiastic to invest.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 177 · Location 2917</strong><br>
It is difficult to fight off these emotions, which is why many investors won’t be able to keep buying as the market falls anyways.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 177 · Location 2919</strong><br>
If you are still worried about investing a large sum of money right now, the problem may be that you’re considering a portfolio that is too risky for your liking. What’s the solution to this? Invest your money now into a more conservative portfolio than you normally would.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 13. How Soon Should You Invest? &gt; Page 177 · Location 2921</strong><br>
If your target allocation is a 80/ 20 stock/ bond portfolio, you might want to consider investing it all into a 60/ 40 stock/ bond portfolio and transitioning it over time.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 14. Why You Shouldn’t Wait to Buy the Dip &gt; Page 178 · Location 2939</strong><br>
14. Why You Shouldn’t Wait to Buy the Dip Even God couldn’t beat dollar-cost averaging</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 14. Why You Shouldn’t Wait to Buy the Dip &gt; Page 179 · Location 2961</strong><br>
Why is this true? Because buying the dip only works when you know that a severe decline is coming and you can time it perfectly.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 14. Why You Shouldn’t Wait to Buy the Dip &gt; Page 179 · Location 2962</strong><br>
The problem is that severe market declines don’t happen too often. In U.S. market history severe dips have only taken place in the 1930s, 1970s, and 2000s. That’s rare. This means that Buy the Dip only has a small chance of beating DCA.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 14. Why You Shouldn’t Wait to Buy the Dip &gt; Page 189 · Location 3050</strong><br>
You should invest as soon and as often as you can.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 16. Why You Shouldn’t Fear Volatility &gt; Page 204 · Location 3269</strong><br>
How much would the market have to decline in the next year for you to forgo investing in stocks altogether to invest in bonds instead?</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 16. Why You Shouldn’t Fear Volatility &gt; Page 208 · Location 3308</strong><br>
The answer is 15% and above.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 16. Why You Shouldn’t Fear Volatility &gt; Page 212 · Location 3341</strong><br>
“If you’re not willing to react with equanimity to a market price decline of 50% two or three times a century, you’re not fit to be a common shareholder and you deserve the mediocre result you’re going to get.”</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 17. How to Buy During a Crisis &gt; Page 221 · Location 3457</strong><br>
As you can see, when U.S. equity markets have gotten cut in half, the future annualized returns usually exceed 25%. This implies that when the market is down by 50%, it’s time to back up the truck and invest as much as you can afford. Of course, you may not have a lot of investable cash to take advantage of these rare occurrences when the market is in turmoil, because of wider economic uncertainty. However, if you do have the cash to spare then the data suggests that it would be wise to take advantage of this buying opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 226 · Location 3523</strong><br>
When Should You Sell? On rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 226 · Location 3530</strong><br>
fear of missing out on the upside and the fear of losing money on the downside. This emotional vice can make you question every investment decision that you make.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 226 · Location 3532</strong><br>
To avoid this mental turmoil, you should come up with a set of conditions under which you would sell beforehand instead of relying on your emotional state when you are thinking of getting out of a position. This will allow you to sell your investments on your own terms, to a predefined plan. After coming up with a list of reasons myself, I can only find three cases under which you should consider selling an investment: To rebalance. To get out of a concentrated (or losing) position. To meet your financial needs. If you aren’t rebalancing your portfolio, getting out of a concentrated (or losing) position, or trying to meet a financial need, then I see no reason to sell an investment—ever.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 227 · Location 3546</strong><br>
it’s usually better to buy immediately rather than over time. The reasoning was simple: since most markets go up most of the time, waiting to buy usually means losing out on upside. When it comes to selling an asset, we can use the same set of reasoning, but come to the opposite conclusion. Since markets tend to go up over time, the optimal thing to do is to sell as late as possible. Therefore, selling over time (or as late as possible) is usually better than selling right away.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 227 · Location 3553</strong><br>
buy quickly, but sell slowly.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 228 · Location 3559</strong><br>
What’s Rebalancing Good for Anyways? “Perfectly balanced, as all things should be.”</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 231 · Location 3593</strong><br>
Given that rebalancing doesn’t typically enhance returns, why do people still do it? To reduce risk.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 234 · Location 3629</strong><br>
result, I recommend an annual rebalance for two reasons: It takes less time. It coincides with our annual tax season.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 234 · Location 3642</strong><br>
Whatever you decide to do when it comes to rebalancing frequency, avoiding unnecessary taxation is a must. This is why I don’t recommend rebalancing frequently in your taxable accounts (i.e., brokerage account). Because every time you do, you have to pay Uncle Sam.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 235 · Location 3647</strong><br>
While selling an asset to rebalance isn’t the worst thing in the world, there is a way to rebalance your portfolio that involves no tax consequences at all—Just Keep Buying. That’s right. You can buy your way back into a rebalanced portfolio. I call this an accumulation rebalance because you are rebalancing by buying your most underweight asset over time.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 239 · Location 3707</strong><br>
The point is that underperformance is inevitable and not a good reason to sell.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 18. When Should You Sell? &gt; Page 240 · Location 3719</strong><br>
Fund the life you need before you risk it for the life you want.</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 20. Why You Will Never Feel Rich &gt; Page 261 · Location 4053</strong><br>
Why You Will Never Feel Rich And why you probably already are</p>
<p><strong>Highlight(yellow) - 21. The Most Important Asset &gt; Page 272 · Location 4217</strong><br>
The Most Important Asset And why you’ll never get any more of it</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saving Is for the Poor and Investing Is for the Rich</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/stock/saving-is-for-the-poor-and-investing-is-for-the-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 13:55:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/stock/saving-is-for-the-poor-and-investing-is-for-the-rich/</guid>
      <description>不同阶段做不同的事,没钱的时候先卖力气搞钱，别想些没用的</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>First, figure out how much you expect to comfortably save in the next year.</li>
<li>Next, determine how much you expect your investments to grow in the next year.</li>
<li>Finally, compare the two numbers. Which is higher, your expected savings or your expected investment growth?</li>
</ul>
<p>If your expected savings are higher, then you need to focus more on saving money and adding to your investments. However, if your expected investment growth is higher, then spend more time thinking about how to invest what you already have. If the numbers are close to each other, then you should spend time on both.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Always Say Less Than Necessary</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/always-say-less-than-necessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 21:57:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/always-say-less-than-necessary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;父母于一年教我们学会开口说话。&lt;br&gt;
而我们要用一生的时间来学会闭嘴。&lt;br&gt;
当你尝试使用语言来打动别人时，你说得越多，就显得越平庸，并且说得越多错得越多。&lt;br&gt;
语带禅机差不多是这么个意思，说得越少，未知越多，而人类天性恐惧未知。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>父母于一年教我们学会开口说话。<br>
而我们要用一生的时间来学会闭嘴。<br>
当你尝试使用语言来打动别人时，你说得越多，就显得越平庸，并且说得越多错得越多。<br>
语带禅机差不多是这么个意思，说得越少，未知越多，而人类天性恐惧未知。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>锋芒不可太露,会引发嫉妒与恐惧</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/never-outshine-the-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 21:33:45 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/never-outshine-the-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;人人都是武大郎，开店的时候不喜欢店员比自己高。&lt;br&gt;
刘邦那样可以驾驭比自己厉害的人太少你也遇不上。&lt;br&gt;
绝大多数的领导都是武大郎，所以你在显示自己能力的时候，可能会让他们对你忌惮。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>人人都是武大郎，开店的时候不喜欢店员比自己高。<br>
刘邦那样可以驾驭比自己厉害的人太少你也遇不上。<br>
绝大多数的领导都是武大郎，所以你在显示自己能力的时候，可能会让他们对你忌惮。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Always make those above you feel comfortably superior.<br>
In your desire to please and impress them, do not go too far in displaying your talents or you mighr accomplish the opposite &ndash; inspire fear and insecurity.<br>
Make your master appear more brilliant the the are and you will attain the hights of power.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一个人生的哲学：不要看这个人对你怎么样，要看她对周围其他人怎么样。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E7%94%9F%E7%9A%84%E5%93%B2%E5%AD%A6%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9C%8B%E8%BF%99%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%AF%B9%E4%BD%A0%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E6%A0%B7%E8%A6%81%E7%9C%8B/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 01:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/philosophy/%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E7%94%9F%E7%9A%84%E5%93%B2%E5%AD%A6%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E7%9C%8B%E8%BF%99%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%AF%B9%E4%BD%A0%E6%80%8E%E4%B9%88%E6%A0%B7%E8%A6%81%E7%9C%8B/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;一个人的行为习惯往往是长期养成的，并反映了其内在的价值观和信念。&lt;br&gt;
一个人如果对待周围其他人都是友善、尊重和善良的，那么他/她也更有可能对你是友好的。反之，如果一个人对待周围其他人都是冷漠、自私和无礼的，那么他/她也更有可能对你是冷漠、自私和无礼的。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>一个人的行为习惯往往是长期养成的，并反映了其内在的价值观和信念。<br>
一个人如果对待周围其他人都是友善、尊重和善良的，那么他/她也更有可能对你是友好的。反之，如果一个人对待周围其他人都是冷漠、自私和无礼的，那么他/她也更有可能对你是冷漠、自私和无礼的。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>容忍傻子，理解傻子，收割傻子。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E5%AE%B9%E5%BF%8D%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90%E7%90%86%E8%A7%A3%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90%E6%94%B6%E5%89%B2%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 09:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E5%AE%B9%E5%BF%8D%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90%E7%90%86%E8%A7%A3%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90%E6%94%B6%E5%89%B2%E5%82%BB%E5%AD%90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;别动上层人的利益，也别动下层人的观念，动上层人的利益犹如要他性命，动下层人的观念犹如刨他祖坟，而下层观念正是上层利益的来源。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>别动上层人的利益，也别动下层人的观念，动上层人的利益犹如要他性命，动下层人的观念犹如刨他祖坟，而下层观念正是上层利益的来源。</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 06:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. The same way that money multiplies through compound interest, the effects of your habits multiply as you repeat them. They seem to make little difference on any given day and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &amp;gt; Location 313&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;。人们做了一些小的改变，没有看到切实的结果，并决定停止。你会想，“我已经连续一个月每天都跑步了，为什么我的身体没有任何变化？一旦这种想法占据了上风，就很容易让好习惯被抛在一边。但为了产生有意义的改变，习惯需要持续足够长的时间才能突破这个高原——我称之为潜在潜力高原。 People make a few small changes, fail to see a tangible result, and decide to stop. You think, “I’ve been running every day for a month, so why can’t I see any change in my body?” Once this kind of thinking takes over, it’s easy to let good habits fall by the wayside. But in order to make a meaningful difference, habits need to persist long enough to break through this plateau—what I call the Plateau of Latent Potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. The same way that money multiplies through compound interest, the effects of your habits multiply as you repeat them. They seem to make little difference on any given day and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 313</p>
<p>。人们做了一些小的改变，没有看到切实的结果，并决定停止。你会想，“我已经连续一个月每天都跑步了，为什么我的身体没有任何变化？一旦这种想法占据了上风，就很容易让好习惯被抛在一边。但为了产生有意义的改变，习惯需要持续足够长的时间才能突破这个高原——我称之为潜在潜力高原。 People make a few small changes, fail to see a tangible result, and decide to stop. You think, “I’ve been running every day for a month, so why can’t I see any change in my body?” Once this kind of thinking takes over, it’s easy to let good habits fall by the wayside. But in order to make a meaningful difference, habits need to persist long enough to break through this plateau—what I call the Plateau of Latent Potential.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 316</p>
<p>Ha 好习惯难以养成,主要是没有进度条</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 317</p>
<p>If you find yourself struggling to build a good habit or break a bad one, it is not because you have lost your ability to improve. It is often because you have not yet crossed the Plateau of Latent Potential.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 320</p>
<p>When you finally break through the Plateau of Latent Potential, people will call it an overnight success.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 335</p>
<p>All big things come from small beginnings. The seed of every habit is a single, tiny decision. But as that decision is repeated, a habit sprouts and grows stronger. Roots entrench themselves and branches grow. The task of breaking a bad habit is like uprooting a powerful oak within us.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 341</p>
<p>FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 341</p>
<p>忽略目标,专注于打造系统</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 345</p>
<p>I began to realize that my results had very little to do with the goals I set and nearly everything to do with the systems I followed.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 346</p>
<p>系统比目标有用</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 347</p>
<p>Goals are about the results you want to achieve. Systems are about the processes that lead to those results. If you’re a coach, your goal might be to win a championship. Your system is the way you recruit players, manage your assistant coaches, and conduct practice. If you’re an entrepreneur, your goal might be to build a million-dollar business. Your system is how you test product ideas, hire employees, and run marketing campaigns. If you’re a musician, your goal might be to play a new piece. Your system is how often you practice, how you break down and tackle difficult measures, and your method for receiving feedback from your instructor.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 352</p>
<p>目标是想要获得的东西,系统是如何获得的方法论</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 353</p>
<p>Now for the interesting question: If you completely ignored your goals and focused only on your system, would you still succeed? For example, if you were a basketball coach and you ignored your goal to win a championship and focused only on what your team does at practice each day, would you still get results?</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 355</p>
<p>不要设定目标为年级第几,而是设定为爱学习</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 360</p>
<p>Problem #1: Winners and losers have the same goals.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 361</p>
<p>Goal setting suffers from a serious case of survivorship bias.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 361</p>
<p>亚军的目标也是冠军,这就是幸存者偏差</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 368</p>
<p>Problem #2: Achieving a goal is only a momentary change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 368</p>
<p>Imagine you have a messy room and you set a goal to clean it. If you summon the energy to tidy up, then you will have a clean room—for now. But if you maintain the same sloppy, pack-rat habits that led to a messy room in the first place, soon you’ll be looking at a new pile of clutter and hoping for another burst of motivation. You’re left chasing the same outcome because you never changed the system behind it. You treated a symptom without addressing the cause.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 371</p>
<p>整理房间是一个目标,爱整洁才是身份</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 373</p>
<p>When you solve problems at the results level, you only solve them temporarily. In order to improve for good, you need to solve problems at the systems level. Fix the inputs and the outputs will fix themselves.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 375</p>
<p>Problem #3: Goals restrict your happiness.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 376</p>
<p>达不成目标还怎么快乐</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 376</p>
<p>The implicit assumption behind any goal is this: “Once I reach my goal, then I’ll be happy.” The problem with a goals-first mentality is that you’re continually putting happiness off until the next milestone.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 383</p>
<p>A systems-first mentality provides the antidote. When you fall in love with the process rather than the product, you don’t have to wait to give yourself permission to be happy. You can be satisfied anytime your system is running. And a system can be successful in many different forms, not just the one you first envision.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 385</p>
<p>Problem #4: Goals are at odds with long-term progress.</p>
<p>Note - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 385</p>
<p>溜溜球效应</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 386</p>
<p>Finally, a goal-oriented mind-set can create a “yo-yo” effect. Many runners work hard for months, but as soon as they cross the finish line, they stop training. The race is no longer there to motivate them. When all of your hard work is focused on a particular goal, what is left to push you forward after you achieve it? This is why many people find themselves reverting to their old habits after accomplishing a goal.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 389</p>
<p>The purpose of setting goals is to win the game. The purpose of building systems is to continue playing the game.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 395</p>
<p>Focusing on the overall system, rather than a single goal, is one of the core themes of this book.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 1: The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits &gt; Location 403</p>
<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. Getting 1 percent better every day counts for a lot in the long-run. Habits are a double-edged sword. They can work for you or against you, which is why understanding the details is essential. Small changes often appear to make no difference until you cross a critical threshold. The most powerful outcomes of any compounding process are delayed. You need to be patient. An atomic habit is a little habit that is part of a larger system. Just as atoms are the building blocks of molecules, atomic habits are the building blocks of remarkable results. If you want better results, then forget about setting goals. Focus on your system instead. You do not rise to the level of your goals. You fall to the level of your systems.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 414</p>
<p>It often feels difficult to keep good habits going for more than a few days, even with sincere effort and the occasional burst of motivation. Habits like exercise, meditation, journaling, and cooking are reasonable for a day or two and then become a hassle. However, once your habits are established, they seem to stick around forever—especially the unwanted ones.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 418</p>
<p>Changing our habits is challenging for two reasons: (1) we try to change the wrong thing and (2) we try to change our habits in the wrong way.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 422</p>
<p>THREE LAYERS OF BEHAVIOR CHANGE</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 425</p>
<p>The first layer is changing your outcomes. This level is concerned with changing your results: losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship. Most of the goals you set are associated with this level of change. The second layer is changing your process. This level is concerned with changing your habits and systems: implementing a new routine at the gym, decluttering your desk for better workflow, developing a meditation practice. Most of the habits you build are associated with this level. The third and deepest layer is changing your identity. This level is concerned with changing your beliefs: your worldview, your self-image, your judgments about yourself and others. Most of the beliefs, assumptions, and biases you hold are associated with this level.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 431</p>
<p>Outcomes are about what you get. Processes are about what you do. Identity is about what you believe.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 434</p>
<p>Many people begin the process of changing their habits by focusing on what they want to achieve. This leads us to outcome-based habits. The alternative is to build identity-based habits. With this approach, we start by focusing on who we wish to become.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 436</p>
<p>目标不是单一成就,而是成为什么人</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 441</p>
<p>Imagine two people resisting a cigarette. When offered a smoke, the first person says, “No thanks. I’m trying to quit.” It sounds like a reasonable response, but this person still believes they are a smoker who is trying to be something else. They are hoping their behavior will change while carrying around the same beliefs. The second person declines by saying, “No thanks. I’m not a smoker.” It’s a small difference, but this statement signals a shift in identity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 446</p>
<p>Most people don’t even consider identity change when they set out to improve. They just think, “I want to be skinny (outcome) and if I stick to this diet, then I’ll be skinny (process).” They set goals and determine the actions they should take to achieve those goals without considering the beliefs that drive their actions. They never shift the way they look at themselves, and they don’t realize that their old identity can sabotage their new plans for change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 454</p>
<p>Behavior that is incongruent with the self will not last.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 457</p>
<p>It’s hard to change your habits if you never change the underlying beliefs that led to your past behavior. You have a new goal and a new plan, but you haven’t changed who you are.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 466</p>
<p>The ultimate form of intrinsic motivation is when a habit becomes part of your identity. It’s one thing to say I’m the type of person who wants this. It’s something very different to say I’m the type of person who is this.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 468</p>
<p>好标签</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 472</p>
<p>True behavior change is identity change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 475</p>
<p>The goal is not to read a book, the goal is to become a reader. The goal is not to run a marathon, the goal is to become a runner. The goal is not to learn an instrument, the goal is to become a musician.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 477</p>
<p>身份认同决定行为</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 477</p>
<p>Your behaviors are usually a reflection of your identity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 482</p>
<p>Doing the right thing is easy. After all, when your behavior and your identity are fully aligned, you are no longer pursuing behavior change. You are simply acting like the type of person you already believe yourself to be.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 496</p>
<p>On any given day, you may struggle with your habits because you’re too busy or too tired or too overwhelmed or hundreds of other reasons. Over the long run, however, the real reason you fail to stick with habits is that your self-image gets in the way. This is why you can’t get too attached to one version of your identity. Progress requires unlearning. Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 499</p>
<p>抛弃旧版本的你,不断迭代</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 502</p>
<p>THE TWO-STEP PROCESS TO CHANGING YOUR IDENTITY</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 503</p>
<p>Your identity emerges out of your habits. You are not born with preset beliefs. Every belief, including those about yourself, is learned and conditioned through experience.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 505</p>
<p>More precisely, your habits are how you embody your identity. When you make your bed each day, you embody the identity of an organized person. When you write each day, you embody the identity of a creative person. When you train each day, you embody the identity of an athletic person.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 506</p>
<p>以身作则的意思是,孩子也想成为和你一样的人(爱学习?可以无限玩手机?)</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 516</p>
<p>Of course, your habits are not the only actions that influence your identity, but by virtue of their frequency they are usually the most important ones. Each experience in life modifies your self-image, but it’s unlikely you would consider yourself a soccer player because you kicked a ball once or an artist because you scribbled a picture. As you repeat these actions, however, the evidence accumulates and your self-image begins to change. The effect of one-off experiences tends to fade away while the effect of habits gets reinforced with time, which means your habits contribute most of the evidence that shapes your identity. In this way, the process of building habits is actually the process of becoming yourself.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 527</p>
<p>Small habits can make a meaningful difference by providing evidence of a new identity. And if a change is meaningful, it actually is big. That’s the paradox of making small improvements. Putting this all together, you can see that habits are the path to changing your identity. The most practical way to change who you are is to change what you do. Each time you write a page, you are a writer. Each time you practice the violin, you are a musician. Each time you start a workout, you are an athlete. Each time you encourage your employees, you are a leader.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 532</p>
<p>Each habit not only gets results but also teaches you something far more important: to trust yourself. You start to believe you can actually accomplish these things.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 537</p>
<p>New identities require new evidence. If you keep casting the same votes you’ve always cast, you’re going to get the same results you’ve always had. If nothing changes, nothing is going to change. It is a simple two-step process: Decide the type of person you want to be. Prove it to yourself with small wins.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 545</p>
<p>“Who is the type of person that could get the outcome I want?” Who is the type of person that could lose forty pounds? Who is the type of person that could learn a new language? Who is the type of person that could run a successful start-up?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 548</p>
<p>This process can lead to beliefs like: “I’m the kind of teacher who stands up for her students.” “I’m the kind of doctor who gives each patient the time and empathy they need.” “I’m the kind of manager who advocates for her employees.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 551</p>
<p>Once you have a handle on the type of person you want to be, you can begin taking small steps to reinforce your desired identity. I have a friend who lost over 100 pounds by asking herself, “What would a healthy person do?” All day long, she would use this question as a guide. Would a healthy person walk or take a cab? Would a healthy person order a burrito or a salad? She figured if she acted like a healthy person long enough, eventually she would become that person. She was right.</p>
<p>Note - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 555</p>
<p>Fake it ,untill you make it</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 558</p>
<p>THE REAL REASON HABITS MATTER Identity change is the North Star of habit change.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 561</p>
<p>you becoming the type of person you want to become?” The first step is not what or how, but who. You need to know who you want to be. Otherwise, your quest for change is like a boat without a rudder. And that’s why we are starting here.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 568</p>
<p>Ultimately, your habits matter because they help you become the type of person you wish to be. They are the channel through which you develop your deepest beliefs about yourself. Quite literally, you become your habits.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 2: How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa) &gt; Location 571</p>
<p>There are three levels of change: outcome change, process change, and identity change. The most effective way to change your habits is to focus not on what you want to achieve, but on who you wish to become. Your identity emerges out of your habits. Every action is a vote for the type of person you wish to become. Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity. The real reason habits matter is not because they can get you better results (although they can do that), but because they can change your beliefs about yourself.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 616</p>
<p>Habits are mental shortcuts learned from experience.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 622</p>
<p>Habits reduce cognitive load and free up mental capacity, so you can allocate your attention to other tasks.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 634</p>
<p>THE SCIENCE OF HOW HABITS WORK The process of building a habit can be divided into four simple steps: cue, craving, response, and reward.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 638</p>
<p>All habits proceed through four stages in the same order: cue, craving, response, and reward.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 645</p>
<p>the cue is the first indication that we’re close to a reward, it naturally leads to a craving. Cravings are the second step, and they are the motivational force behind every habit.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 654</p>
<p>The third step is the response.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 660</p>
<p>The first purpose of rewards is to satisfy your craving. Yes, rewards provide benefits on their own. Food and water deliver the energy you need to survive.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 664</p>
<p>Second, rewards teach us which actions are worth remembering in the future. Your brain is a reward detector. As you go about your life, your sensory nervous system is continuously monitoring which actions satisfy your desires and deliver pleasure.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 673</p>
<p>The four stages of habit are best described as a feedback loop. They form an endless cycle that is running every moment you are alive. This “habit loop” is continually scanning the environment, predicting what will happen next, trying out different responses, and learning from the results.*</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 676</p>
<p>In summary, the cue triggers a craving, which motivates a response, which provides a reward, which satisfies the craving and, ultimately, becomes associated with the cue.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 689</p>
<p>All behavior is driven by the desire to solve a problem.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 738</p>
<p>How to Create a Good Habit The 1st law (Cue): Make it obvious. The 2nd law (Craving): Make it attractive. The 3rd law (Response): Make it easy. The 4th law (Reward): Make it satisfying.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 743</p>
<p>How to Break a Bad Habit Inversion of the 1st law (Cue): Make it invisible. Inversion of the 2nd law (Craving): Make it unattractive. Inversion of the 3rd law (Response): Make it difficult. Inversion of the 4th law (Reward): Make it unsatisfying.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 750</p>
<p>Whenever you want to change your behavior, you can simply ask yourself: How can I make it obvious? How can I make it attractive? How can I make it easy? How can I make it satisfying?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 757</p>
<p>Every goal is doomed to fail if it goes against the grain of human nature.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 3: How to Build Better Habits in 4 Simple Steps &gt; Location 760</p>
<p>Chapter Summary A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic. The ultimate purpose of habits is to solve the problems of life with as little energy and effort as possible. Any habit can be broken down into a feedback loop that involves four steps: cue, craving, response, and reward. The Four Laws of Behavior Change are a simple set of rules we can use to build better habits. They are (1) make it obvious, (2) make it attractive, (3) make it easy, and (4) make it satisfying.</p>
<p>THE 1ST LAW: Make It Obvious</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 791</p>
<p>With enough practice, you can pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it. Automatically, your brain encodes the lessons learned through experience. We can’t always explain what it is we are learning, but learning is happening all along the way, and your ability to notice the relevant cues in a given situation is the foundation for every habit you have.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 800</p>
<p>This is one of the most surprising insights about our habits: you don’t need to be aware of the cue for a habit to begin. You can notice an opportunity and take action without dedicating conscious attention to it. This is what makes habits useful.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 817</p>
<p>“Until you make the unconscious conscious, it will direct your life and you will call it fate.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 828</p>
<p>Pointing-and-Calling is so effective because it raises the level of awareness from a nonconscious habit to a more conscious level.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 833</p>
<p>The more automatic a behavior becomes, the less likely we are to consciously think about it. And when we’ve done something a thousand times before, we begin to overlook things. We assume that the next time will be just like the last.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 836</p>
<p>One of our greatest challenges in changing habits is maintaining awareness of what we are actually doing.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 4: The Man Who Didn’t Look Right &gt; Location 873</p>
<p>With enough practice, your brain will pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it. Once our habits become automatic, we stop paying attention to what we are doing. The process of behavior change always starts with awareness. You need to be aware of your habits before you can change them. Pointing-and-Calling raises your level of awareness from a nonconscious habit to a more conscious level by verbalizing your actions. The Habits Scorecard is a simple exercise you can use to become more aware of your behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 888</p>
<p>I will partake in at least 20 minutes of vigorous exercise on [DAY] at [TIME] in [PLACE].”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 904</p>
<p>Too many people try to change their habits without these basic details figured out. We tell ourselves, “I’m going to eat healthier” or “I’m going to write more,” but we never say when and where these habits are going to happen.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 908</p>
<p>Many people think they lack motivation when what they really lack is clarity.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 912</p>
<p>Simply follow your predetermined plan. The simple way to apply this strategy to your habits is to fill out this sentence: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION]. Meditation. I will meditate for one minute at 7 a.m. in my kitchen. Studying. I will study Spanish for twenty minutes at 6 p.m. in my bedroom. Exercise. I will exercise for one hour at 5 p.m. in my local gym. Marriage. I will make my partner a cup of tea at 8 a.m. in the kitchen.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 927</p>
<p>HABIT STACKING: A SIMPLE PLAN TO OVERHAUL YOUR HABITS</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 940</p>
<p>The Diderot Effect states that obtaining a new possession often creates a spiral of consumption that leads to additional purchases.</p>
<p>Note - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 941</p>
<p>迪德罗效应</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 946</p>
<p>Each action becomes a cue that triggers the next behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 948</p>
<p>One of the best ways to build a new habit is to identify a current habit you already do each day and then stack your new behavior on top. This is called habit stacking.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 953</p>
<p>“After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [NEW HABIT].”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 958</p>
<p>The key is to tie your desired behavior into something you already do each day.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 5: The Best Way to Start a New Habit &gt; Location 1011</p>
<p>The 1st Law of Behavior Change is make it obvious. The two most common cues are time and location. Creating an implementation intention is a strategy you can use to pair a new habit with a specific time and location. The implementation intention formula is: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION]. Habit stacking is a strategy you can use to pair a new habit with a current habit. The habit stacking formula is: After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [NEW HABIT].</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1036</p>
<p>Environment is the invisible hand that shapes human behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1089</p>
<p>If you want to make a habit a big part of your life, make the cue a big part of your environment. The most persistent behaviors usually have multiple cues.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1113</p>
<p>habits can be easier to change in a new environment.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6: Motivation Is Overrated; Environment Often Matters More &gt; Location 1143</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Small changes in context can lead to large changes in behavior over time. Every habit is initiated by a cue. We are more likely to notice cues that stand out. Make the cues of good habits obvious in your environment. Gradually, your habits become associated not with a single trigger but with the entire context surrounding the behavior. The context becomes the cue. It is easier to build new habits in a new environment because you are not fighting against old cues.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1182</p>
<p>Shaming obese people with weight-loss presentations can make them feel stressed, and as a result many people return to their favorite coping strategy: overeating. Showing pictures of blackened lungs to smokers leads to higher levels of anxiety, which drives many people to reach for a cigarette. If you’re not careful about cues, you can cause the very behavior you want to stop.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1185</p>
<p>Bad habits are autocatalytic: the process feeds itself. They foster the feelings they try to numb. You feel bad, so you eat junk food. Because you eat junk food, you feel bad.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1199</p>
<p>If you can’t seem to get any work done, leave your phone in another room for a few hours. If you’re continually feeling like you’re not enough, stop following social media accounts that trigger jealousy and envy. If you’re wasting too much time watching television, move the TV out of the bedroom. If you’re spending too much money on electronics, quit reading reviews of the latest tech gear. If you’re playing too many video games, unplug the console and put it in a closet after each use.</p>
<p>Note - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1203</p>
<p>移除敏感源</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 7: The Secret to Self-Control &gt; Location 1209</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 1st Law of Behavior Change is make it invisible. Once a habit is formed, it is unlikely to be forgotten. People with high self-control tend to spend less time in tempting situations. It’s easier to avoid temptation than resist it. One of the most practical ways to eliminate a bad habit is to reduce exposure to the cue that causes it. Self-control is a short-term strategy, not a long-term one.</p>
<p>THE 2ND LAW: Make It Attractive</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1236</p>
<p>How to Make a Habit Irresistible</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1276</p>
<p>Make it attractive. The more attractive an opportunity is, the more likely it is to become habit-forming.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1287</p>
<p>If you want to increase the odds that a behavior will occur, then you need to make it attractive. Throughout our discussion of the 2nd Law, our goal is to learn how to make our habits irresistible.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1315</p>
<p>As an adult, daydreaming about an upcoming vacation can be more enjoyable than actually being on vacation.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1358</p>
<p>psychology theory known as Premack’s Principle. Named after the work of professor David Premack, the principle states that “more probable behaviors will reinforce less probable behaviors.” In other words, even if you don’t really want to process overdue work emails, you’ll become conditioned to do it if it means you get to do something you really want to do along the way. You can even combine temptation bundling with the habit stacking strategy we discussed in Chapter 5 to create a set of rules to guide your behavior.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1362</p>
<p>The habit stacking + temptation bundling formula is: After [CURRENT HABIT], I will [HABIT I NEED]. After [HABIT I NEED], I will [HABIT I WANT].</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1371</p>
<p>If you want to check Facebook, but you need to exercise more: After I pull out my phone, I will do ten burpees (need). After I do ten burpees, I will check Facebook (want).</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 8: How to Make a Habit Irresistible &gt; Location 1378</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 2nd Law of Behavior Change is make it attractive. The more attractive an opportunity is, the more likely it is to become habit-forming. Habits are a dopamine-driven feedback loop. When dopamine rises, so does our motivation to act. It is the anticipation of a reward—not the fulfillment of it—that gets us to take action. The greater the anticipation, the greater the dopamine spike. Temptation bundling is one way to make your habits more attractive. The strategy is to pair an action you want to do with an action you need to do.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1414</p>
<p>one of the deepest human desires is to belong. And this ancient preference exerts a powerful influence on our modern behavior.</p>
<p>Note - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1415</p>
<p>利用归属感可以做很多事情，比如社群，宗教，Niche，小团体。 这也是做产品的方向</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1421</p>
<p>Most of the time, going along with the group does not feel like a burden. Everyone wants to belong. If you grow up in a family that rewards you for your chess skills, playing chess will seem like a very attractive thing to do. If you work in a job where everyone wears expensive suits, then you’ll be inclined to splurge on one as well. If all of your friends are sharing an inside joke or using a new phrase, you’ll want to do it, too, so they know that you “get it.” Behaviors are attractive when they help us fit in.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1425</p>
<p>We imitate the habits of three groups in particular: The close. The many. The powerful.</p>
<p>Note - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1427</p>
<p>模仿习惯的 3 个来源</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 9: The Role of Family and Friends in Shaping Your Habits &gt; Location 1510</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The culture we live in determines which behaviors are attractive to us. We tend to adopt habits that are praised and approved of by our culture because we have a strong desire to fit in and belong to the tribe. We tend to imitate the habits of three social groups: the close (family and friends), the many (the tribe), and the powerful (those with status and prestige). One of the most effective things you can do to build better habits is to join a culture where (1) your desired behavior is the normal behavior and (2) you already have something in common with the group. The normal behavior of the tribe often overpowers the desired behavior of the individual. Most days, we’d rather be wrong with the crowd than be right by ourselves. If a behavior can get us approval, respect, and praise, we find it attractive.</p>
<p>Bookmark - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1518</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1526</p>
<p>“It always starts with your friends. One friend smokes, then you try it.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1546</p>
<p>Some of our underlying motives include:* Conserve energy Obtain food and water Find love and reproduce Connect and bond with others Win social acceptance and approval Reduce uncertainty Achieve status and prestige</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1553</p>
<p>Find love and reproduce = using Tinder Connect and bond with others = browsing Facebook Win social acceptance and approval = posting on Instagram Reduce uncertainty = searching on Google Achieve status and prestige = playing video games</p>
<p>Note - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1556</p>
<p>每个习惯背后都对应着原始欲望,所以最好是替代</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1600</p>
<p>“I’m not confined to my wheelchair—I am liberated by it. If it wasn’t for my wheelchair, I would be bed-bound and never able to leave my house.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1605</p>
<p>Finance. Saving money is often associated with sacrifice. However, you can associate it with freedom rather than limitation if you realize one simple truth: living below your current means increases your future means. The money you save this month increases your purchasing power next month.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 10: How to Find and Fix the Causes of Your Bad Habits &gt; Location 1633</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 2nd Law of Behavior Change is make it unattractive. Every behavior has a surface level craving and a deeper underlying motive. Your habits are modern-day solutions to ancient desires. The cause of your habits is actually the prediction that precedes them. The prediction leads to a feeling. Highlight the benefits of avoiding a bad habit to make it seem unattractive. Habits are attractive when we associate them with positive feelings and unattractive when we associate them with negative feelings. Create a motivation ritual by doing something you enjoy immediately before a difficult habit.</p>
<p>THE 3RD LAW: Make It Easy</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1666</p>
<p>Walk Slowly, but Never Backward</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1677</p>
<p>It is easy to get bogged down trying to find the optimal plan for change: the fastest way to lose weight, the best program to build muscle, the perfect idea for a side hustle. We are so focused on figuring out the best approach that we never get around to taking action. As Voltaire once wrote, “The best is the enemy of the good.”</p>
<p>Note - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1680</p>
<p>最好是好的敌人,想要最好就不会行动</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1684</p>
<p>Sometimes motion is useful, but it will never produce an outcome by itself. It doesn’t matter how many times you go talk to the personal trainer, that motion will never get you in shape. Only the action of working out will get the result you’re looking to achieve.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1693</p>
<p>Motion makes you feel like you’re getting things done. But really, you’re just preparing to get something done. When preparation becomes a form of procrastination, you need to change something. You don’t want to merely be planning. You want to be practicing.</p>
<p>Note - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1694</p>
<p>你永远不会准备好,准备是拖延的一种借口</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 11: Walk Slowly, but Never Backward &gt; Location 1742</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 3rd Law of Behavior Change is make it easy. The most effective form of learning is practice, not planning. Focus on taking action, not being in motion. Habit formation is the process by which a behavior becomes progressively more automatic through repetition. The amount of time you have been performing a habit is not as important as the number of times you have performed it.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 12: The Law of Least Effort &gt; Location 1851</p>
<p>When you wake up, making breakfast will be easy. Want to draw more? Put your pencils, pens, notebooks, and drawing tools on top of your desk, within easy reach. Want to exercise? Set out your workout clothes, shoes, gym bag, and water bottle ahead of time. Want to improve your diet? Chop up a ton of fruits and vegetables on weekends and pack them in containers, so you have easy access to healthy, ready-to-eat options during the week.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 12: The Law of Least Effort &gt; Location 1872</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Human behavior follows the Law of Least Effort. We will naturally gravitate toward the option that requires the least amount of work. Create an environment where doing the right thing is as easy as possible. Reduce the friction associated with good behaviors. When friction is low, habits are easy. Increase the friction associated with bad behaviors. When friction is high, habits are difficult. Prime your environment to make future actions easier.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1918</p>
<p>“When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do.” You’ll find that nearly any habit can be scaled down into a two-minute version: “Read before bed each night” becomes “Read one page.” “Do thirty minutes of yoga” becomes “Take out my yoga mat.” “Study for class” becomes “Open my notes.” “Fold the laundry” becomes “Fold one pair of socks.” “Run three miles” becomes “Tie my running shoes.”</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1922</p>
<p>培养从两分钟小习惯开始</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1922</p>
<p>The idea is to make your habits as easy as possible to start.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1923</p>
<p>新的习惯越简单越好,它很容易完成</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1924</p>
<p>this is a powerful strategy because once you’ve started doing the right thing, it is much easier to continue doing it.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1924</p>
<p>A new habit should not feel like a challenge.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1925</p>
<p>行的习惯不应该是挑战</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1943</p>
<p>People often think it’s weird to get hyped about reading one page or meditating for one minute or making one sales call. But the point is not to do one thing. The point is to master the habit of showing up. The truth is, a habit must be established before it can be improved.</p>
<p>Note - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1945</p>
<p>微小习惯最容易形成,并且会长大</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 13: How to Stop Procrastinating by Using the Two-Minute Rule &gt; Location 1998</p>
<p>Chapter Summary Habits can be completed in a few seconds but continue to impact your behavior for minutes or hours afterward. Many habits occur at decisive moments—choices that are like a fork in the road—and either send you in the direction of a productive day or an unproductive one. The Two-Minute Rule states, “When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do.” The more you ritualize the beginning of a process, the more likely it becomes that you can slip into the state of deep focus that is required to do great things. Standardize before you optimize. You can’t improve a habit that doesn’t exist.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2061</p>
<p>Unsubscribe from emails. Turn off notifications and mute group chats. Set your phone to silent. Use email filters to clear up your inbox. Delete games and social media apps on your phone.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2068</p>
<p>Enroll in an automatic savings plan. Set up automatic bill pay. Cut cable service. Ask service providers to lower your bills.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2070</p>
<p>Of course, there are many ways to automate good habits and eliminate bad ones. Typically, they involve putting technology to work for you. Technology can transform actions that were once hard, annoying, and complicated into behaviors that are easy, painless, and simple. It is the most reliable and effective way to guarantee the right behavior.</p>
<p>Note - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2073</p>
<p>通过自动化手段来消除坏习惯，比如取消游戏订阅</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2076</p>
<p>Medicine: Prescriptions can be automatically refilled. Personal finance: Employees can save for retirement with an automatic wage deduction. Cooking: Meal-delivery services can do your grocery shopping. Productivity: Social media browsing can be cut off with a website blocker.</p>
<p>Note - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2078</p>
<p>比如每天晚上自动断网</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 14: How to Make Good Habits Inevitable and Bad Habits Impossible &gt; Location 2103</p>
<p>The inversion of the 3rd Law of Behavior Change is make it difficult. A commitment device is a choice you make in the present that locks in better behavior in the future. The ultimate way to lock in future behavior is to automate your habits. Onetime choices—like buying a better mattress or enrolling in an automatic savings plan—are single actions that automate your future habits and deliver increasing returns over time. Using technology to automate your habits is the most reliable and effective way to guarantee the right behavior.</p>
<p>THE 4TH LAW: Make It Satisfying</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2143</p>
<p>The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2173</p>
<p>We are more likely to repeat a behavior when the experience is satisfying. This is entirely logical. Feelings of pleasure—even minor ones like washing your hands with soap that smells nice and lathers well—are signals that tell the brain: “This feels good. Do this again, next time.” Pleasure teaches your brain that a behavior is worth remembering and repeating.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2176</p>
<p>赋予行为意义：打水不是麻烦而是锻炼？ 锻炼不是累而是享受生活？</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2191</p>
<p>The first three laws of behavior change—make it obvious, make it attractive, and make it easy—increase the odds that a behavior will be performed this time. The fourth law of behavior change—make it satisfying—increases the odds that a behavior will be repeated next time. It completes the habit loop.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2193</p>
<p>告诉自己从这个响应里得到了好处</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2234</p>
<p>What is immediately rewarded is repeated. What is immediately punished is avoided.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2235</p>
<p>有奖励的行为被重复，有惩罚的行为被抛弃</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2236</p>
<p>Our preference for instant gratification reveals an important truth about success: because of how we are wired, most people will spend all day chasing quick hits of satisfaction. The road less traveled is the road of delayed gratification. If you’re willing to wait for the rewards, you’ll face less competition and often get a bigger payoff. As the saying goes, the last mile is always the least crowded.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2238</p>
<p>少有人走的路不会拥挤，延迟满足往往有最大的回报</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2243</p>
<p>Here’s the problem: most people know that delaying gratification is the wise approach. They want the benefits of good habits: to be healthy, productive, at peace. But these outcomes are seldom top-of-mind at the decisive moment. Thankfully, it’s possible to train yourself to delay gratification—but you need to work with the grain of human nature, not against it. The best way to do this is to add a little bit of immediate pleasure to the habits that pay off in the long-run and a little bit of immediate pain to ones that don’t.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2246</p>
<p>人性就是立刻满足，我们不能与人性作对，所以需要一点技巧</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2261</p>
<p>One solution is to turn the situation on its head. You want to make avoidance visible. Open a savings account and label it for something you want—maybe “Leather Jacket.” Whenever you pass on a purchase, put the same amount of money in the account. Skip your morning latte? Transfer $5.</p>
<p>Note - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2263</p>
<p>开一个梦想账户，当你想买东西时，直接转入替代账户。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2266</p>
<p>One of my readers and his wife used a similar setup. They wanted to stop eating out so much and start cooking together more. They labeled their savings account “Trip to Europe.” Whenever they skipped going out to eat, they transferred $50 into the account. At the end of the year, they put the money toward the vacation.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2275</p>
<p>You do it because it’s who you are and it feels good to be you. The more a habit becomes part of your life, the less you need outside encouragement to follow through. Incentives can start a habit. Identity sustains a habit.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 15: The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change &gt; Location 2281</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The 4th Law of Behavior Change is make it satisfying. We are more likely to repeat a behavior when the experience is satisfying. The human brain evolved to prioritize immediate rewards over delayed rewards. The Cardinal Rule of Behavior Change: What is immediately rewarded is repeated. What is immediately punished is avoided. To get a habit to stick you need to feel immediately successful—even if it’s in a small way. The first three laws of behavior change—make it obvious, make it attractive, and make it easy—increase the odds that a behavior will be performed this time. The fourth law of behavior change—make it satisfying—increases the odds that a behavior will be repeated next time.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2301</p>
<p>Making progress is satisfying, and visual measures—like moving paper clips or hairpins or marbles—provide clear evidence of your progress. As a result, they reinforce your behavior and add a little bit of immediate satisfaction to any activity. Visual measurement comes in many forms: food journals, workout logs, loyalty punch cards, the progress bar on a software download, even the page numbers in a book. But perhaps the best way to measure your progress is with a habit tracker.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2412</p>
<p>Chapter Summary One of the most satisfying feelings is the feeling of making progress. A habit tracker is a simple way to measure whether you did a habit—like marking an X on a calendar. Habit trackers and other visual forms of measurement can make your habits satisfying by providing clear evidence of your progress. Don’t break the chain. Try to keep your habit streak alive. Never miss twice. If you miss one day, try to get back on track as quickly as possible. Just because you can measure something doesn’t mean it’s the most important thing.</p>
<p>Note - 16: How to Stick with Good Habits Every Day &gt; Location 2417</p>
<p>Kindle 的连续读书多少天何尝不是一种习惯进度条呢？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 17: How an Accountability Partner Can Change Everything &gt; Location 2493</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The inversion of the 4th Law of Behavior Change is make it unsatisfying. We are less likely to repeat a bad habit if it is painful or unsatisfying. An accountability partner can create an immediate cost to inaction. We care deeply about what others think of us, and we do not want others to have a lesser opinion of us. A habit contract can be used to add a social cost to any behavior. It makes the costs of violating your promises public and painful. Knowing that someone else is watching you can be a powerful motivator.</p>
<p>Note - 17: How an Accountability Partner Can Change Everything &gt; Location 2498</p>
<p>对坏习惯进行监督与惩罚</p>
<p>ADVANCED TACTICS: How to Go from Being Merely Good to Being Truly Great</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 18: The Truth About Talent (When Genes Matter and When They Don’t) &gt; Location 2686</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The secret to maximizing your odds of success is to choose the right field of competition. Pick the right habit and progress is easy. Pick the wrong habit and life is a struggle. Genes cannot be easily changed, which means they provide a powerful advantage in favorable circumstances and a serious disadvantage in unfavorable circumstances. Habits are easier when they align with your natural abilities. Choose the habits that best suit you. Play a game that favors your strengths. If you can’t find a game that favors you, create one. Genes do not eliminate the need for hard work. They clarify it. They tell us what to work hard on.</p>
<p>Note - 18: The Truth About Talent (When Genes Matter and When They Don’t) &gt; Location 2692</p>
<p>选者你适合的领域</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2717</p>
<p>The human brain loves a challenge, but only if it is within an optimal zone of difficulty. If you love tennis and try to play a serious match against a four-year-old, you will quickly become bored. It’s too easy. You’ll win every point. In contrast, if you play a professional tennis player like Roger Federer or Serena Williams, you will quickly lose motivation because the match is too difficult.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2720</p>
<p>人喜欢挑战，但是没有胜率或者没有互动的挑战无法坚持</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2723</p>
<p>The Goldilocks Rule states that humans experience peak motivation when working on tasks that are right on the edge of their current abilities. Not too hard. Not too easy. Just right.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2724</p>
<p>要找到自己匹配的难度才更有动力</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2757</p>
<p>The greatest threat to success is not failure but boredom.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2757</p>
<p>对成功威胁最大的不是失败，而是无聊</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2790</p>
<p>The only way to become excellent is to be endlessly fascinated by doing the same thing over and over. You have to fall in love with boredom.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2791</p>
<p>如果你无法让它变的有趣，那你就必须爱上无聊</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2791</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The Goldilocks Rule states that humans experience peak motivation when working on tasks that are right on the edge of their current abilities. The greatest threat to success is not failure but boredom. As habits become routine, they become less interesting and less satisfying. We get bored. Anyone can work hard when they feel motivated. It’s the ability to keep going when work isn’t exciting that makes the difference. Professionals stick to the schedule; amateurs let life get in the way.</p>
<p>Note - 19: The Goldilocks Rule: How to Stay Motivated in Life and Work &gt; Location 2796</p>
<p>成功的敌人不是失败，而是无趣与无聊，所以我们必须让它有趣。 做产品也是一样，必须一开始就有人用，有互动，有反馈，否则你坚持不下去的。一定要从一开始就有种子用户，开发中的时候就有一个群的人在期待。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - 20: The Downside of Creating Good Habits &gt; Location 2938</p>
<p>Chapter Summary The upside of habits is that we can do things without thinking. The downside is that we stop paying attention to little errors. Habits + Deliberate Practice = Mastery Reflection and review is a process that allows you to remain conscious of your performance over time. The tighter we cling to an identity, the harder it becomes to grow beyond it.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Conclusion: The Secret to Results That Last &gt; Location 2982</p>
<p>That’s the power of atomic habits. Tiny changes. Remarkable results.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>成功的敌人不是失败，而是无趣与无聊</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F%E7%9A%84%E6%95%8C%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8D%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%B1%E8%B4%A5%E8%80%8C%E6%98%AF%E6%97%A0%E8%B6%A3%E4%B8%8E%E6%97%A0%E8%81%8A/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 06:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F%E7%9A%84%E6%95%8C%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8D%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%B1%E8%B4%A5%E8%80%8C%E6%98%AF%E6%97%A0%E8%B6%A3%E4%B8%8E%E6%97%A0%E8%81%8A/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;成功的敌人不是失败，而是无趣与无聊，所以我们必须让它有趣。 做产品也是一样，必须一开始就有人用，有互动，有反馈，否则你坚持不下去的。一定要从一开始就有种子用户，开发中的时候就有一个群的人在期待。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>成功的敌人不是失败，而是无趣与无聊，所以我们必须让它有趣。 做产品也是一样，必须一开始就有人用，有互动，有反馈，否则你坚持不下去的。一定要从一开始就有种子用户，开发中的时候就有一个群的人在期待。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a People Magnet</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-to-become-a-people-magnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 01:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/how-to-become-a-people-magnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1---understanding-human-nature&#34;&gt;1 - Understanding human nature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are, above all, interested in themselves. Yup. Sorry. No matter who you are people will always be a thousand times more interested in themselves than in you. No judgment here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People’s actions are governed by self-interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every human relationship, your counterpart will always think or ask themselves “what’s in it for me?” Remember this question “What’s in it for me?” By the way, you’re asking this question in all your interactions too, consciously or subconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="1---understanding-human-nature">1 - Understanding human nature</h2>
<p>People are, above all, interested in themselves. Yup. Sorry. No matter who you are people will always be a thousand times more interested in themselves than in you. No judgment here.</p>
<p>People’s actions are governed by self-interest.</p>
<p>In every human relationship, your counterpart will always think or ask themselves “what’s in it for me?” Remember this question “What’s in it for me?” By the way, you’re asking this question in all your interactions too, consciously or subconsciously.</p>
<p>People are above all interested in themselves and not in you.</p>
<h2 id="2---the-most-important-subject-of-any-conversation">2 - The most important subject of any conversation</h2>
<p>The most important subject that anyone will want to talk about with you is… THEMSELVES.</p>
<p>when you talk with people about themselves, they will love you for your wise choice of subject. They will be totally fascinated by the subject and show an enormous interest.</p>
<p>When you are talking to people, forget about “I,” “my,” and “mine” for a while and substitute it with a word that will make you a very sought after conversational partner: The word “YOU.”</p>
<p>When you get from “I,” “my,” “mine,” to “YOU” and “YOUR” your power and influence will increase by a significant degree.</p>
<p>get them talking about themselves. Who doesn’t love to talk about themselves? If you can show true interest and get people to talk about themselves, they will like you a lot, so ask them lots of questions about themselves.</p>
<p>Stop talking about yourself and start talking about the person in front of you or get them to talk about themselves.</p>
<h2 id="3---make-people-feel-important">3 - Make people feel important</h2>
<p>The desire to be recognized. The desire to be important. The desire to be noticed. The desire to be “someone.” This is the most powerful motivator.</p>
<p>Give every person you meet the importance they deserve-which is almost definitely the importance YOU think YOU deserve. Don’t ignore them, don’t talk down on them. Make them feel important. Listen to them! If you don’t listen, they feel unimportant. Compliment them, but only if it’s a sincere compliment.</p>
<p>Don’t interrupt people. Make a short pause before answering. This gives them the feeling that you have listened closely and are interested in what they have to say.</p>
<p>Make people feel important, and they’ll always be on your side.</p>
<h2 id="4---the-most-important-characteristic-agree-with-people">4 - The most important characteristic: Agree with people.</h2>
<p>The most important characteristic: Agree with people.</p>
<p>Well, first of all, people like people who agree with them. Second, people don’t like people who disagree with them. Third, people don’t like being disagreed with. Am I right or am I right? Adopt the attitude of being agreeable. Learn to agree with people and let them know when you do so. Nod your head. Say “yes,” “right,” “I totally agree with you,” “I totally get you.”</p>
<p>“Any fool can disagree with people”<br>
我无常心,众心为心。</p>
<p>“Do I want to be right or do I want to be in peace?”</p>
<p>Agreeing with people, on the other hand, is a wise, intelligent and good decision, even more so when the other person is wrong.<br>
立场为先,不论对错</p>
<p>Don’t argue-even if you are right. Why? Easy: Nobody ever wins an argument. Both lose. One loses, and the other one loses even if he or she is right. You also don’t win a lot of friends by arguing, do you? Who wants to be with a person that argues all the time anyway?</p>
<p>Some people might even want to provoke you because they love fighting. They feed on fights. There’s a saying in Spain: “If one doesn’t want to fight, two won’t fight.” Ignore the fighters. Change the subject, Walk away. Whatever-You don’t want fighters as friends anyway.</p>
<p>If you make a mistake, admit it. It’s a sign of a strong person, and you’ll be admired for it as average and mediocre people don’t admit their mistakes.</p>
<p>Remember people like people who agree with them.</p>
<h2 id="5---how-to-make-people-like-you-immediately">5 - How to make people like you immediately</h2>
<p>&ldquo;You never get a second chance to make a first impression.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the first moment when the door opens, when you make eye contact, even before you say anything; give the person your most sincere smile. A smile can do miracles.</p>
<p>Smile at the baker, the butcher, in the subway, at the newspaper stand and see what happens. Smile even when you are talking on the phone! The person on the other end of the phone will notice it. Smiling is contagious, so in most cases, people will smile back and be nice to you.<br>
伸手不打笑脸人</p>
<p>is not only good for your relationships, but also for your health! Science has demonstrated that laughing or smiling a lot daily improves your mental state and creativity. It also alters your stress response in difficult situations by slowing down your heart rate and decreasing stress levels.</p>
<p>Smile and win in all relationships.</p>
<h2 id="6---how-to-make-a-good-impression">6 - How to make a good impression</h2>
<p>You can’t expect others to believe in you if you don’t believe in you, yet. Start being proud of yourself, of who you are, of where you come from, and of what you do for a living. This is not the time to be modest! Careful though. It’s also not the time to be arrogant. I’m talking about healthy self-esteem. Knowing who you are, knowing your strength, but also knowing that you are not better than anybody else (and remembering that nobody is better than you either).</p>
<p>Say only things you mean and mean the things you say. As I mentioned before, cheap compliments, empty promises, and meaningless words will always be discovered and cause the opposite effect of what you want to achieve.</p>
<p>Being overanxious makes people wonder, and they start doubting. “Why is he so anxious?”, “What does she have to hide?”</p>
<p>Never try to make yourself look good, by putting other people down. This makes you look bad and can damage your effort to make friends and influence people.</p>
<p>a person that treats you nicely and disrespects the waiter is not a nice person.</p>
<p>If you can’t say nice things, say nothing. Don’t put people down.</p>
<p>Other people’s opinion about us is primarily made by how we behave.</p>
<h2 id="7---how-to-connect-with-people">7 - How to connect with people</h2>
<p>One great way to connect with people is by being interested in them and in the things that interest them.<br>
有相同的爱好，玩一样的游戏</p>
<p>If you make an effort to study their interests, you’ll surely get good results. I know a lot of salespeople who know everything that can interest their client even before they meet them the first time in person. Those are also the most successful salespeople. They talk about the interests of their potential clients with true interest and then close the sale.</p>
<p>Be nice. Even on the phone. If you are smiling on the phone, the person on the other end of the line can feel it.</p>
<p>People can smell false praise and played interest from a mile away.</p>
<p>Show true interest in other people and succeed</p>
<h2 id="8---how-to-develop-an-attractive-personality">8 - How to develop an attractive personality</h2>
<p>One of the most important ingredients is Acceptance. You must accept people as they are. So simple and yet sometimes so complicated, right? To make it easier remember these things. People are not like you. They are not perfect (you also aren’t, and-even better-you don’t have to be!). You can’t change them no matter how hard you try. They might not have the same values as you and many times they won’t live up to your high expectations.<br>
你必须接受这帮傻逼,他们学不会和人平等交流。也不想改变自己的想法,你不要尝试改变他们。</p>
<p>Accept and like people just as they are.</p>
<p>Another ingredient is Approval. No matter how many faults somebody has, you can always find something to approve of.<br>
无论多么离谱的人,你也能找到角度来认可他</p>
<p>Appreciation. Next to love, appreciation is probably the most critical force in the universe. When do our marriages and jobs go sour? When we don’t appreciate them anymore.</p>
<p>Accept. Approve of. Appreciate. Use this formula to become a people magnet.</p>
<h2 id="9---its-what-they-want-not-what-you-want">9 - It’s what they want, not what you want</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 416</p>
<p>When you want to influence people always have in mind: It’s what they want, not what you want. I love the example Dale Carnegie put in his classic “How to make friends and influence people”: He loved strawberry and cream, but when he went fishing he didn’t use strawberries with cream to bait the fish, but worms. Fish want worms, not strawberries.</p>
<p>We have to put ourselves in their shoes and see things from their point of view. We have to make them really, really want what we have to offer them. We have to speak their language, use the words they would use and talk in terms of what they want.</p>
<p>The more you think about the needs and want of other people, the more successful relationships you will get. Be careful though and don’t forget your own needs and wants. Remember: It’s what they want, not what you want.<br>
人人都像你祈祷,你就是上帝,赐予他们想要的夸奖,赞美,倾听,认同</p>
<h2 id="10---listen-to-people-actively">10 - Listen to people actively</h2>
<p>One of the most critical skills of a “people magnet” is the ability and skill of &ldquo;active listening&rdquo; or listening profoundly. The more you listen, the smarter you will get. You will also be more liked, and people will love to have conversations with you. Why? Because you’ll be of a rare breed. Most people never listen.</p>
<p>A good listener will always have the advantage over a good talker because he or she always allows people to hear their favorite speaker in the world: themselves.</p>
<p>Listening profoundly means to listen to the person in front of you while giving them your full attention. Look at the person who is talking. Listen with your eyes, with your ears, with your whole body and keep looking at them. Nod your head to show them you are agreeing with their points, smile.</p>
<p>Lean towards the speaker. Show interest. Show them you don’t want to miss a single word. Ask questions. This will show the speaker that you are listening and will flatter him/her. It can be super simple questions like “and then what happened” or “and then what did you do?”</p>
<p>Quiet down the little voice in your head that comes up with advice and a solution thirty seconds after the person starts speaking. Don’t listen to answer. Listen to understand. If you are rehearsing what you are going to say next, you are not listening! Don’t interrupt the speaker until he or she is finished, or don’t just wait for your counterpart to pause so that you can begin to speak. Don’t change subjects. On the contrary ask for more.</p>
<p>If you want to give advice, ask for permission. Most of the time the person who is speaking will come up with the solution-if you let her or him finish.</p>
<p>Don’t forget using “you” and “your” instead of “me, my, mine.”</p>
<p>Try it! Becoming a good listener will take your conversations and relationships to an entirely new level. When people feel that you are listening to them, they will automatically like to be around you. Be a good listener!</p>
<h2 id="11--become-an-influencer">11- Become an influencer</h2>
<p>Influencing people means to get them to do what you want them to do. So, the logical first step will be to find out what will make them do it. You need to know what they want. You need to know what will motivate them, what will move them.</p>
<p>The biggest mistake we make when trying to influence people is that we think that other people like what we like, are motivated by things that motivate us, are after what we are after.<br>
爱好,欲望,信念</p>
<p>Everybody is different. Everyone has different values. Everyone likes different things, and everyone has different motivators.</p>
<p>To influence people, you need to find out what they want. Once you know what they want you can make them take action by telling them what they want to hear.</p>
<p>You show them how they can get what they want by doing what you want them to do. Yup. That’s manipulating at its best-so I hope dear reader that you just wish the best for the people you want to influence because this power-just like the power of electricity or the atom-can be used to create something beautiful, or to destroy. Choose wisely.</p>
<p>First of all, you will have to find out what people want, what they are looking for. If they want security, talk security. If they want to leave their day job, show them ways to leave their day job, if they want financial freedom, you talk financial freedom. The point is to find out what people want and then show them how to get what they want by doing what you want them to do (e.g., buy the course, buy the clothes, come to work for you, etc.).</p>
<p>If you are looking for a job, you would first find out what the employer is looking for, what abilities and responsibilities are needed for the job, and then you would show them that you can fill these needs better than anybody else.</p>
<p>When you know what somebody is looking for, you can talk the language they want to hear.</p>
<p>So, from now on listen very carefully to what people say, watch with great interest what they do and ask lots of questions. Make an effort to find out what people want and then use it to influence them.<br>
仔细倾听,找出他们的喜好欲望,并且加以利用</p>
<p>Find out what people want most.</p>
<h2 id="12---how-to-convince-people-real-quick">12 - How to convince people real quick</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 501</p>
<p>A great way to convince people is quoting someone. That’s why testimonials and opinions of others, in other words, social proof go a long, long way. Let somebody else speak for you even if the person is not present in the moment.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you are selling something and you are asked about the product quote a relevant customer opinion. In that case, your customer is answering the question although he or she isn’t there with you.</li>
<li>If somebody wants to know if you are paying your suppliers on time, you can mention how happy your other suppliers are with you paying their bills on time.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are applying for a job, mention all the good things your past employers and colleagues say about you.</p>
<p>It’s a psychological mystery. If you tell people directly about how great you are, they will be hugely skeptical, yet they don’t have any doubts that what you tell them is true if you tell them through third person’s testimonials.</p>
<p>Speak through third persons. Quote statistics and/or people. Relate facts. Tell success stories.</p>
<h2 id="13---get-people-to-say-yes-to-you">13 - Get people to say YES to you</h2>
<p>The ability that will boost the chances of getting people to say “yes” to you, and don’t forget: If you get them to say yes to you, you’ll get them to do whatever you want them to do.</p>
<h2 id="1-give-people-reasons-to-say-yes-to-you">1. Give people reasons to say yes to you</h2>
<h2 id="2-ask-yes-questions">2. Ask “yes” questions</h2>
<p>Do you want to be happy? Do you want to be independent? Do you want to live a life free from worries?</p>
<h2 id="3-give-them-a-choice-between-two-yeses-dont-give-people-a-choice-between-yes-and-no-let">3. Give them a choice between two yeses Don’t give people a choice between yes and no. Let</h2>
<p>When you are giving the other party a choice between yes and no, you might hear an awful lot of nos. It’s much better to not ask open questions. “Do you want the red or the black?” instead of “Do you want one of these?” “Do you want to start today or on Wednesday?” instead of “Do you want to start here?” “Do you want to pay cash or credit card?”, instead of “Do you want this?” I’m not saying that this will work every single time, but your success rate will increase. It will surely work a lot better than giving people a choice between answering yes or no.</p>
<h2 id="4-expect-people-to-say-yes-to-you">4. Expect people to say yes to you</h2>
<p>Get the easy yes, yes and yes and more yeses will come.</p>
<h2 id="14---talk-less-do-more">14 - Talk less, do more</h2>
<p>You are what you do, not what you say you’ll do.</p>
<p>People who just talk about the great things they will do for their friends, their company, their community and never follow up with action lose credibility and sooner or later nobody is going to take them seriously anymore.<br>
夸夸其谈之辈很快就会露馅</p>
<p>Talk less and convince the people around you by your actions.<br>
人狠话不多说更有威慑力</p>
<p>Stop talking and start doing. NOW.</p>
<h2 id="15---respect-other-peoples-opinions">15 - Respect other people’s opinions</h2>
<p>You won’t be right all the time. And even the times you are right, it’s a lot more beneficial for you not to prove others wrong.</p>
<p>It’s impossible to alter people’s opinions after having hurt their feelings.</p>
<p>Saying things like “I’m going to prove this to you” is like saying “I’m smarter than you and I’m going to prove it” and the only thing it will cause is opposition and will make it impossible to change your counterpart’s opinion.</p>
<p>Start by admitting that you could be wrong. It changes the whole conversations. You are admitting a mistake. “I might be wrong, but let’s look at it.”</p>
<p>Show respect for the other person&rsquo;s opinion. Put yourself in their shoes and try to understand them.</p>
<p>If you want to be right and have to point out other people’s mistakes all the time soon, you will be alone, and nobody will want to be around you.</p>
<p>Use diplomacy, be smart, be subtle. Don’t prove other people wrong</p>
<h2 id="16---be-authentic-be-transparent-be-you">16 - Be authentic. Be transparent. Be you!</h2>
<p>Don’t play any roles. Let people feel that what they see is what they get.<br>
人设早晚崩塌</p>
<p>Don’t put on a mask. Stop playing roles to please others. Stop faking and allow yourself to be you.<br>
不能同意,和前面几章明显矛盾。 我无常心,众心为心</p>
<h2 id="17---communicate-effectively">17 - Communicate effectively</h2>
<p>Get your counterpart to talk about themselves. Ask questions about the others’ interests like why? Where? How?</p>
<p>In a world where everybody continually wants to talk about themselves, listening is GOLD.</p>
<h2 id="18---the-deadly-sin-in-human-relations-you-need-to-avoid">18 - The deadly sin in human relations you need to avoid</h2>
<p>As humans, we are innately selfish.</p>
<p>You are human, so you will be tempted to talk about yourself. You want to shine. You want to be admired. You want to be acknowledged. You want to impress. Anyways, you are much better off to resist this temptation.<br>
开启上帝模式,跳出三界外,不玩地位 0 和游戏,赐予他们需要的东西吧</p>
<p>Do you want the other person’s permission for something? Do you want their business? Their goodwill? If you want any of this, keep the conversation focused on them.</p>
<p>If you want to be successful, let others do the talking about themselves and listen. Only talk about yourself when you are invited, or asked to do so. If others are interested in you, they will ask. If so, talk a little bit about yourself and then turn the focus back to them.</p>
<p>Don’t be selfish. Keep the focus on them.</p>
<h2 id="19---say-thank-you">19 - Say thank you!</h2>
<p>Bookmark - Location 683</p>
<p>I’m a huge fan of gratitude. I think it’s one of the most powerful forces in the universe and being very grateful not only brings good things into our lives, but it also makes us notice more and more of those that are already there.</p>
<p>It’s human nature to like and respond to people who appreciate us and show us gratitude.<br>
希望别人感恩与感激也是人性</p>
<p>Be grateful to people and show it to them with kind words or little gestures and you can be assured that it will come back to you multiplied.</p>
<p>Say it with joy. Maintain eye contact. It means a lot more when you look people that you thank in the eyes. Say “Thank you, Peter,” “Thank you, Mary.” Use people’s names. It makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Let the power of gratitude change your relationships and your life for the better.</p>
<h2 id="20---admit-your-mistakes">20 - Admit your mistakes</h2>
<p>If we want to build trust with people and influence them and want to be the real thing we have to find the strength of admitting our mistakes-even if it’s difficult. Don’t waste your energy making up excuses or justifications.</p>
<p>Admitting a mistake and taking the consequences takes much more strength than denial. And it’s much healthier. Instead of losing energy denying it, it will liberate you.</p>
<p>Admit your mistakes, but avoid repeating the same ones over and over again.</p>
<h2 id="21---stop-gossiping">21 - Stop gossiping</h2>
<p>I know, sometimes it’s very tempting to hear the latest rumors from other people. The problem is that most probably the person who tells you these rumors starts spreading rumors about you, once you turn your back on them.<br>
传别人闲话给你的人,也会传你的闲话</p>
<p>Stop gossiping. Everybody wants to be with a person of integrity.</p>
<h2 id="22---stop-judging">22 - Stop judging</h2>
<p>Judging and condemning others. People don’t want to be judged. Period. People want to be liked, made to feel important, and appreciated. Not judged.</p>
<p>Don’t judge people. Once you are tempted to judge, take a look at yourself and see if you have the flaws you judge in other people.</p>
<h2 id="23---forgive-everyone">23 - Forgive everyone</h2>
<p>The antidote to this is Forgiveness! To be a forgiving person is not only good for your relationships with other people, it’s also the fast track to success and happiness. This is not about being right or wrong; it’s about you being well and not wasting energy. Forgive even if it was the other party who wronged you. You are doing it for yourself!<br>
不要去记恨人渣,别让他们持续伤害你</p>
<p>Let them go, forgive them, forget them and move on.</p>
<p>Don’t be a fool! Forgive everyone and be fun to be around!</p>
<h2 id="24---keep-your-word">24 - Keep your word</h2>
<p>Remember a good reputation built over a long time can be destroyed in seconds.</p>
<p>If you talk a lot but don’t follow up with action, people will lose trust in you.</p>
<p>Never make promises you can’t keep and over-deliver on everything you do. If you say you are going to be somewhere, be there. Mean everything you say. No wishy-washy talk. If you don’t mean it, don’t say it. Do what you say you’re going to do. Never tell a lie. If you can’t, don’t or won’t do something, tell people the truth right away. Don’t play with people’s emotions. Don’t say things only to impress. Be authentic.</p>
<p>Don’t undermine your reputation and your self-worth. Tell the truth and keep your commitments.</p>
<h2 id="25---treat-others-as-you-would-like-others-to-treat-you">25 - Treat others as you would like others to treat you.</h2>
<p>Do unto others as you would have others do unto you.</p>
<h2 id="26---remember-peoples-names">26 - Remember people’s names</h2>
<p>Remember people’s names. You’ll make people feel more important, and most importantly you build better relationships and trust.</p>
<h2 id="27---avoid-arguments">27 - Avoid arguments</h2>
<p>Do you ever really, really win an argument? Yes? I don’t think so. You might have “won” the argument, but you surely lost your “opponents” sympathy.</p>
<p>You can’t win an argument. If you lose it, you lose it; if you win it, you also lose it. Why? Because you made the other party look inferior and might even have hurt their dignity. And yes. You probably haven’t changed their opinion anyway.</p>
<p>How many times did you win an argument with your boss? Did the promotion come right away, or are you still waiting? How many times did you win an argument against a client? Where you right? Yes? Did you win? Yes? Did he buy? Probably not. If possible concentrate on things you agree on instead of focusing on things on which you differ.<br>
争论不可能赢,赢了面子输掉里子</p>
<p>If someone wants to start an argument with you, agree with them. The blue car is better than the red one? Yes! You are right. Period. No room for an argument. It’s not a sign of weakness to avoid arguments. It’s a sign of strength. Remember, you can’t win anyway. If</p>
<p>instead of wasting your time arguing with them give them the feeling of significance and win their goodwill.</p>
<p>Avoid arguments. Save your time. You can’t afford to lose time arguing, nor can you afford to take the consequences.</p>
<p>remember not many people are able to admit mistakes.</p>
<p>Could they be right? What benefit will my reaction have? What price do I have to pay if I’m right? Is it better to be quiet? Where is the opportunity here? Avoid arguments. You can’t win them.</p>
<h2 id="28---praise-and-acknowledge-people-honestly-and-sincerely">28 - Praise and acknowledge people honestly and sincerely</h2>
<p>Praise the behavior, not the person. It will create an incentive for others to act the same way.<br>
夸他们做的事情,不要去直接夸奖人,会显得不真诚</p>
<p>Make saying kind things to at least three different people a daily habit.</p>
<h2 id="29---show-everyone-kindness-and-respect">29 - Show everyone kindness and respect</h2>
<p>Show every person you meet kindness and respect. Every person has a story as compelling and complicated as your own. Just as you are extraordinary, so are they.</p>
<p>Many times in my life, people I first thought of as “What a strange person” or “He doesn&rsquo;t seem to be very bright” have become my best friends. Meet people with kindness and respect and great things can come from it.</p>
<p>Every now and then you might end up disappointed when you are kind to people, and they don’t respond to it, or maybe even take advantage of you. Don’t let this change you. It’s not your problem; it’s theirs. It’s a price worth paying for meeting all the other great people who’ll come into your life.<br>
你肯定会遇到一些傻逼,别理他们就好</p>
<p>Remember: If somebody is rude to you, it’s their problem, not yours.</p>
<p>Show everyone kindness and respect. They deserve it. Even the &ldquo;bad&rdquo; ones.</p>
<h2 id="30---dont-give-direct-orders---be-more-subtle">30 - Don’t give direct orders - be more subtle</h2>
<p>People don’t like to be given direct orders. It goes against our nature. You can convince people much more subtly by asking questions like “Did you consider this option?” or “Do you think that would work?” or “What would you think of this?”, “Maybe this one would work better?”</p>
<p>Always give people the opportunity to get things done themselves.</p>
<p>Asking questions is not only a smoother way to get results it also stimulates the creativity of the person you ask. It’s much easier for people to accept a decision or an order if they at least feel that they had their part in the process.</p>
<p>Effective leaders use the power of questions instead of giving direct orders.</p>
<h2 id="31---believe-in-peoples-potential">31 - Believe in people’s potential</h2>
<p>Remind your employees of their outstanding work in the past, give them a vision of themselves they are eager to live up to, believe in them, and they will rise to the occasion.</p>
<p>You can easily lead people and make them trust you if you have their respect and you earn that respect by believing in them and showing respect for their abilities and their work.</p>
<p>Believe in the potential of people, and you will see miracles happen.</p>
<h2 id="32---be-an-example">32 - Be an example</h2>
<p>The best way of influencing others is by being an example. Treat other people how you want to be treated. Adopt the attitude you want other people to show you. You might have heard the theory that other persons are like a mirror towards us. Observe this fact closely!</p>
<p>You need to accept that you cannot change others. What you can do is to accept them as they are and be the best example and person that you can be.<br>
你不能改变任何人,只能让他们模仿你</p>
<p>Be the example of what you want to see in the world.</p>
<h2 id="33---remain-humble">33 - Remain Humble</h2>
<p>Remain Humble<br>
做人要谦虚</p>
<p>Humble people have a clear idea of their abilities and achievements; they acknowledge their flaws and admit mistakes and limitations. They are open to new ideas even if they don’t entirely agree with them. They appreciate the value of everything and accept there are many different ways that people can contribute to this world.<br>
不要固步自封</p>
<ul>
<li>Enjoying the lowly status of being an outsider and a nobody</li>
</ul>
<p>Remain humble and enjoy the advantages of it.</p>
<h2 id="34---let-the-other-person-come-up-with-your-idea">34 - Let the other person come up with your idea</h2>
<p>No one likes being sold on something or being told something. We want to feel that the decision was ours or that the idea was ours. We want people to ask us for our opinions, our wishes, and our thoughts. So, why not use this to your advantage?</p>
<p>The best way is always to plant the idea in somebody’s mind and let them think about it and meditate on it. Frequently, you will see the same person coming up with the same idea a couple of days later defending it as if it were their own idea. (I have to admit that this happens to me from time to time).<br>
别告诉他们你的你的想法,引导他们自己想出来</p>
<p>The easiest way to let the other person feel it was their idea is ASKING. When you make an offer, ask the client what he really needs, or ask them to complete your offer to themselves. If you go on a family vacation, ask your family where they want to go and come to a consensus. If you are going out with friends, ask them what they like best. If you go on date night with your spouse ask him or her, what they’d like to do. So easy and yet so difficult, right?</p>
<p>Ask and let the other person come up with your idea.</p>
<h2 id="35---be-on-time">35 - Be on time</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The while we keep a man waiting, he reflects on our shortcomings.” True or true?</p>
<h2 id="36---focus-on-the-other-persons-strengths">36 - Focus on the other person’s strengths</h2>
<p>Our focus determines our overall perception of the world.</p>
<p>So, if we focus on other people’s strengths what will happen? Yes. Exactly. We’ll see more of their strengths! Will that improve our personal relationships? You bet it will.</p>
<ul>
<li>What are their unique strengths? • What are you most proud of thinking of them? • What do they do best? • What are their most significant personal and professional accomplishments? • What gifts do they have? • What makes them unique and compelling?</li>
</ul>
<p>Focus on the other person’s strengths and see them in an entirely new way.</p>
<h2 id="37---dont-criticize">37 - Don’t criticize.</h2>
<p>Criticism is useless. The only thing it does is put a person on the defensive and makes them try to justify themselves.</p>
<p>The thought that criticism can improve something is old and outdated. Criticism only brings resentment and can demoralize family members, friends, colleagues, and employees.<br>
批评已经不好使了,对个人企业政府都不会有用</p>
<p>We all know people we want to lecture, improve, and change, but you know what? Forget it. It’s impossible to change other people unless they are the ones who want to change. What you can do is start with yourself. Be the change you want to see in others, be the role model; be the example.<br>
再强调一次,不要尝试用任何方法改变任何人。不可能成功</p>
<p>No good will come out of criticizing others. Swallow your criticism and work on yourself instead.</p>
<h2 id="40---a-great-way-to-give-feedback">40 - A great way to give feedback</h2>
<p>with the criticism that comes after the “BUT”. The feedback will lose its effectivity and maybe even credibility. You can easily avoid this using “and” instead of “but.”</p>
<h2 id="41---let-the-other-person-save-face">41 - Let the other person save face</h2>
<h2 id="41-let-the-other-person-save-face">41-Let the other person save face</h2>
<p>When somebody makes a mistake, let them save face.</p>
<h2 id="42---make-people-feel-happy-about-what-you-are-telling-them-to-do">42 - Make people feel happy about what you are telling them to do</h2>
<p>We don’t like to be told what to do. Period. Even if it’s from people close to us.</p>
<p>A brilliant way of rejecting offers or invitations is this one: 1. Express gratitude for the invitation 2. Show your honest regret that you can’t accept the job or the event 3. Suggest a substitute who can do the job instead of you</p>
<h2 id="44---recognize-the-worth-of-every-individual">44 - Recognize the worth of every individual</h2>
<p>The most common mistakes that damage relationships are the following: • Failure to give credit for suggestions • Failure to correct unfairness • Failure to praise and encourage • Criticizing people in front of others • Failure to ask employees their opinions • Failure to inform employees of their progress • Favoritism</p>
<p>Make people feel worthy by thinking that they are important. Yes, it’s that easy. If you are convinced that other people are important, your behavior will show it.</p>
<p>Remember. People want to feel important.</p>
<p>Notice people. Everybody wants to be noticed. When you notice somebody, you are paying them a big compliment. You&rsquo;re boosting their morale showing them “I recognize you.” And what happens then? People become friendlier, more helpful and better workers.</p>
<p>Recognize the worth of every individual, and you will win allies for life.</p>
<h2 id="45---talk-about-your-own-mistakes-first">45 - Talk about your own mistakes first.</h2>
<h2 id="45-talk-about-your-own-mistakes-first">45-Talk about your own mistakes first.</h2>
<p>Admit your mistakes-even if you haven’t corrected them yet-this makes you an authentic, honest person that people want to be around-because you are of a rare breed. In the best case, you can even convince somebody to change their behavior and not make the same mistakes you made.</p>
<p>Talk about your mistakes first and praise a lot-and people will want to hear your opinion and advice.</p>
<h2 id="46---be-nice">46 - Be nice</h2>
<p>My friend Manuel is the nicest guy you can imagine. Always helping, always smiling, people like to be around him. He has an immensely powerful network that he uses to help everyone, but when he notices people taking advantage of him, he tells them very clearly that they can now leave his inner circle and if they do any more bad stuff he will use the same network to destroy them.<br>
善良必需带刺</p>
<p>Be nice but don’t let other people fool you. Even nice people say “NO” or “enough is enough” every now and then.</p>
<h2 id="47---be-positive">47 - Be positive</h2>
<p>Be an optimist. Be positive in every interaction. It’s free, and people will seek your company.</p>
<h2 id="48---praise-and-praise-a-lot">48 - Praise and praise a lot!</h2>
<h2 id="48-praise-and-praise-a-lot">48-Praise and praise a lot!</h2>
<p>When you praise, go into details. “Good job” is not enough. Tell the person exactly what he or she is doing well and why it’s so crucial for you or your company. Remember, we all want real appreciation and praise, but it has to be sincere and genuine. The principles in this book only work when they are honest and come directly from your heart. Transform people’s lives by praising them.</p>
<h2 id="49---how-to-make-a-good-impression--2nd-part">49 - How to make a good impression | (2nd part)</h2>
<p>Don’t try too hard to make a good impression, but tell everyone around you that they are making a good impression.</p>
<h2 id="50--help-others-to-like-themselves-better-boost-their-self-esteem">50- Help others to like themselves better. Boost their self-esteem</h2>
<p>Make it a habit to see the good in people, to give them sincere compliments and watch how much better your relations with others become. Help them like themselves better.</p>
<h2 id="51---make-it-look-easy">51 - Make it look easy</h2>
<p>If you tell your kids, your spouse or your employees that they are too stupid to do a certain thing, not talented enough, that they’re doing it all wrong then you killed all their aspirations right there in the beginning-if they are unfortunate enough to believe you. On the other hand, if you use encouragement, make it seem easy, tell them that nobody is born a master at his craft and that with patience and consistency they can hone their skill and the outcome will look quite different.</p>
<p>Make it look easy and see people thrive.</p>
<h2 id="52---use-positive-talk">52 - Use positive talk</h2>
<p>Science has now found out that the way we talk about ourselves or events has a profound impact on our mindset and even our reality. People who tend to talk pessimistically in the morning tend to experience their day as much worse, while people who speak positively at the start of the day tend to experience their day as much more positive, meeting with much more opportunities. It’s not rocket science. We’ve all experienced it.</p>
<p>So cut the crap. Eliminate complaining, sarcasm and teasing from your conversations and use positive talk.<br>
少废话,戒讽刺挖苦,聊点爱听的</p>
<h2 id="54---write-a-thank-you-note">54 - Write a Thank you Note</h2>
<p>Show people that they are making the world a better place and write them a thank you note or a thank you email.</p>
<h2 id="55---beware-of-people-with-false-self-esteem">55 - Beware of people with false self-esteem</h2>
<p>Someone who walks into a room showing off, bragging, looking like a peacock, probably doesn’t have high self-esteem. In fact, this behavior is the exact opposite of healthy self-esteem. If we can choose, we really don’t want to be around this kind of people. To worsen matters, people with false self-esteem will always judge and value you-and themselves-by what you achieve and by your results, not for what you really are.</p>
<p>Stick around people with higher levels of self-esteem. Mostly, they are humble and don&rsquo;t need to show off continually.</p>
<p>Become a high self-esteem person and stay away from low self-esteem people except if you can be a role model for them.</p>
<h2 id="56---put-yourself-in-other-peoples-shoes">56 - Put yourself in other people&rsquo;s shoes</h2>
<h2 id="56-put-yourself-in-other-peoples-shoes">56-Put yourself in other people&rsquo;s shoes</h2>
<p>Empathy is one of the keys to success in our relationships with other people. It’s easy to judge and condemn people, any fool can do that. It’s a lot harder to try to understand them. If you have the patience and make an effort to understand them, to find out what makes them tick you can achieve anything and surely people will love to be around you.</p>
<h2 id="58---dont-make-assumptions">58 - Don’t make assumptions</h2>
<p>Stop making assumptions and start asking questions. It will change everything.</p>
<h2 id="59---dont-take-anything-personally">59 - Don’t take anything personally</h2>
<p>Whatever people say to you-the good or the bad-is none of your business. Only YOU have to know who you are. Get over the need to be right. Remember what you want: To be right or to be in peace? Be smart. Choose peace.</p>
<p>Save yourself some suffering and don’t take anything personally.<br>
天要下雨,由他去吧</p>
<h2 id="60---stop-spending-time-with-the-wrong-people">60 - Stop spending time with the wrong people</h2>
<p>Stop spending time with the wrong people</p>
<p>if you meet somebody that just doesn’t like you, think to yourself. “Well, I guess this is just one from the other 50%” and move on. And even more important: don’t try to change yourself so that they like you or spend time with you. It’s useless.</p>
<p>Life is too short to spend time with people who don’t treat you with love and respect. Let them go and make new friends.<br>
生命短暂,远离傻逼坏逼</p>
<h2 id="62---solve-your-problems-right-away">62 - Solve your problems right away</h2>
<p>Did you ever notice that some people spend more time and energy avoiding and dancing around their problems, blaming others for them, than in trying to solve them?<br>
抱怨没用,解决问题<br>
Conclusion</p>
<p>Your attitude will be crucial. Keep a positive mindset even when things don&rsquo;t go that well. Remember, sometimes when we are working towards a goal we get tested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Master The Game</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/money-master-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/money-master-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The largest financial institutions are set up to make a profit for themselves, not their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I really want? (Vision.) 2. What is important about it? (Values.) 3. How will I get it? (Methods.) 4. What is preventing me from having it? (Obstacles.) 5. How will I know I am successful? (Measurements.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is certainly one of the ways we can turn the dreams we have into the reality we live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The largest financial institutions are set up to make a profit for themselves, not their clients.</p>
<ol>
<li>What do I really want? (Vision.) 2. What is important about it? (Values.) 3. How will I get it? (Methods.) 4. What is preventing me from having it? (Obstacles.) 5. How will I know I am successful? (Measurements.)</li>
</ol>
<p>Money is certainly one of the ways we can turn the dreams we have into the reality we live.</p>
<p>success leaves clues. People who succeed at the highest level are not lucky; they’re doing something differently than everyone else does.</p>
<p>I’ll put you in the room with these and many other superstars who get consistent results, decade after decade, in up markets and down, booms and busts. Together we will uncover the core secrets to their investment success and see how to apply them even to the smallest amount of money.</p>
<p>The idea is to know how to survive and thrive in any market condition. These real experts will explain how.<br>
Bookmark - Location 714</p>
<p>they can anticipate the road ahead. Remember this: anticipation is the ultimate power.</p>
<p>This book is committed to one primary outcome: to set you up so you have an income for life without ever having to work again. Real financial freedom! And the good news is, it can be achieved by anyone.</p>
<p>It is not realistic to finance a 30-year retirement with 30 years of work. You can’t expect to put 10% of your income aside and then finance a retirement that’s just as long.</p>
<p>No matter where you live, if you don’t have another source of income, you could end up the best-dressed greeter at Wal-Mart.</p>
<p>It’s an amazing feeling to know you’ll never run out of income.</p>
<p>We know we need to save more and invest. So why don’t we do it? What’s holding us back?</p>
<p>SECTION 1: WELCOME TO THE JUNGLE: THE JOURNEY BEGINS WITH THIS FIRST STEP</p>
<p>SECTION 2: BECOME THE INSIDER: KNOW THE RULES BEFORE YOU GET IN THE GAME</p>
<p>SECTION 3: WHAT’S THE PRICE OF YOUR DREAMS? MAKE THE GAME WINNABLE</p>
<p>SECTION 4: MAKE THE MOST IMPORTANT INVESTMENT DECISION OF YOUR LIFE</p>
<p>SECTION 5: UPSIDE WITHOUT THE DOWNSIDE: CREATE A LIFETIME INCOME PLAN</p>
<p>SECTION 6: INVEST LIKE THE .001%: THE BILLIONAIRE’S PLAYBOOK</p>
<p>SECTION 7: JUST DO IT, ENJOY IT, AND SHARE IT</p>
<p>Compound interest is such a powerful tool that Albert Einstein once called it the most important invention in all of human history.</p>
<p>200 years after Franklin’s death, a period of time that had seen stocks grow at an average compounded rate of 8%,</p>
<p>our earned income will never bridge the gap between where we are and where we really want to be. Because earned income can never compare to the power of compounding! Money is better than poverty, if only for financial reasons.</p>
<p>Before you speak, listen. Before you write, think. Before you spend, earn. Before you invest, investigate. Before you criticize, wait. Before you pray, forgive. Before you quit, try. Before you retire, save. Before you die, give.</p>
<p>You have to move from just working for money to a world where money works for you.</p>
<p>You’re already a financial trader. You might not think of it in just this way, but if you work for a living, you’re trading your time for money. Frankly, it’s just about the worst trade you can make. Why? You can always get more money, but you can’t get more time.</p>
<p>If you stop working, you stop making money. So let’s take you out of the equation and look for an alternative approach. Let’s build a money machine to take your place—and, let’s set it up in such a way that it makes money while you sleep.</p>
<p>the most important financial decision of your life. The decision? What portion of your paycheck you get to keep. How much will you pay yourself—off the top, before you spend a single dollar on your day-to-day living expenses?</p>
<p>Whatever that number is, you’ve got to stick to it. In good times and bad. No matter what. Why? Because the laws of compounding punish even one missed contribution.</p>
<p>Can anybody remember when the times were not hard and money not scarce?</p>
<p>But here’s the key to success: you have to make your savings automatic.</p>
<p>It’s time to take the first of the 7 Simple Steps to your Financial Freedom! The most important financial decision of your life needs to be made right now! It’s time for you to decide to become an investor, not just a consumer. To do this, you simply have to decide what percentage of your income you will set aside for you and your family and no one else.</p>
<p>If you don’t want to work, you have to work to earn enough money so that you won’t have to work.</p>
<p>The bottom line is, if we feel like we’re losing something, we avoid it; we won’t do it. That’s why so many people don’t save and invest. Saving sounds like you’re giving something up, you’re losing something today. But you’re not. It’s giving yourself a gift today of peace of mind, of certainty, of the large fortune in your future.</p>
<p>Obviously money meant very different things for Adolf Merckle and Chuck Feeney. What does money really mean to you? Do you use money, or does money use you? Like I’ve said from the beginning: if you don’t master money, at some level, it’s going to master you.</p>
<p>Whatever emotion you’re after, whatever vehicle you pursue—building a business, getting married, raising a family, traveling the world—whatever you think your nirvana is, I have found it’s only an attempt by your brain to meet one or more of six human needs.</p>
<p>“What’s the secret to wealth?” And he said, “Tony, you know it, and you know it well. You teach it to everyone. It’s gratitude.”</p>
<p>BECOME THE INSIDER: KNOW THE RULES BEFORE YOU GET IN THE GAME</p>
<p>You have to learn the rules of the game, and then you have to play better than anyone else.</p>
<p>Whether you are a seasoned investor or just beginning to see yourself as an investor, the jungle that Ray Dalio so vividly described holds the same dangers for all of us. But most of the danger lies in the fact that what you don’t know can hurt you.</p>
<p>Money Power Principle 1. Don’t get in the game unless you know the rules!</p>
<p>But the system isn’t set up for your broker to have endless options and complete autonomy in finding what’s best for you. And this could prove costly.</p>
<p>Risk comes from not knowing what you’re doing.</p>
<p>The core concept of successful investing is simple: Grow your savings to a point at which the interest from your investments will generate enough income to support your lifestyle without having to work.</p>
<p>There are two phases to your investing game: the accumulation phase, in which you are socking away money for growth, and the decumulation, during which you are withdrawing income.</p>
<p>The goal of the nonprofessional should not be to pick winners—neither he nor his “helpers” can do that—but should rather be to own a cross section of businesses that in aggregate are bound to do well. A low-cost S&amp;P 500 index fund will achieve this goal.</p>
<p>When you look at the results on an after-fee, after-tax basis, over reasonably long periods of time, there’s almost no chance that you end up beating the index fund.<br>
Note - Location 1705<br>
中国特色股市除外</p>
<p>From 1984 to 1998, a full 15 years, only eight out of 200 fund managers beat the Vanguard 500 Index. (The Vanguard 500, put together by founder Jack Bogle, is a mirror image of the S&amp;P 500 index.)</p>
<p>Just how badly does chasing performance hurt us? Over a 20-year period, December 31, 1993, through December 31, 2013, the S&amp;P 500 returned an average annual return of 9.28%. But the average mutual fund investor made just over 2.54%, according to Dalbar, one of the leading industry research firms. Ouch! A nearly 80% difference.</p>
<p>Because we buy high and sell low. We follow our emotions (or our broker’s recommendations) and jump from fund to fund. Always looking for an edge. But when the market falls, when we can’t take the emotional pain any longer, we sell. And when the market is up, we buy more.</p>
<p>As a famous money manager named Barton Biggs observed, “A bull market is like sex. It feels best just before it ends.”</p>
<p>The goal in investing is to get the maximum net return for a given amount of risk (and, ideally, the lowest cost).</p>
<p>Life isn’t about waiting for the storm to pass; it’s about learning to dance in the rain. It’s about removing the fear in this area of your life so you can focus on what matters most.</p>
<ul>
<li>Stocks have by far been the best place to be for long-term growth over time. • Stocks are volatile. In the pages ahead, you will learn from the “market masters” how to “smooth out the ride” by investing in and diversifying across multiple different indexes. • Don’t be sold that someone is going to beat the market. Instead, align yourself with the market! Once you put your indexing plan in place (which we will do step by step), you won’t have to spend your time trying to pick which stock to buy because the index will have done it for you. This will save you a tremendous amount of time and angst in trying to pick a winner. • Begin to think like an insider! Never again will you tolerate the “herd” mentality in your own life.</li>
</ul>
<p>MYTH 2: “OUR FEES? THEY’RE A SMALL PRICE TO PAY!”</p>
<p>The mutual fund industry is now the world’s largest skimming operation, a $7 trillion trough from which fund managers, brokers, and other insiders are steadily siphoning off an excessive slice of the nation’s household, college, and retirement savings.”</p>
<p>You put up the capital, you took all the risk, and they made money no matter what happened.<br>
Note - Location 1960<br>
基金经理</p>
<p>MYTH 3: “OUR RETURNS? WHAT YOU SEE IS WHAT YOU GET”</p>
<p>Most people are familiar with the boilerplate disclaimer that past performance doesn’t guarantee future results. Far fewer are aware of how past performance numbers themselves can be misleading.</p>
<p>So if the fund advertises a 6% return, its investors achieved closer to 3%.</p>
<p>“Follow the money. Always follow the money.”</p>
<p>MYTH 4: “I’M YOUR BROKER, AND I’M HERE TO HELP”</p>
<p>“It is difficult to get a man to understand something, when his salary depends on his not understanding it.”</p>
<p>THE CHEF DOESN’T EAT HIS OWN COOKING</p>
<p>it was found that 49% of the managers owned no shares in the fund they manage. That’s right. The chef doesn’t eat his own cooking.</p>
<p>So the obvious question is, if the people who manage the fund aren’t investing in the fund they run, why in the world would I? Good question!!! The chef doesn’t eat his own cooking if the ingredients are bad or if he knows what the kitchen really looks and smells like. These fund managers are smart—they work under the hood.</p>
<p>MYTH 6: TARGET-DATE FUNDS: “JUST SET IT AND FORGET IT”</p>
<p>MYTH 7: “I HATE ANNUITIES, AND YOU SHOULD TOO”</p>
<p>MYTH 8: “YOU GOTTA TAKE HUGE RISKS TO GET BIG REWARDS!”</p>
<p>Remember Warren Buffett’s top two rules of investing? Rule 1: don’t lose money! Rule 2: see rule 1.</p>
<p>allow you and me to participate in the gains of the stock market without risking any of our principal!</p>
<p>But here’s the truth: the ultimate thing that stops most of us from making significant progress in our lives is not somebody else’s limitations, but rather our own limiting perceptions or beliefs.</p>
<p>Everybody has a fear of failure at some level; at times we’ve all been fearful that perhaps we are not enough.</p>
<p>Money is nothing more than a reflection of your creativity, your capacity to focus, and your ability to add value and receive back.</p>
<p>I want you to know that you’re the creator of your life, not just a manager. Sometimes</p>
<p>The day you stop racing is the day you win the race.</p>
<p>You can make them more conservative or more aggressive. You’re in control, so put in numbers that fit with your lifestyle, your current reality, and your future dreams.</p>
<p>One of the most powerful ways to accelerate the pace at which you achieve your financial goals—and the most painless way I know—is to implement the Save More Tomorrow plan,</p>
<p>She had left out a huge piece of future earnings, one that many people neglect to include in their financial planning: Social Security.</p>
<p>And yet contrast is a beautiful thing. When you get around people who are playing the game of life at a higher level, you either get depressed, pissed off, or inspired.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 1. SAVE MORE AND INVEST THE DIFFERENCE</p>
<p>If everything seems under control, you’re not going fast enough.</p>
<p>The goal of these next minichapters is to get you thinking about how to make your financial dreams come true faster than you ever thought possible.</p>
<p>You can be rich by having more than you need, or by needing less than you have.</p>
<p>the best strategy to get around your belief system is to develop a new belief!</p>
<p>What if—in one fell swoop, in one single move—you could save a huge chunk of money toward your Financial Freedom, and it wouldn’t cost you a dime more?</p>
<p>You want to know the banker’s secret? Your interest payments will tack on an additional 100% or more to your loan value.</p>
<p>Prepay your next month’s principal, and you could pay off a 30-year mortgage in 15 years in many cases! Does that mean double your monthly payments? No, not even close! Here’s the key: Money Power Principle 3. Cut your mortgage payments in half! The next time you write your monthly mortgage check, write a second check for the principal-only portion of next month’s payment.</p>
<p>Take your $4 habit and boost it to $10 a day, and now you’re drinking away over $141,250 in savings over 20 years. That’s the cost of a four-year college education!</p>
<p>At the end of the day, the question to ask yourself is this: Do my expenses, big and small, bring me the thrill they once did?</p>
<p>“How do you truly become more valuable? Learn to work harder on yourself than you do on your job.</p>
<p>“All you have to do to earn more money in the same amount of time is simply become more valuable.”</p>
<p>And if you employ yourself, your raise becomes effective when you are!</p>
<p>“For things to change, you have to change. For things to get better, you have to get better.”</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 3. REDUCE FEES AND TAXES (AND INVEST THE DIFFERENCE)</p>
<p>Remember you get to spend only what you keep; if you invest with a 3% net return, it takes 24 years to double your money.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 4. GET BETTER RETURNS AND SPEED YOUR WAY TO VICTORY</p>
<p>If you’re prepared, and you know what it takes, it’s not a risk. You just have to figure out how to get there. There is always a way to get there.</p>
<p>SPEED IT UP: 5. CHANGE YOUR LIFE—AND LIFESTYLE—FOR THE BETTER</p>
<p>My favorite things in life don’t cost any money. It’s really clear that the most precious resource we all have</p>
<p>Never test the depth of the river with both feet.</p>
<p>Asset allocation is the most important investment decision of your lifetime,</p>
<p>He told me that there are only three tools for reducing your risk and increasing your potential for financial success: 1. Security selection—stock picking; 2. Market timing—short-term bets on the direction of the market; and 3. Asset allocation—your long-term strategy for diversified investing.</p>
<p>It means dividing up your money among different classes, or types, of investments (such as stocks, bonds, commodities, or real estate) and in specific proportions that you decide in advance, according to your goals or needs, risk tolerance, and stage of life.</p>
<p>good people often fail because they do the right thing at the wrong time.</p>
<p>I don’t gamble, because winning a hundred dollars doesn’t give me great pleasure. But losing a hundred dollars pisses me off.</p>
<p>when you buy shares of an ETF, you are not buying the actual stocks, bonds, commodities, or whatever else is bundled in the fund—you are buying shares in an investment fund that owns those assets.</p>
<p>if you have your money machine in full gear, and you have the desire, there’s nothing wrong with setting aside a tiny percent of your Risk/Growth Bucket to pick some stocks and do some day trading. “Index your important money, then go have fun,” Burton Malkiel told me. “It’s better than going to the racetrack.” But, he said, limit yourself to 5% or less of your total assets or portfolio.</p>
<p>What if I put my money in the stock market at its peak, and it starts dropping? Or if I buy into a bond fund, and the interest rates begin to spike? Markets are always going to fluctuate, and we’ve learned that nobody, I mean nobody, can consistently and successfully predict when it’s going to happen. So how do we protect ourselves from all the ups and downs and really succeed?</p>
<p>“We tend to put money into the market and take it out at exactly the wrong time.”</p>
<p>Nobody could guess that the US government would do something that no government has ever done in human history—it decided to prop up the markets by “printing” $4 trillion, while telling the world that it would continue to do so indefinitely, literally until the economy recovered!</p>
<p>if you think you can time the markets, you’re wrong.</p>
<p>Far more money has been lost by investors preparing for corrections, or trying to anticipate corrections, than has been lost in corrections themselves.</p>
<p>Remember, the goal is to take emotion out of investing because emotion is what so often destroys investing success, whether it’s greed or fear.</p>
<p>You can actually make higher returns by investing regularly in a volatile stock market.</p>
<p>to be a successful investor, you need to rebalance your portfolio at regular intervals.</p>
<p>allocation is everything! So you want to diversify between your Security Bucket and your Risk/Growth Bucket. You want to diversify across asset classes, markets, and time. 2. You don’t want to hesitate to get in the market trying to have perfect timing; instead, use dollar-cost averaging and know that volatility can be your friend, providing opportunities to buy investments cheaply when the market is down. This technique will increase your portfolio’s value when the markets come back up. 3. Have a Dream Bucket that gives you emotional juice and excitement so you can experience the benefits of your investing prowess in the short term and midterm instead of just someday far in the future. 4. Use rebalancing and tax harvesting to maximize your returns and minimize losses.</p>
<p>Here is the reality: most people couldn’t stomach another 2008 without selling some or all of their investments.</p>
<p>Remember, a 66% loss would require nearly 200% gains just to get back to even—just to recoup the portion of your nest egg that it may have taken your entire life to save!</p>
<p>FREEDOM: CREATING YOUR LIFETIME INCOME PLAN</p>
<p>I have enough money to retire comfortably for the rest of my life. Problem is, I have to die next week.</p>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>No matter what anyone tells you, or sells you, there isn’t a single portfolio manager, broker, or financial advisor who can control the primary factor that will determine if our money will last.</p>
<p>you are dead, who cares?! What’s painful is if you live too long with no income—that’s when you’ll really suffer.”</p>
<p>The key to abundance is meeting limited circumstances with unlimited thoughts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>人人都能用英语</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/english/%E4%BA%BA%E4%BA%BA%E9%83%BD%E8%83%BD%E7%94%A8%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 04:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/english/%E4%BA%BA%E4%BA%BA%E9%83%BD%E8%83%BD%E7%94%A8%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;只“学”不“用”（这是大多数中国学生的写照）的下场就是在十几年之后依然在学依然无用（这是大多数中国学生的现实）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“学一辈子”，却坚持“一辈子不用”的原因就在于害怕犯错。儿时犯错往往招致惩罚，成年之后，就算没有来自他人的惩罚，还有因为犯错而导致自己自卑和尴尬，所以，很多人是“不惜一切代价”避免出错的。然而，要知道知识的习得过程离不开试错，没有试错，就不可能有全面而真实的进步。所以，要知道犯错是正常的，甚至是不可或缺的。做事的时候，出错是必然的，如果正在做事却一点错都没有，那不是做事 ── 那是在做梦。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>只“学”不“用”（这是大多数中国学生的写照）的下场就是在十几年之后依然在学依然无用（这是大多数中国学生的现实）。</p>
<p>“学一辈子”，却坚持“一辈子不用”的原因就在于害怕犯错。儿时犯错往往招致惩罚，成年之后，就算没有来自他人的惩罚，还有因为犯错而导致自己自卑和尴尬，所以，很多人是“不惜一切代价”避免出错的。然而，要知道知识的习得过程离不开试错，没有试错，就不可能有全面而真实的进步。所以，要知道犯错是正常的，甚至是不可或缺的。做事的时候，出错是必然的，如果正在做事却一点错都没有，那不是做事 ── 那是在做梦。</p>
<p>animals are born equal, but some animals are more equal than others.”</p>
<p>能够流利阅读英语的好处很多。自由两个字基本上就是最大的概括。比如，我们可以直接阅读一手的文献资料，而不必经过漫长的等待之后去读实际上错误百出的译文。译文往往并不靠谱，因为翻译真的是很难很难的工作。很多的时候，译文不靠谱都怪不得译者，起码，至少有一部分语言是根本无法翻译的。如若你能够流利阅读英语，那你在阅读译作的时候，一定会时不时笑出来 ── 很多翻译错的句子，你甚至可以根据经验在脑子里还原出原本的英文。不用依赖翻译，是一种莫大的解脱。当你的英文阅读熟练到一定程度之时，你会自然而然地庆幸，那是一种千金不换的庆幸。不过，现在还没到那时候，至于当下么，信不信只能由你。</p>
<h2 id="自己不知道">自己不知道</h2>
<p>——因为中文的名词是不分单复数的，中文的动词是没有时态的。这两个错误剔除掉之后，相当于解决了大多数的问题。</p>
<p>“一致关系”：主谓一致、主句从句时态一致、非谓语动词与逻辑主语主动被动关系一致、代词指代一致、并列成分结构一致……</p>
<p>作为英语使用者，也不要被英语老师所迷惑。作为老师，教育产品的一部分，他当然会强调“正确”、“准确”、“标准”——无论他们自己是否真的“正确”、“准确”、“标准”。有时候想想挺悲哀的，大部分老师不得不抬高对自己的要求，并不是出于对进步的渴望，而只不过是为了满足“消费者”的实际上并不合理的期望，英语老师也是人，于是其中的大多数有着与其他大多数人一样的心理局限或者说人性局限。一个人做不到的时候，就会装，一直装到自己都信了为止</p>
<p>不敢开口说英语还有另外一个重要的担心，被周围的人所嘲弄。这确实令人厌烦。可是，想想吧：一个正常的人会嘲弄婴儿蹒跚的脚步么？不会。一个正常人会嘲弄残疾人么？不会，也不应该。那么再看看，有人讲外语发音不标准或者难听却会招致嘲弄，有道理么？有人讲外语一辈子带着口音并且改不过来而招致嘲弄，有道理么？</p>
<p>“是否听懂”在这里并不重要。大幅度提高听觉输入量的目的在于重建语音识别能力，重点并不在于文字理解能力。婴儿在</p>
<p>“双语语音过滤器”早就应该固化了。事实上，我很怀疑各种英语幼教占用了太多原本可以用来习得其它技能的时间，进而限制了幼儿大脑的发展。不过，不能指望只听听录音看看电视，孩子就可以学会外语</p>
<p>——只要开始做，就会发现其实并不难，因为“哪怕听不懂都无所谓”。听得多了，听得久了，早晚有一天想听不懂都不太容易。当然，即便是最初的时候，为了效果更佳，可以有意识地渐渐提高文本难度，并且最好配合精读。这期间几乎所有的人都会感觉没什么进步，但是，这种</p>
<h2 id="泡脑子">泡脑子</h2>
<p>大多数人学英语最终失败的重要原因之中最严重却又最隐蔽的可能是这个：大多数人对短期收益要求太高，对长期收益要求太低。</p>
<p>事实上，大多数人很难做到用母语流畅朗读任何句子——尽管大多数人都认为自己可以做到。举例来说，也许大多数人能够在不作任何准备的情况下，能够比较流畅地朗读《读者》杂志中的任意句子</p>
<p>而这些“快速阅读”建议基本上都是治标不治本的，因为它们解决的都是输入速度问题而已，而不是输入之后的理解速度问题。输入的速度再快，理解速度跟不上，又于事何补？有的时候有点想不明白为什么那么多人脑子里明明想着要提高</p>
<p>1.拿起词典独自上路查词典与朗读一样是提高阅读理解能力的最直接有效的手段之一。</p>
<p>2.不查词典者死我们身体的每一个器官都或多或少拥有一定的“进化能力”。弹琴弹久了，手指就会变得更加灵活；长期坚持锻炼，心肺功能就会更加强大；话说得比别人更多，舌头就比别人更灵活</p>
<p>英语老师与学生最大的不同可能只有一个，英语老师必须查词典（如果还有别的话，就是语法书之类的参考书），而学生却有除了查词典之外的另外一个选择——参加各种各样的课程。英语课上老师做什么呢？其实大抵上只不过是把昨天晚上他查过的单词、词组，以及他通过查词典（以及其它的工具书）再动脑才搞明白的句子给学生们讲一遍。而学生呢？做在下面听。学生们倒是听了，然而，本质上却没有参与阅读理解的过程</p>
<p>遇到弄不明白“爱情”与“婚姻”不是一回事儿的异性，最好敬而远之，否则痛苦的一生“就在不远处等着你”……</p>
<p>遇到搞不清“政府”与“国家”之间区别的人，轻易不要与之沟通，否则你可能会因此发现麻烦不断祸患无穷……</p>
<p>不知道“目标”与“计划”并非一回事的人，并不知道他们自己可能会因为“死守计划”（Stick to theplan）而最终无法达成目标……</p>
<p>不知道“上学”和“学习”不是一回事儿的人，其中一些可能会因为自己有博士学位就瞧不起中专毕业的人；反过来，另外一些可能会因为自己只有中专文凭而憎恨那些有博士学位的人……</p>
<p>不知道“一个人”和“一个人的看法”之间的区别的人，要么可能迷信权威，要么可能把自己当作绝对权威……</p>
<p>不知道 “Action”和 “Reaction”之间的差异的人，弄不好一辈子都是周遭环境的奴隶而已却又完全处于无意识状态……</p>
<p>很多学生讨厌历史课，其实只不过是没弄明白“历史”与“历史书”之间的重要差异……</p>
<p>整理词汇。要知道，读完一篇文章之后，自己动手整理词汇，远比背单词书效率高出许多——可惜，大多数人并不相信。</p>
<p>一个五年级的学生，如果每天能够做到独立阅读 10 分钟的话，那么就要比那些不做独立阅读的孩子每年多读 62 万 2 千词……</p>
<p>——管它是抽象的还是具体的。形容词是干什么的？你用形容词来记录你对你能够感知的那个事物的感知。动词呢？动词用来记录你能够感知的那个事物所发出的动作。那么最后，副词呢？副词修饰动词的时候，是用来记录你对你能够感知的那个事物所发出之动作的感知；副词用来修饰形容词的时候，是用来记录你对你能够感知的那个事物的感知的感知。（这一分钟的内容看起来比较拗口，只要能做到对这些文字断句准确，理解无误，那么仅在一分钟之后就已经脱胎换骨</p>
<p>“简洁、朴素、有效、准确、具体”。当然，这不是铁律，如果有能力用华丽的文字说清楚道理也不是不行；反过来，用朴素的语言叙述动人的故事也未尝不可。但是所有希望自己的思考结果能够有效表达的人都最好牢记这十个字的标准</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>在搞清楚用户的问题之前就动手开发，这是我多次犯过的大忌。</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E5%9C%A8%E6%90%9E%E6%B8%85%E6%A5%9A%E7%94%A8%E6%88%B7%E7%9A%84%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E4%B9%8B%E5%89%8D%E5%B0%B1%E5%8A%A8%E6%89%8B%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91%E8%BF%99%E6%98%AF%E6%88%91%E5%A4%9A%E6%AC%A1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 12:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/%E5%9C%A8%E6%90%9E%E6%B8%85%E6%A5%9A%E7%94%A8%E6%88%B7%E7%9A%84%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E4%B9%8B%E5%89%8D%E5%B0%B1%E5%8A%A8%E6%89%8B%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91%E8%BF%99%E6%98%AF%E6%88%91%E5%A4%9A%E6%AC%A1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1. Do consumers recognize that they have the problem you are trying to solve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. If there was a solution, would they buy it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Would they buy it from us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Can we build a solution for that problem?” The common tendency of product development is to skip straight to the fourth question and build a solution before confirming that customers have the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1. Do consumers recognize that they have the problem you are trying to solve?</p>
<p>2. If there was a solution, would they buy it?</p>
<p>3. Would they buy it from us?</p>
<p>4. Can we build a solution for that problem?” The common tendency of product development is to skip straight to the fourth question and build a solution before confirming that customers have the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>财富与幸福指南</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E4%B8%8E%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 08:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E4%B8%8E%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;追求财富，而不是金钱或地位。财富是指在你睡觉时仍能为你赚钱的资产。金钱是我们转换时间和财富的方式。地位是你在社会等级体系中所处的位置。&lt;br&gt;
Note - Location 321&lt;br&gt;
社会地位是个 0 和游戏&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>追求财富，而不是金钱或地位。财富是指在你睡觉时仍能为你赚钱的资产。金钱是我们转换时间和财富的方式。地位是你在社会等级体系中所处的位置。<br>
Note - Location 321<br>
社会地位是个 0 和游戏</p>
<p>依靠出租时间是不可能致富的。你必须拥有股权（企业的部分所有权），才能实现财务自由。</p>
<p>获得财富的一个途径，就是为社会提供其有需求但无从获得的东西，并实现规模化。</p>
<p>要想获得财富，就必须充分利用杠杆效应。商业杠杆来自资本、劳动力和复制边际成本为零的产品（代码和媒体）。</p>
<p>有一大批机器人可供我们免费使用。为了提高热效率、节约空间，这些机器人就集中放在数据中心。用起来吧。</p>
<p>学习微观经济学、博弈论、心理学、说服术、伦理学、数学和计算机。</p>
<p>设定一个大胆的个人时薪，并严格执行。如果解决一个问题节省的成本低于时薪，那就忽略问题；如果外包一项任务的成本低于时薪，那就选择外包。</p>
<p>你真正想要的其实是财富。财富就是在你睡觉时也可以帮你赚钱的资产。财富是可以进行生产的工厂和机器人。财富是不分昼夜为客户服务的计算机程序。财富也可以是银行里被投资于其他资产或业务的钱。</p>
<p>要想在社会上赚到钱，就要为社会提供其有需求但无从获得的东西。如果社会已经创造出需要的产品和服务，你也就不被需要了。</p>
<p>通过互联网，每个人都可以找到自己的受众。只要在网上进行独特的自我表达，你就有机会传播快乐，累积财富，打造产品，创立企业。[78]</p>
<p>出发点并不重要，行为本身才重要。因此，遵守道德标准并非易事。</p>
<p>如果不持有企业股权，个人投入和收益的关联性就会非常强。几乎所有领取月薪的工作，即便是律师或医生这样的高薪职业，也需要投入时间才能获得相应的收入。</p>
<p>第一种是劳动力杠杆，也就是让别人给你打工。劳动力杠杆是一种最古老的杠杆，但在现代社会，这种杠杆的效果并不是最好的。[1]我甚至认为这是一种最落后的杠杆。因为管理他人是一件非常复杂、极具挑战的工作，需要高超的领导技巧，弄不好管理者会落个众叛亲离、被手下生吞活剥的下场。[78]</p>
<p>资本是第二种相对较好的杠杆形式。资本杠杆就是用钱来扩大决策的影响力。[1]资本是一种更现代的杠杆形式，利用资本杠杆有一定的难度，需要一定的技能。在 20 世纪，人们曾经利用资本杠杆获得了惊人的财富。资本杠杆是 20 世纪杠杆的主要形式。</p>
<p>而编程、写书、录播客、发推特、拍视频这些事情不需要经过任何人的许可。由此可见，新杠杆就像一个均衡器，极大地缩小了人与人之间的差距，让社会变得更平等。[78]比如，每个出色的软件开发者现在都有一大群机器人在为其工作。写好代码后，这些机器人就开始工作，在开发者睡觉的时候也在为其赚钱。[78]靠出租自己的时间是永远无法致富的。</p>
<p>人生的一大目标应该是掌控自己的时间。理想的工作是利用杠杆效应的工作。在这种工作模式下，你可以掌控自己的时间，并能对自己的产出成果负责。如果你通过提供绝佳的解决方案给企业带来了神奇的转机，那么你必将得到金钱的回报。特别是，如果别人根本不知道你是如何做到的，他们就必须不断地付钱给你，让你继续提供这种产品或服务。而你之所以能够做到这一点，就是因为你的痴迷、技能或天赋。</p>
<p>还有一点对我有所裨益：我把自由看得高于一切。我说的自由是多种多样的：想做什么就做什么的自由，不想做什么就不去做的自由，不受自我情绪或外界影响的自由，等等。自由是我最珍视的价值。</p>
<p>要直面现实，就要放下自我，消除自我意识，忘记自我判断，平复自我情绪。人虽然是高级动物，但情绪化的自我意识的存在会带来反刍式思维，让一些欲望蒙蔽我们的双眼，让我们看不清现实，从而让我们对“世界应该怎样”妄下判断。这种情况经常发生，尤其是在把政治诉求和商业问题搅在一起时。</p>
<p>难点在于看清真相。要看清真相，就必须摆脱自我，因为自我不想面对真相。自我越弱小，对自己反应的限制越少，对自己想要的结果的执念越低，就越容易看清现实。</p>
<p>对美好现实的渴求蒙蔽了对真实世界的认知。所谓痛苦，就是无法继续无视事实。</p>
<p>Note - Location 1130<br>
越是渴望以某种特定的方式解决问题，我就越不可能看清事实。</p>
<p>没有思考，你就不会有出色的商业创意，也不可能做出正确的判断。我鼓励大家每周至少花一天时间来思考（最好是两天，因为即使预留了两天，最终也可能变成一天）。</p>
<p>悠闲的大脑才能产生伟大的创意。一个倍感压力、案牍劳形、四处奔波、焦头烂额的人，是没有办法思考的。所以，一定要为思考挤出时间。[7]</p>
<p>几乎所有的偏见都是为了帮助人们在信息不完整的情况下迅速做出判断。对于重要的决策，要抛开记忆和身份，专注于问题本身。</p>
<p>Bookmark - Location 1244</p>
<p>如果难以抉择，那答案就是否定的</p>
<p>人与人的区别不是“受过教育”和“没受过教育”，而是“喜欢阅读”和“不喜欢阅读”。</p>
<p>阅读数学、科学和哲学领域的经典作品。不要读畅销书，不要看新闻。避免加入任何所谓的“读书俱乐部”，避免追求任何的社群认同。把真理置于社群认同之上。[11]</p>
<p>而现实是，生活就是一场单人游戏。人独自出生，独自死亡，独自解读人世间的一切。你的记忆只属于你一个人。你出生前无人在意，你离开人世后也无人在意，你存在于人世间只是短短几十年，人生就是一场单人游戏。</p>
<p>从本质上讲，生活的过程就是用精心培养的好习惯替换那些在不经意间养成的坏习惯，努力成为一个更幸福的人。你的幸福指数最终取决于你的习惯和你花最多时间与之相处的人。</p>
<p>你的秘密越多，幸福感就越低。[11]</p>
<p>新闻的目的就是让人感到焦虑和愤怒。但新闻背后的科学、经济学、教育和冲突趋势是有积极意义的。要保持良好的心境、乐观的心态。[11]i<br>
追求财富，而不是金钱或地位。财富是指在你睡觉时仍能为你赚钱的资产。金钱是我们转换时间和财富的方式。地位是你在社会等级体系中所处的位置。<br>
Note - Location 321<br>
社会地位是个 0 和游戏</p>
<p>依靠出租时间是不可能致富的。你必须拥有股权（企业的部分所有权），才能实现财务自由。</p>
<p>获得财富的一个途径，就是为社会提供其有需求但无从获得的东西，并实现规模化。</p>
<p>要想获得财富，就必须充分利用杠杆效应。商业杠杆来自资本、劳动力和复制边际成本为零的产品（代码和媒体）。</p>
<p>有一大批机器人可供我们免费使用。为了提高热效率、节约空间，这些机器人就集中放在数据中心。用起来吧。</p>
<p>学习微观经济学、博弈论、心理学、说服术、伦理学、数学和计算机。</p>
<p>设定一个大胆的个人时薪，并严格执行。如果解决一个问题节省的成本低于时薪，那就忽略问题；如果外包一项任务的成本低于时薪，那就选择外包。</p>
<p>你真正想要的其实是财富。财富就是在你睡觉时也可以帮你赚钱的资产。财富是可以进行生产的工厂和机器人。财富是不分昼夜为客户服务的计算机程序。财富也可以是银行里被投资于其他资产或业务的钱。</p>
<p>要想在社会上赚到钱，就要为社会提供其有需求但无从获得的东西。如果社会已经创造出需要的产品和服务，你也就不被需要了。</p>
<p>通过互联网，每个人都可以找到自己的受众。只要在网上进行独特的自我表达，你就有机会传播快乐，累积财富，打造产品，创立企业。[78]</p>
<p>出发点并不重要，行为本身才重要。因此，遵守道德标准并非易事。</p>
<p>如果不持有企业股权，个人投入和收益的关联性就会非常强。几乎所有领取月薪的工作，即便是律师或医生这样的高薪职业，也需要投入时间才能获得相应的收入。</p>
<p>第一种是劳动力杠杆，也就是让别人给你打工。劳动力杠杆是一种最古老的杠杆，但在现代社会，这种杠杆的效果并不是最好的。[1]我甚至认为这是一种最落后的杠杆。因为管理他人是一件非常复杂、极具挑战的工作，需要高超的领导技巧，弄不好管理者会落个众叛亲离、被手下生吞活剥的下场。[78]</p>
<p>资本是第二种相对较好的杠杆形式。资本杠杆就是用钱来扩大决策的影响力。[1]资本是一种更现代的杠杆形式，利用资本杠杆有一定的难度，需要一定的技能。在 20 世纪，人们曾经利用资本杠杆获得了惊人的财富。资本杠杆是 20 世纪杠杆的主要形式。</p>
<p>而编程、写书、录播客、发推特、拍视频这些事情不需要经过任何人的许可。由此可见，新杠杆就像一个均衡器，极大地缩小了人与人之间的差距，让社会变得更平等。[78]比如，每个出色的软件开发者现在都有一大群机器人在为其工作。写好代码后，这些机器人就开始工作，在开发者睡觉的时候也在为其赚钱。[78]靠出租自己的时间是永远无法致富的。</p>
<p>人生的一大目标应该是掌控自己的时间。理想的工作是利用杠杆效应的工作。在这种工作模式下，你可以掌控自己的时间，并能对自己的产出成果负责。如果你通过提供绝佳的解决方案给企业带来了神奇的转机，那么你必将得到金钱的回报。特别是，如果别人根本不知道你是如何做到的，他们就必须不断地付钱给你，让你继续提供这种产品或服务。而你之所以能够做到这一点，就是因为你的痴迷、技能或天赋。</p>
<p>还有一点对我有所裨益：我把自由看得高于一切。我说的自由是多种多样的：想做什么就做什么的自由，不想做什么就不去做的自由，不受自我情绪或外界影响的自由，等等。自由是我最珍视的价值。</p>
<p>要直面现实，就要放下自我，消除自我意识，忘记自我判断，平复自我情绪。人虽然是高级动物，但情绪化的自我意识的存在会带来反刍式思维，让一些欲望蒙蔽我们的双眼，让我们看不清现实，从而让我们对“世界应该怎样”妄下判断。这种情况经常发生，尤其是在把政治诉求和商业问题搅在一起时。</p>
<p>难点在于看清真相。要看清真相，就必须摆脱自我，因为自我不想面对真相。自我越弱小，对自己反应的限制越少，对自己想要的结果的执念越低，就越容易看清现实。</p>
<p>对美好现实的渴求蒙蔽了对真实世界的认知。所谓痛苦，就是无法继续无视事实。</p>
<p>Note - Location 1130<br>
越是渴望以某种特定的方式解决问题，我就越不可能看清事实。</p>
<p>没有思考，你就不会有出色的商业创意，也不可能做出正确的判断。我鼓励大家每周至少花一天时间来思考（最好是两天，因为即使预留了两天，最终也可能变成一天）。</p>
<p>悠闲的大脑才能产生伟大的创意。一个倍感压力、案牍劳形、四处奔波、焦头烂额的人，是没有办法思考的。所以，一定要为思考挤出时间。[7]</p>
<p>几乎所有的偏见都是为了帮助人们在信息不完整的情况下迅速做出判断。对于重要的决策，要抛开记忆和身份，专注于问题本身。</p>
<p>Bookmark - Location 1244</p>
<p>如果难以抉择，那答案就是否定的</p>
<p>人与人的区别不是“受过教育”和“没受过教育”，而是“喜欢阅读”和“不喜欢阅读”。</p>
<p>阅读数学、科学和哲学领域的经典作品。不要读畅销书，不要看新闻。避免加入任何所谓的“读书俱乐部”，避免追求任何的社群认同。把真理置于社群认同之上。[11]</p>
<p>而现实是，生活就是一场单人游戏。人独自出生，独自死亡，独自解读人世间的一切。你的记忆只属于你一个人。你出生前无人在意，你离开人世后也无人在意，你存在于人世间只是短短几十年，人生就是一场单人游戏。</p>
<p>从本质上讲，生活的过程就是用精心培养的好习惯替换那些在不经意间养成的坏习惯，努力成为一个更幸福的人。你的幸福指数最终取决于你的习惯和你花最多时间与之相处的人。</p>
<p>你的秘密越多，幸福感就越低。[11]</p>
<p>新闻的目的就是让人感到焦虑和愤怒。但新闻背后的科学、经济学、教育和冲突趋势是有积极意义的。要保持良好的心境、乐观的心态。[11]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>让时间陪你慢慢变富 定投改变命运</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%AE%A9%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E9%99%AA%E4%BD%A0%E6%85%A2%E6%85%A2%E5%8F%98%E5%AF%8C-%E5%AE%9A%E6%8A%95%E6%94%B9%E5%8F%98%E5%91%BD%E8%BF%90/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 02:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%AE%A9%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4%E9%99%AA%E4%BD%A0%E6%85%A2%E6%85%A2%E5%8F%98%E5%AF%8C-%E5%AE%9A%E6%8A%95%E6%94%B9%E5%8F%98%E5%91%BD%E8%BF%90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 几乎所有人都有定投的资格和能力&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(yellow) - Location 135&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;定投这个策略，包括以下几个要点：标的究竟是什么？长期究竟是多久？定期究竟是多长的间隔？每次投入至少多少金额？&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1 几乎所有人都有定投的资格和能力</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 135</p>
<p>定投这个策略，包括以下几个要点：标的究竟是什么？长期究竟是多久？定期究竟是多长的间隔？每次投入至少多少金额？</p>
<p>2 证券交易市场是世界第九大奇迹</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 197</p>
<p>人们总以为“选择股票”是很困难的事情——其实，一点都不难！因为那所谓的“困难”，完全是惯性思维造成的，实际上，那只不过是人们总是不肯或者不敢使用最简单直接粗暴有效的方法的结果。这个方法太简单了，简单到令人难以置信：直接选择市场上所有人都最看好的股票。</p>
<p>3 究竟有没有只涨不跌的投资标的</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 260</p>
<p>所以，巴菲特总是推荐普通人购买标准普尔 500 指数基金——在中国，标准普尔 500 的对应标的就是沪深 300 指数基金。指数基金的好处就在于它本质上等同于“跟紧大市”，不用赌某个公司的运气，而是赌全国的运气，或者是全球的运气——反正，长期来看，人类经济规模就是不断增长的。你看，只要是长期，突然之间就不再是赌了，因为长期来看，风险竟然可以被稀释殆尽。</p>
<p>4 普通人做投资的唯一正确方式</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 359</p>
<p>“一把梭”的人忍受不了太久的痛苦——事实上，任何人都无法长期承受痛苦。这跟所谓的“坚强”完全没有任何关系。从另外一个角度来看，这也不是愚笨，这只是愚昧。在一个月，或者两个月、三个月的痛苦之后，甚至在事后看来马上就要挺过去了的时候，即，在第六个月的时候（或者稍前），很多人会基于种种原因离场——交易市场上把这种行为称为“割肉”。你看，韭菜都是自己割自己的，并且割下来的都是血淋淋的肉。</p>
<p>5 为什么很少有人使用定投策略</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 387</p>
<p>6 定投策略神奇力量背后的深刻机理</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.1.所有人都应该培养自己的主动人格 &gt; Location 472</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.1.所有人都应该培养自己的主动人格 &gt; Location 482</p>
<p>远离那些整天抱怨的人——他们不知道自己正在做什么。他们会义愤填膺豪气万丈地抱怨不公平，好像天道站在他们那边一样。他们永远不想知道真相：这世界就是不公平的。用更准确更不偏不倚不卑不亢的词汇去描述，那就是，这世界充满了不对称性，正如这世界充满了不确定性一样。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.2.大多数主动的人竟然不知道边界 &gt; Location 540</p>
<p>他们自身作为父母，自己的未来不会有任何改善；他们的孩子被父母不知不觉变成了“对自身从来都是被动的人”。正确的选择原本应该是：家长应该主动把自身变得越来越好；使得孩子因羡慕产生变好的愿望，进而孩子会采取主动，哪怕仅仅是表面模仿都是好的开始。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.4.驾驭趋势的最优策略只能是主动地被动 &gt; Location 636</p>
<p>一个决策是否重大，是否有意义，只看一个衡量标准就好了：它是针对趋势的选择吗？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.4.驾驭趋势的最优策略只能是主动地被动 &gt; Location 665</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.5.定投是“主动地被动”的最佳践行策略 &gt; Location 680</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.6.顺应趋势的被动力量究竟有多么强大 &gt; Location 772</p>
<p>投资周期越长，被动的优势越大；投资额度越大，被动的优势越大。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.7.在主动的边界内你还有多少空间 &gt; Location 818</p>
<p>一切的真相都没有任何义务照顾你的情绪。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.8.对于长期的理解决定你的结果 &gt; Location 868</p>
<p>如果你感到绝望，那只不过是因为你现在差而已。如果你的感受是很绝望，那只不过是因为你现在真的很差。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.8.对于长期的理解决定你的结果 &gt; Location 872</p>
<p>你越差，就越需要耐心。勇气是什么来着？勇气是唯一不可伪造的美德。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.8.对于长期的理解决定你的结果 &gt; Location 903</p>
<p>一个上升，不叫趋势，一个下降，也不叫趋势；一个上升加上一个下降，构成一个周期；判断趋势需要至少两个周期。两个周期之后，那两个波动所构成的，只能是三种趋势之一：上升、水平，或者下降。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - 6.9.普通人究竟有什么样的极端优势 &gt; Location 992</p>
<p>十多年前，我偶尔听到某大公司两个中层干部正在讨论如何让下属乖乖听话：——唉，你是咋做到让他们乖乖听话的啊？我可真是愁死了！——那还不简单吗？组织老婆团一起去看房！我告诉你呀，别看他们现在在你面前牛逼哄哄，只要他们买了房，今天交了首付，明天就是孙子！没跑！</p>
<p>7 愚蠢与愚昧的区别以及被动聪明</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1068</p>
<p>8 有些人总是身处正确的一侧</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1147</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1178</p>
<p>对所有普通人来说，定投策略绝对可行，毫无水分，并且全靠你自己。这里所说的普通人，不分种族、不分国籍、不分地域、不分性别、不分年龄、不分高矮胖瘦美丑，也不分何种性取向……关键在于，甚至压根儿不分智商和学历！</p>
<p>9 镜像世界另外一侧的众生相</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1202</p>
<p>他们的解释总是惊人的一致：唉，我就是太贪了！</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1210</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1226</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1249</p>
<p>10 定投是普通人必需的选择</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1296</p>
<p>决定一个人富有的三个条件，一是出身，二是运气，三是努力；而这三者之中，努力是最微不足道的。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1337</p>
<p>结语</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1405</p>
<p>在你的主动的边界之内，不断增强心理建设，并且拼命想办法在场外赚钱；与此同时，在主动的边界之外，主动地选择一个绝对值得长期持有的标的，用你在场外赚到的钱，定期投入……长此以往，你就可以借助趋势产生的神奇的被动力量，不仅有可能摆脱阶层固化的束缚，甚至干脆改变命运——最终，获得自由。</p>
<p>Note - Location 1408</p>
<p>国运看起来是一个终极标的,我应该定投标普 500。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>财富自由之路_李笑来</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1%E4%B9%8B%E8%B7%AF_%E6%9D%8E%E7%AC%91%E6%9D%A5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/investment/%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1%E4%B9%8B%E8%B7%AF_%E6%9D%8E%E7%AC%91%E6%9D%A5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;00.20160729 出售时间的三条铁律 ★&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(blue) - Location 163&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;出售时间的三条铁律：成长才是根本关键，重视价值忽略估值，耐心比什么都重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(blue) - Location 167&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所谓的个人财富自由，指的就是某个人再也用不着为了满足生活必需而出售自己的时间了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>00.20160729 出售时间的三条铁律 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 163</p>
<p>出售时间的三条铁律：成长才是根本关键，重视价值忽略估值，耐心比什么都重要。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 167</p>
<p>所谓的个人财富自由，指的就是某个人再也用不着为了满足生活必需而出售自己的时间了。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 203</p>
<p>选择的判断标准有一个就足够了：我选择的事能不能让我积累更多的能力？</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 204</p>
<p>现在外卖很发达，我去收外卖的时候，就常常想，那么多人把自己的时间用那么便宜的价格卖出去，然后做的居然是完全没有能力积累效应的事，他们以后可怎么办呀？</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 207</p>
<p>不需要突破，也就不需要成长、不需要进一步学习。做这样的工作可能会有一些聊以自慰的成就感（多半来自稳定)，但是因为没有成长，而一辈子不可能跨越里程碑。</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 245</p>
<p>了一种习惯，因为欺骗的短期收益总是很高。长久以后，这个习惯几乎无法根除，你看坚守铁律之所以难，是因为违背铁律的诱惑实在太大了。可是反过来看，所有的欺骗都不长久，都有水落石出的一天，这样来看，桥水的达里奥给出的建议实在很睿智。</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 253</p>
<p>没有耐心的人，更容易选择“终点式思维”，他们希望快一点完事儿，快一点看到结果，然后就能去到他们臆想出来的那个世界了。沒耐</p>
<p>01.20160801 阻碍财富自由的三大坑 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 278</p>
<p>1.你必须把最宝贵的注意力全部放在你自己身上的“成长”。2.创业就是成长。没有成长就不是创业。3.不珍惜自己注意力的人，最终注定是贫穷的，因为他们终生被收割，终生不可能有真正有价值的产出，怎么可能最终变得富有？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 291</p>
<p>第一大坑，叫&quot;莫名其妙地凑热闹&quot;</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 298</p>
<p>.网上的热闹更多，甚至可以给自己泡杯茶，摆好姿势再围观。呀！万科出事儿了！呀！吴亦凡出事儿了！呀！赵薇出事儿了!呀. . .这种人现在在网上被叫做吃瓜群众。比起在路边围观的人，网上的吃瓜群众们还会将凑热闹变成一种闹剧——一群人本来就莫名其妙地围观，结果看着看着，围观的人居然也相互之间吵了起来，引来更多的人围观. . .据说好奇心是创造力的源泉呢，你看，事实上，无论是谁都有满满的好奇心。可惜，都浪费在看莫名其妙的热闹上了。不过，这也很正</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 305</p>
<p>第二个大坑，叫&quot;心急火燎地随大流&quot;突然之间，某个“趋势”就出现了。比如最近的&quot;内容创业&quot;,比如去年的&quot;O2O&quot;……有什么东西火了！于是，转瞬间就会有一大批人（事实上，总是绝大多数人）心急火燎地去随大流……可是他们忘了，在任何一个大的趋势出现的时候，一定有另外一批人，早就准备好了——虽然可能并不是有意准备的。若是内容创业真的是趋势，大潮流，那么，在此之前随写了十年字的那票人显然是“虽然不故意却必然准备最充分”的呀，这才开始心急火燎的人，哪儿是另外一票人的对手呢？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 318</p>
<p>第三个大坑，叫&quot;操碎了别人的心肝&quot;</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 330</p>
<p>—句话：自己是泥菩萨，一条小河都过不去，却要操碎了别人的心肝，真不知道图个啥。人家创业失败了，你也不会有损失，可若是人家创业成功了，你害怕，是不？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 345</p>
<p>钱不是最重要的，因为它可以再生；时间也不是最重要的，因为它本质上不属于你，你只能试着与它做朋友，让它为你所用。你的注意力才是你所拥有的最重要、最宝贵的资源——从这个角度望过去，人生其实是公平的，因为你的注意力确实是你自己可以做主的，除非你自己放弃。所以，那结局是好是坏，其实真的是你自己选的。</p>
<p>Note - Location 348</p>
<p>注意力</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 351</p>
<p>这可能是人生最有价值的建议——因为，最终，你的一切价值，都是你的注意力的产出。而且，更为关键的是，一个人的注意力，很可能是唯一能够称得上是“与生俱来”的有产出能力的资源，仔细想想吧，还有别的什么是这样的吗？……那放在自己的哪儿上?答案明确而又唯一：放在“成长”上。有一句硅谷的“陈词滥调”其实是很有意义的：“创业就是成长。没有成长就不是创业。”</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 359</p>
<p>如果你想多走一步，可以试着罗列下面的内容（这个不算作业)：1.回顾一下你关注的事都是什么？罗列出来，判断一下，那些东西与你有关吗？与你的成长有关吗？2.回顾一下上周你关注的事情都是什么？罗列出来？判断一下，那些东西与你有关吗？与你的成长有关吗？3.回顾一下上个月……我知道你自己根本就想不起来了罢？</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 365</p>
<p>某种意义上，广告，其实就是这样的商业模式,不是吗？你可以研究一下微博上的营销大号，它们最擅长“吸引眼球”——“收割廉价甚至免费注意力”的另外一个说法；你再看看有多少人甚至在“主动贡献自己的注意力”，而后你就多少可以明白为什么这种商业模式可以最终做到“长盛不衰”。</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 370</p>
<p>你若是胆敢不在意你的注意力，你的注意力(事实上你的注意力其实就是真正有价值的你）就会被无情地收割起来然后被卖掉。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 373</p>
<p>不珍惜自己注意力的人，最终注定是贫穷的，因为他们终生被收割，终生不可能有真正有价值的产出，怎么可能最终变得富有？</p>
<p>01.20160805 我们最重要的财富是“注意力”★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 385</p>
<p>关键词：积累效应，幸福的关键，个体价值 1.当有些人问到为什么自己的行程满满当当，却依然感觉无甚收获时，我就会提醒他们，满的，是你的时间；闲置的，是你的注意力；荒废的，是你的成长。2.要把注意力放在自己的成长上。放在一切可以有积累效应的技能上，然后给予充分的学习、思考和磨炼。3.要把注意力不求回报地放到真爱身上，这是真正幸福的关键 。4.把注意力放在对整个社会真正有贡献的事情上去。个体价值等于他的社会贡献率。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 425</p>
<p>荒废的，是你的成长。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 455</p>
<p>掉进注意力三大坑的原因：对大多数人来说，短期享乐可比长期收获有用多。满足个人所谓的安全感、归属感、成就感。</p>
<p>02.20160812 付费就是捡便宜 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 463</p>
<p>1.过去的一段时间里，你付费捡到的便宜都有哪些？别说是这个频道，这个频道当然是超值的，这毫无疑问。2.过去的一段时间里，你在哪些可以捡便宜的地方却浪费了时间与注意力？3.过去的一段时间里，你发生过多少次因为跟家人吵架而整天心情不好的情况？4.如果你需要持续的注意力，却反复被打扰，你有沒有想出过什么有效对策？5.你在哪些地方忽略了资产的价值顺序，乃至于你吃了大亏?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 471</p>
<p>什么资源最重要？（注意力）什么资源更重要？（注意力 &gt;时间 &gt;金钱）</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 479</p>
<p>很多人留言说，不知道该用注意力去干嘛。O 积累知识 O 磨炼技能 O 观察生活 O 思考未来 O 创造价值 O 经营人脉</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 512</p>
<p>防范的东西。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 513</p>
<p>于是，我早就发明了自己的方法：手机永远设置为静音，所有的 pushnotification 全都关掉。我专注做事的时候，就是不该接受任何打扰的。等我停下来，休息的时候，可以顺手处理那些未读短信和未接来电。</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 527</p>
<p>是因为总体上来看花钱买时间更划算啊！</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 557</p>
<p>想要别人主动接近你，最好的方法就是时不时做出令人敬佩的事情。</p>
<p>03.20160819 人生最重的枷锁是“安全感”★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 561</p>
<p>1.几乎所有的进步都是放弃了部分安全感才可能获得的。2.追求百分之百的安全感，肯定会把自己困在永恒的当下。3.我们必须放弃一部分安全感，才能深入长期地观察、思考。4.不要与缺乏安全感的人合作——因为他们的世界里，实际上不可能有真正的合作关系。5.关于读书，把注意力放在如何应用读到的知识，改善自己的生活。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 573</p>
<p>大多数人是这样的：时时刻刻关注身边所有可以被关注的东西，而且非常害怕竟然有被自己漏掉的。没有办法长期集中观察，不能长期深入思考，注意力始终放在周围发生的每件事上。这样的人没有过去，也没有将来，他们甚至不知道自己原本可以有过去和将来。对于他们来说，只有一个没有前后对比的现在。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 580</p>
<p>终则可能导致被困在永恒的当下。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 583</p>
<p>从某种意义上来说:几乎所有的进步都是放弃了部分安全感才可能获得的。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 588</p>
<p>存，而是为了追求所谓的&quot;不被时代抛弃&quot;的安全感 。不信你看周围有多少人是追求百分之百的安全感的，他们时时刻刻被身边所发生的一切吸引，他们不可能在任何事情上深入长期观察、深入长期思考——这不一定是他们的本性，这只不过是他们自己没有意识到生存这种模式有什么局限——他们就像那些动物一样，就被困在永恒的当下 。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 604</p>
<p>之一就是不冒险。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 616</p>
<p>合作是什么？合作的本质其实是大家各自放弃一小部分安全感，并把那一部分安全感交由合作方来保障。信任是什么？信任是相信对方不会利用自己主动放弃的那一部分安全感。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 623</p>
<p>所谓的缺乏安全感，其实就是不相信他人竟然可以不利用自己放弃的那一部分安全感，所以只能自己去搞定百分之百的安全——这真是令人心力交瘁的状态，不是吗？如果你已经知道人们缺乏安全感的根源究竟是什么，你就会明白为什么这条建议是正确的：不要与缺乏安全感的人合作——因为他们的世界里，实际上不可能有真正的合作关系。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 646</p>
<p>百分之百的安全，带来的是百分之百的束缚。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 647</p>
<p>你的时间和注意力转瞬即逝，尽量不要把它们浪费在迅速贬值的信息上。</p>
<p>04.20160826 生活的根基“活有未来”★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 691</p>
<p>•长期来看，脑力的产出率一定比体力的产出率高，且高出许多个量级……•体力増长的玻璃顶很明显，脑力増长的玻璃顶不知道在哪儿……•体力衰退的时间来得很早，脑力衰退的时间来得晚很多……•通过暴力可获得的暴利正在减少，因为大趋势上来看，一定是知识更可能产生更大的暴利……</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 753</p>
<p>不要期望一次就能预测对。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 760</p>
<p>所谓的投资，无非就是用现在的资源换取未来的资源。</p>
<p>05.20160902 遇到贵人的方法 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 774</p>
<p>笃信加上耐心，才有可能帮你熬过偶然的失落，等到必然的好运。很多时候，阻碍我们行动的可能不是自己的能力，而是我们脑子里错误的观念。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 878</p>
<p>1.乐观的人更容易成为他人的贵人；2.贵人更容易遇到贵人;3.能帮助他人进步的才是真正的贵人；4.优秀的人，值得尊重的人更容易获得帮助;5.乐于分享的人更容易获得帮助；6.不给他人制造负担的人更容易获得帮助；7.不耻于求助的人更容易获得帮助；8.求助的时候不宜仅用金钱作为回报，帮助他人的时候不宜收取金钱回报；9.贵人不一定是牛人，牛人常常只不过是自顾自地牛，贵人不一样，他们常常“以和为贵”，更懂得“独贵</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 882</p>
<p>贵不如众贵贵”；10.很多时候，人们的成功，源自于大量的人希望看到他成功。反过来，若是有大量的人不愿意看到某人成功，那么此人很难获得所谓的“贵人相助”；11.正在做正确事情的人，更容易获得贵人相助，所谓得道多助，说的就是这个；12.活在未来的人更容易遇到贵人，因为别人能在他的身上看到未来。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 899</p>
<p>不是“求助”。</p>
<p>06.20160909 关于“资本”★</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 958</p>
<p>资本确实主要由钱构成，但，仅仅一堆钱放在那里肯定算不上是资本。</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1001</p>
<p>投资环境里，用一万元作为本金盈利 50%,和用十万元作为本金盈利 15%，前者的成绩优于后者，或者稍微专业化一点的说法是：前者的资金效率高于后者。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 1006</p>
<p>他们买垃圾股的根本原因就在于&quot;那玩意儿便宜&quot;。他们是看重绝对值的，所以，即便盈利潜力再高的股票，他们只要看一眼价格，&ldquo;觉得太贵&rdquo;，就扭头而去。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 1022</p>
<p>換言之，年收入 6 万元的人，拿出 5 千块钱作为投资款，并给这个投资款&quot;判上个无期徒刑&quot;，其实在很大的概率上并不会影响自己的生活质量。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 1024</p>
<p>获取财富的诀窍之一就是不冒险 。放弃安全感是为了让你有更多的精力，专注于特定的领域，长期地观察，深入地思考，而不是鼓励大家去冒险。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1052</p>
<p>以成为出类拔萃的投资人，那只不过是早晚的事情，首先因为他已经起步了；而且还相当于早已&quot;贏在起点&quot;，因为最初那个&quot;给自己的资金判上个无期徒刑&quot;的行为已经为他日后能够养成&quot;长期深入思考未来&quot;的能力打下了最殷实的基础。有了这个底子，很多的技巧根本就用不着了，很多的陷阱自动消失了，很多的无奈纠结瞬间烟消云散……我知道你现在很可能会觉得&quot;无期徒刑&quot;既残酷又没必要——可这就是你要习得的智慧：挣扎着学会分得清楚&quot;</p>
<p>07.20160916 关于“落后”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1220</p>
<p>1.早晚有一天，你要做到不再为了生活而出卖自己的时间。2.早晚有一天，你要做到不落后，成为前百分之二十，甚至前百分之一……</p>
<p>08.20160923 从平庸走向卓越的最佳策略：“多维竞争”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1252</p>
<p>很多时候，比较是一个坑，大坑。再干脆点说，比较就是陷阱。……所以我们要想办法选择无需比较即可获得的快乐与幸福——此句从书中原文修订而来。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1270</p>
<p>单个维度上，大家比的是长度；两个维度上，大家比的是面积；三个纬度上，大家比的是体积。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1317</p>
<p>比如你想要背单词。那就不要只是看着背，而是边看、边写、边说地背。一个维度变成三个维度，效果不说翻三倍，也至少比在那里眼巴</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1319</p>
<p>我在那篇《付费就是捡便宜》的文章中提到过，为了让老婆也能理解“注意力最宝贵”，我可是花了不少功夫，从不同维度给她解释了各种理由，多到可以出一本书了。所以只要你细心，其实有很多地方都可以借助多维度发挥巨大的作用。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1361</p>
<p>况，规划一个最适合自己的路径。如果暂时没有足够突出的维度，那就好好打磨自己的技能；如果已经在某一维度足够优秀，不要沉浸于已有的成绩中，不妨换个维度去突破一下自己的局限。</p>
<p>09.20160930 认识“元认知能力”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1391</p>
<p>注意力才是最宝贵的财富；付费其实是花钱捡便宜；百分之百的安全感可能是最大的枷锁；活在未来才可能遇见财富；自己先成为贵人才能不断遇到更多的贵人；很可能 1%之后都是落后；为自己打造多维度的竞争力才是出路；</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1410</p>
<p>一个人的财富创造能力最终也只与元认知能力有关——其他的都是附属因素。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1432</p>
<p>其实并不了解自己的思考过程、思考原理、思考方式；更是因为大多数人从未认真审视过自己的思考结果是否确实正确合理。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1490</p>
<p>你的创造，只有你自己觉得有价值的话，是几乎没有什么意义的，要有他人也认为有价值才可以，并且，“他人”的人数越多越好，“他人”人数越多，你的创造价值越高——不是吗？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1525</p>
<p>所谓的智商高，不光是能够解几道数学题，而是能够洞察这些数字背后的原理。所谓情商高，不光是会与人和睦相处，而是懂得对方内心深层次的需求。</p>
<p>10.20161007 提高元认知能力的方法 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1635</p>
<p>至干脆是生命之中绝对“不可或缺”的内容。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1657</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1661</p>
<p>方案的结果”。而认清情绪的来源，就是在调用元认知能力。</p>
<p>11.20161014“万能钥匙”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1778</p>
<p>我们的注意力除了被各种娱乐新闻，搞笑段子吸引之外，还会被另一种东西吸引：困扰我们的问题。解决英语听力问题：只要说得出，就能听得懂。你平时涉及的领域越多，在每个领域了解得越深，你就更有可能找到更多且更优质的钥匙。相从平庸走向卓越，最好的方法就是“多维竞争”。践行现在学到的理念时，需要你放弃一部分过去已有的安全感，将注意力集中到现在的方法中。</p>
<p>12.20161021“坚持”与“毅力”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1826</p>
<p>无论做什么事情，在开始之前，都要想尽一切办法为这个事情赋予重大的意义，甚至多重重大的意义。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1843</p>
<p>靠，这哪儿是人干的事儿啊？！然后，我就花了一个下午琢磨，有没有办法把背单词这事儿赋予一个重大的意义呢？很快我就想到一个。考过 TOEFL/GRE，拿到高分，在新东方教书，据说年薪百万，那……一个单词就相当于 50 块钱，这个爽啊！原来我计划刚开始先每天背五十个单词适应一段时间呢，想到这一层，马上决定，不行，第一天就要赚上 5000 元！这一转眼都是许多许多年前的事情了，你能想象在那样的时代里，一天赚上 5000 元人民币是什么心情吗？！</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1900</p>
<p>一个脑子里有“快速阅读”概念的人，永远也不知道自己读书没有收获，不是因为读得太慢，而是从来没有认真思考过。</p>
<p>Note - Location 1901</p>
<p>学而不思等于没学</p>
<p>13.20161028“错过”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1970</p>
<p>阅读时的快感会让人有一种错觉，认为自己看懂了文章的内容，生活就会自动变得不一样。但那只是幻觉，如果你回想不出自己当初到底读到了什么，其实这些文字对你的意义并不大。最终你只会在走过弯路之后才会想起，原来自己曾经读到过类似的提醒。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2031</p>
<p>系，调动所有感官为自己创造“带入感”，去琢磨、去研究、去想象，这个观念若是被自己吸收之后，自己应该变成什么样子？</p>
<p>14.20161104 这个世界是有生命的 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2067</p>
<p>很多客观上并不存在的事物，由于主观上存在一个概念，于是就好像那东西“真实存在”一样……</p>
<p>15.20161111 彻底戒掉“抱怨”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2184</p>
<p>最应该彻底戒掉的恶习是这个：抱怨记录自己的抱怨次数，以此督促自己戒掉抱怨 。改变能改变的，接受不能改变的，这才是我们生活幸福的前提 。抱怨的害处，并不仅仅在于浪费时间，也不仅仅在于那样会暴露自己的无能；它真正的害处在于，它会让你不由自主地放弃挣扎 。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2267</p>
<p>能解决就去解决（能力）；不能解决就承受（坚韧）；再观察一下，就发现，其实，绝大多数人，在第一个层面——能力上，就输了；而在第二个层面——坚韧上，从来就没有一丝一毫的进步</p>
<p>16.20161118 看见别人的好才能获得新生 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2327</p>
<p>某天上午，听一个人给我讲了一番道理，我觉得：“哇，好厉害！”当天下午，听另外一个人给我讲了另外一番道理，我又觉得：“哇，好厉害！”晚上躺在床上回想，突然发现这两个人所说的道理背后的根本竟然是矛盾冲突的……</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2402</p>
<p>你竟然可以从那些“原本你可能讨厌的人”的身上学到大量的好东西。更为惊人的是，由于你能更多地、不断地看到别人的好，你所身处的的的确确比原来要美好太多了……我总是不由自主地想，多多少少好奇，过去那么多年里，我错过了多少实际存在的美好呢？而且，若是错过了，肯定只能怪自己。</p>
<p>Note - Location 2405</p>
<p>我不喜欢樊登,可能只是嫉妒他能轻易的骗到钱</p>
<p>17.20161125 正确本身的价值</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2490</p>
<p>人云亦云很轻松，独立判断很困难。想要违背主流的观点，作出自己独立的选择，不光需要勇气，还需要智力。这样又费心、又费神的事情，当然不容易受欢迎。而这也击中了大多数“表现型选手”。因为他们只在乎看起来是否足够好，至于是不是真的好，他们其实并不关心。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2507</p>
<p>“听大多数人的话，参考少数人的意见，最终自己做决定。”这是很睿智的原则——在这里，“听大多数人的话”的意思不是只“按照他们那么说的那么做”，而是“听听他们怎么说，琢磨他们怎么想”。</p>
<p>Note - Location 2509</p>
<p>看看驴是怎么想的</p>
<p>18.20161202 什么决定你的命运 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2923</p>
<p>1.我发现一个需求需要被满足可尚未被满足； 2.我自己就有很强烈的这个需求； 3.我问了我身边的人，他们都说也有这个需求； 4.市场上没有满足这个需求的产品； 5.如果我做出来，那么就是第一个做出来的，于是，一定很有优势，很有前景……这是个很常见的思路，也是最难以说服的想法——因为每句话看起来都是对的，连起来看更像是对的……可是，真的吗？“我有一个很强烈的需求”和“整个世界都有这个强烈的需求”差别甚大。</p>
<p>19.20161209“自我驱动力”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2998</p>
<p>“用英语”对绝大多数人来说，根本就不是刚需。很多人觉得学英语重要，是因为周围的人都这么认为。对于绝大多数人来说，通过英语考试才是真正的刚需。这也证明了为什么那么多人会在考完四六级之后，就再也不去碰任何英语相关的材料，即便他们口口声声说英语重要。其实不论是英语、健身还是任何其他的技能，当它无法影响你的生活时，你都不能感受到它的必要性。不信你可以回头看看自己年初许下的愿望，是不是少了哪一项你的生活都不会受影响？既然不是刚需，那就是“不必需”，于是，事实上“不用也可以”，事实上“没有也行”，虽然“有倒也挺好”，可“没有的话顶多是有点怨念而已”……</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3054</p>
<p>“找借口”是一种刚需。或者说找借口就是一种习惯。每当遇到困难的时候，总是能够第一时间找到各种各样的理由，说服自己可以放弃。这种习惯或者说刚需是一个大坑。如果你往坑里看一下，就会发现无数人在下面挣扎。</p>
<p>20.20161216 认知、选择、培养正确的刚需 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3330</p>
<p>急切地想要改变现状。现状越差，越没有积累，就越急切。又因为积累这个东西，谁都没什么办法像变戏法一样弄出来，于是，在面临“要么认了”、“要么从现在开始积累”这种极为难受的选择之时，有相当数量的人最后直接选择“铤而走险”。其实很多道理已经有了非常朴素的解释，但是因为它太过“耳熟能详”，所以被我们忽略了。这个时候就需要我们通过合理的比喻，让它再次引起你的重视。比如不要急于改变现状，这就有点类似于“不要想摆脱地心引力”。只要我们还活在地球上，你就无法逃脱地心引力的</p>
<p>20.20161216 如何认知、选择、培养正确的刚需</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3393</p>
<p>在表现型选手的眼里，这个世界只有“成功”和“失败”。在此之间，并没有任何中间状态。而在进取型选手的眼里，他们知道成功和失败，只是某一刻的状态，在它们之间还有无数个过渡阶段，也就是我们所说的“成长”。所以对于表现型选手来说，如果不能成功，那就一定意味着失败。所以当他们看不到成功的希望时，多半都会选择放弃。但是进取型选手则不然。他们知道除了失败跟成功之外，自己还有一个状态：不断成长，不断接近成功。</p>
<p>21.20161223 投资的刚需是避险</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3567</p>
<p>从众很容易，你不需要思考，只要把自己的大脑托付给大众即可。但是你同样无法享受“特立独行且正确”所带来的收益。其实不光是投资理财，这句话可以在生活的方方面面中得到运用。我们之前一直强调注意力的珍贵。我们通过各种方式节省下来的注意力，就是为了最后把它运用到提升自己的判断力上。提升自己的专业能力，学会如何合理地规避风险，这些都是最需要我们投入注意力的事情。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3645</p>
<p>如何区分自己是在“看傻瓜冒险”，还是正在被当作“冒险中的傻瓜”？这里有一条简单朴实的判断标准：能否清晰说出“行动依据”。如果你的依据只不过是“别人都这么做”、“大家都这么想”、“我得到了小道消息”等等，那么你成为被别人观察的“傻瓜”的几率就很大。有独立判断能力的人，总能给出清晰的依据，即便它不是每次都正确，但一定是可以通过反馈来修正的。</p>
<p>22.20161230 尊重资本量级的差异</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3862</p>
<p>但是人和人之间的差别，其实就是在这一次选择中产生的。对于你来说，生活中真正的刚需到底是“找借口”还是“找方法”，将极大程度影响你的未来。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3882</p>
<p>当然，他们也会去实践，只不过他们会躲掉明显的坑，达成目标的效率就相对高很多。</p>
<p>24.20170113 开始投资活动的条件</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4466</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4483</p>
<p>这里有几个小要点：1.事实上，你开始跟踪的股票，究竟是不是 GAFATA 其实无所谓的。如果你英文不好，那在国内股票市场上选一个你有根据地认为可能会持续成长的企业就可以了——因为接下来的时间里，你闲着没事儿就要关注这个企业的财报与其他新闻的。2.金额必须设置成 1 元——也就是最方便且金额最小的单位。1 元、1000 元、1000 万元，抑或是美元或者人民币，其实都无所谓的。不是因为“反正是虚拟投资”，而是因为从一开始你就要养成习惯：关注相对值而不是绝对值——增长比例才真正重要。3.每个月只更新一次数据，每个月的其它时间里，绝对不要去看这个数据，看它不仅没意义，更可怕的是会养成坏习惯——至于那个坏习惯有多可怕，以后你会越来越明白的。（进一步的自我训练是：如果竟然有哪怕一次破例，没到月底就忍不住去看数据了，那你一定要想办法恰当地惩罚自己一下……）</p>
<p>24.20170113 开始投资活动的条件 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4639</p>
<p>学不好英语就别学了，直接用吧。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4684</p>
<p>多数人关注点都在“我要什么”，只有少数人会同时想到“我有什么”。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4689</p>
<p>永远不要去嘲笑别人。真正做好过一件事情的人，是不会去嘲笑他人的，因为他们知道做好一件事情有多不容易。</p>
<p>25.20170120 你能准确预测股票？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 4733</p>
<p>正是在这些常识上的认知差别，注定了一部分人做的是赌博，而另一部分人做的则是投资。</p>
<p>26.20170127 贪婪与诱惑 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5242</p>
<p>“财富自由”是个实在的目标，不愁吃不愁穿，不用再为了生活而出售时间之后，你可以做很多原本你没机会、没能力做的事情——那才是自由的滋味。不要操别人的心，把注意力放在自己的成长上去。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5248</p>
<p>财富自由的定义：从某一时刻开始，再也用不着为生活出售自己的时间。</p>
<p>28.20170210 全部押上意味着什么？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5584</p>
<p>“把一切都押上去”之后所发生的事情，在这世界的各个角落里，历史上重演了无数遍。结果出现的那一瞬间之前还以为是“勇气”的东西，在结果出现的那一瞬间突然显得是“那么明显地、那么无以复加地愚蠢”……</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5649</p>
<p>60%的胜算，投资你的总资产的 20%，本质上已经是“押上全部”了！——</p>
<p>28.20170210 全部押上意味着什么？★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5694</p>
<p>为了回避那个最大的风险（从此再无机会），你作为投资者，必须牢记且绝对不能触犯的铁律是：永远不要押上全部！</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5727</p>
<p>从此再无机会。套用赌徒们常说的一句话——“要想尽一切办法留在赌桌上！”因为一旦被清退，一旦离开了赌桌，就再无任何机会。中国的古话说，“留得青山在，不怕没柴烧”，其实说的也是同样的道理。</p>
<p>29.20170217 最简单的安全投资策略是“定投”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5910</p>
<p>定投策略：定期等额购买某一支（或几只）成长型股票。假设，基于种种原因，根据你的知识与判断，最终，你选择了某支股票，你认定它是个“成长型公司”，之后你就可以开始行动了：设定一个期限，可以是每周，也可以是每月，也可以是每个季度；每个期限到达之时，无视股价的变化，购买等量金额的该公司股票。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 5941</p>
<p>如果定投策略如此有效的话，那岂不是应该人人都这么做？那为什么最终很少有人真正采用且贯彻实施这么简单这么有效的安全投资策略呢？一句简单的“大多数人根本熬不住”，事实上并没有给出太多的本质解读。如果我们有能力穿透表象看透实质的话，就会发现，定投策略的关键，并不在于“定期”，也不在于“定额”，甚至并不在于“长期坚持定投策略”……那关键在哪儿？关键在于：在开始之前，你通过深入的研究，得到了相当确定的结论：这是一家成长性极强的公司……因为，你的收益 =公司成长性 x 定投策略效用。如果事实上该公司的成长性是零，那么，定投策略的效用等同于无；如果最终证明，该公司不仅没有成长，甚至干脆衰落了，那么定投策略的效用事实上等同于放大了损失。</p>
<p>29.20170217 最简单的安全投资策略是“定投”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 6144</p>
<p>当你进入一个新的领域时，由于无知带来的恐惧感是你必须要面对的困难之一。这个时候只需要告诉自己：再坚持几天，再多看几遍。你就会发现，原来陌生的东西会变得熟悉，不懂的概念会慢慢变得清晰。等到熬过这个阶段再去回顾时，就会看到自己已经成长了很多。</p>
<p>32.20170310 做个正常“时间买卖”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 6815</p>
<p>让我们心甘情愿地付出的人。而这里所说的付出，常常是我愿意花时间、花精力主动联络，主动维系友谊的那些人。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 6818</p>
<p>朋友就是那些我愿意花时间与精力，与之共同做成至少一件事儿的人。</p>
<p>33.20170317 关于“写作”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7030</p>
<p>没有执行的想法只不过是幻觉。“写对别人有用的东西”，这是写作的终极技巧，没有什么比这个更重要的了。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7044</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7074</p>
<p>这固然是一个好的方法，但它有自身的局限性。因为不是每个人都愿意给你机会去讲解，毕竟他人的时间也非常珍贵。这个时候“写作”就成为了实践这种想法的最佳途径。第一，你不需要再依靠他人就可以独自完成“教别人”的流程。而且在这个过程中，你可以不断反复打磨，而不必担心对方会不耐烦。第二，文章发表之后，你也可以得到真实世界的反馈。相信我，只要你说得足够清楚，并且真的对大家有用，这个世界就会给你相应的反馈。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7110</p>
<p>没有执行的想法只不过是幻觉。于是，到最后，即便是那少数的 5%中的绝大多数，有的也只不过是幻觉而已。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7140</p>
<p>持续写作很可能是锻炼学习能力、锻炼思考能力、锻炼分析能力、锻炼沟通能力的最直接、最低成本的方式。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7155</p>
<p>“写对别人有用的东西”，这是写作的终极技巧，没有什么比这个更重要的了。仅仅这么一个问题，就会把这世间绝大多数文字过滤掉，</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7169</p>
<p>等我准备好以后，我就……我看过很多说这种话的人，但最后真正准备好并且把事情做成的寥寥无几。实际上很多人打着“准备”的名义为自己的拖延找借口。比如写作这件事情，其实你写的每一篇文章都是在为后面的一篇文章做准</p>
<p>34.20170324 决定“你的价格”的要素 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7238</p>
<p>千万不要误以为价格和成本直接完整相关，它们只是间接部分相关。你想想，人们出钱购买一个产品，是因为他们真的需要，而不是因为那个产品的制作成本有多高，这也很明显，是吧？你有个产品，在我出手购买之前，你的一切成本都跟我没关系，你的情怀也跟我完</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7244</p>
<p>天呐！我这么努力，我这么勤奋，可为什么这么惨？！也许这很无情，却是事实：这世界不需要你。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7255</p>
<p>你如何变得更值钱呢？-答案很简单啊！成为一个真正有用的人。刚才提到这么一句话，你可能没太注意：与这世界产生强联系，是增强生活幸福感的最根本方式呢。现在你反应过来了吗？为什么少数人明显比大多数人更幸福，而且幸福程度高出很多很多？解释很简单啊：他们与这个世界有更强的联系……</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7279</p>
<p>由于“对别人有用”对我来说是最重要的，所以，我在写作的过程中，甚至干脆放弃掉了绝大多数的修辞，只留下不可或缺的两种（类比和排比），因为“文笔”这事儿对我来说，根本不重要，因为它对读者来说根本不重要。对我的读者来说，最重要的是：我花时间、我花精力、我甚至花钱，读到的东西最好真正能给我带来变化（“有用”的另外一个说法）……别说修辞了，我有时为了“真正对读者有用”连传说中必须的那种“简单清楚的结构”都肯直接放弃，不惜被认为啰嗦，不惜被认为重复——因为有些重要的点，就是需要通过反复才能说清楚、听明白、做得好。这么多年过来，我很清楚地知道我的这个价值观给我带来了多大的收益，多少的幸福。让我们稍微聚</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7289</p>
<p>1.他（们）真正的需求是什么，最需要的又是什么？ 2.我是那个能够满足他需求的人吗？ 3.如果我能，有没有可能成为必需？ 4.如果我不能，我怎样才能？ 5.有必要一定由我去满足这个需求吗？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7336</p>
<p>很多时候选择比努力还要重要。因为如果你选错了方向，不论你多么努力，只要没有人需要你，你的劳动成果就不被认可。</p>
<p>35.20170331 关于“选择的方法”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7434</p>
<p>——无论是谁在任何时候做出的选择，最终都要面对不确定的未来，所以，即便选择足够正确了，最终也不一定成功，但胜算更高，这是很显然的，是吧？</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7443</p>
<p>很多人在选择面前不知所措，一方面是因为没有明确的价值观，另一方面也是因为：不愿意承担选择后的结果。</p>
<p>36.20170407 关于“成长率”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7540</p>
<p>满足温饱的生意；能够赚钱的生意（温饱之外还有富余）；能够成长的生意（富余越来越多）；能够做到成长率不断提高的生意（这里包含着一个很多人从来都没想过的概念：成长率）……</p>
<p>37.20170414“提高成长率”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7663</p>
<p>很多人误以为乐观的人不会焦虑，事实上并非如此。乐观的人一样会焦虑，只不过，他们感受到焦虑之后，会用元认知能力分辨一个事实，“花时间去焦虑”本身并不解决问题。于是，就会去寻找解决方案，而后把注意力放在解决问题之上，而不是仅仅看着问题发愁……</p>
<p>38.20170421 关于“知识”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7877</p>
<p>知识本身并无法给我们创造价值，只有因为它的存在，改变了我们的选择时，它的作用才能真的体现出来。</p>
<p>39.20170428 关于“智商”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 7992</p>
<p>所谓的智商，其实就是“解决问题的能力”。（不一定是“马上解决问题的能力”，“经过长期努力终于解决问题”，也是很强的能力，实际上就是智商高的表现……</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 8047</p>
<p>经常花时间“设身处地”地从他人角度思考（暂时把关注焦点从自己身上挪到他人身上），绝对是提高“智商”的快捷方式……当然，很多人把这个叫做“情商”，我个人觉得自己并不需要这个概念。</p>
<p>40.20170505 关于“速成”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 8413</p>
<p>习一切技能必须的过程——关键在于： 1.尽快开始这个过程； 2.尽快度过这个过程。</p>
<p>44.20170602 一个人生的作弊器“学习能力”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 9353</p>
<p>能学会有人手把手教的东西；能学会书本上所教授的技能；能学会没有人能教授的技能……</p>
<p>47.20170623“精明的时间买卖”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 9818</p>
<p>有一笔数目并不小的你根本用不上的钱，是财富自由的一个基本标志。把自己所学的知识传授给别人，这是对于个人商业模式的双重升级过程。给这件事情赋予重大的意义，甚至多重重大的意义。不仅要理解别人，还要理解整个主要由别人构成的世界 。虽然说升级个人商业模式很重要，但是不要急于求成，可以先把解决自己的刚需作为目标。</p>
<p>48.20170630 最好的个人商业模式 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 10113</p>
<p>成长的方法是什么？几乎只有一个答案：学习。有意义的人生之中，貌似没有什么比这两个字更重要的了。习得每一个技能，都是给自己赋能，让自己拥有更强的能力。拥有更多的技能，就是拥有更多维度的能量。人之所以能够进步，之所以能够成长，就是因为学习能力，甚至，在我的世界里，我把学习、进步、成长，统一称为“</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 10134</p>
<p>既然你的目标是“终归有一天不再出售自己的时间了”；那么你的行动就应该是“想办法合理地逐步减少自己出售时间的数量”；而方法就是“能用钱换时间的时候尽量用钱换时间”；进而，省下来的时间全都“投资”到自己的持续进化上去……</p>
<p>50.20170714 应用“原则”在关键时刻作出正确的选择 ★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 10457</p>
<p>永远只选择鼓励他人绝不与他人公开争吵相信试错常常是进步的唯一途径相信“教”是最好的学习方法长期保持耐心才能看到最后的结果做了再说，而不是说了也不做</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 10526</p>
<p>如何做出高质量的选择？1.选择前，添加和筛选必要的条件；2.选择时，用条件严格地筛选。</p>
<p>52.20170728 关于“执行力”★</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 10748</p>
<p>程，没有人能够跳过。如果你会做，直接做就是了。如果不会做，当然是要去学了！学会了就开始做，如果学不会，那原本就应该接着学……可是绝大多数人在这里就选择了“不了了之”。还有更狠、更气人的情况：明知道这事儿应该怎么做，甚至每一步都很清楚，可就是不做、没做；也不是不想做，但反正不是今天做，明天呗？最气人的情况是这样的：也不是没做，做过，很早就做过，但就是没有持续做……</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero to Sold</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/zero-to-sold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 07:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/business/zero-to-sold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We found out that many other teachers did the same when they started talking about their self-built solutions in their online communities. Teachers began to share their templates through Google sheets. It was clear that this was a shared problem in a very tight-knit community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - Location 252&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;发现了一个群体的集体痛点&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight(pink) - Location 252&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;even though it helped, was clunky and overwhelming. I looked into it, and it seemed quite possible to build a web-based application that would do this work faster and more reliably.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We found out that many other teachers did the same when they started talking about their self-built solutions in their online communities. Teachers began to share their templates through Google sheets. It was clear that this was a shared problem in a very tight-knit community.</p>
<p>Note - Location 252</p>
<p>发现了一个群体的集体痛点</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 252</p>
<p>even though it helped, was clunky and overwhelming. I looked into it, and it seemed quite possible to build a web-based application that would do this work faster and more reliably.</p>
<p>Note - Location 254</p>
<p>发现了一个更好的解决方案</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 254</p>
<p>There was a sizeable market with an apparent, shared, and critical problem. The problem was solvable, but no one had yet built anything to make it noticeably easier.</p>
<p>Note - Location 255</p>
<p>商机的定义。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 262</p>
<p>So, we released it to the public, built a landing page, and waited. Nothing happened. One or two people signed up for the free trial, but there was not much else. We hadn&rsquo;t done any marketing, and we hadn&rsquo;t made any sales. The service just sat there, idling.</p>
<p>Note - Location 264</p>
<p>市场需要冷启动</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 264</p>
<p>And then, one day, everything changed. In a comment to a Facebook post about how teachers dealt with feedback, Danielle dropped the link to our product with an explanation of how she used it. Teachers started to respond, asking for more details, they checked out the program, and came back to share their newly found discovery on social media.</p>
<p>Note - Location 266</p>
<p>在知乎上也经常有类似操作</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 267</p>
<p>that fueled the growth of our business from its first few users to thousands of customers a couple of months later. It was surreal, but we had tapped into a highly active tribe. Once we understood that, we didn&rsquo;t need to do much when it came to marketing our product: our users would do most of that for us.</p>
<p>Note - Location 269</p>
<p>社区一条帖子就完成了冷启动：一个好东西被大家看到了。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 278</p>
<p>Every day, new teachers would sign up, and since we provided a service that solved their problems well, we had incredibly high retention and conversion rates.</p>
<p>Note - Location 279</p>
<p>确实解决问题并且高频使用</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 279</p>
<p>For many of our customers, teaching from home was a side hustle. Using our product enabled many of them to turn this into a full-time source of income. We priced our service to be affordable and easily justified. We even increased our prices by 50% a year into running the business, and it continued growing nevertheless.</p>
<p>Note - Location 281</p>
<p>价值被真正的创造了出来</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 303</p>
<p>business from nothing, without any outside funding or assistance. Bootstrapping is about accomplishing the</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 331</p>
<p>In the Preparation Stage, the focus will be on finding an audience, their biggest problem, and a solution that solves that problem in a way to make people pay for it. You will find out how to price your product initially and start selling.</p>
<p>Note - Location 333</p>
<p>第一阶段最大的问题是种子用户与定价让他们付钱</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 334</p>
<p>In the Survival Stage, the focus will be on finding a repeatable way to make money. You will learn how to work on the product, listen to your early customers, and start building out processes and automation to stay on top of your business.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 352</p>
<p>Find your niche audience. Find and validate their critical problem. Invent and validate a solution to their problem. Build a product to implement that solution. Build a business that can repeatedly sell that product to your audience.</p>
<p>Note - Location 354</p>
<p>价值创造一般过程</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 362</p>
<p>Tech founders—and I count myself as one—focus on products because that is what we use to solve our problems. After all, when you run into a challenging task, what do you look for first? An in-depth scientific explanation for the epistemological essence of the task? Or a tool that will do the job for you seconds after you install it?</p>
<p>Note - Location 365</p>
<p>作为一个技术宅,万不可太沉迷于技术,应该关注产品。解决问题而不是研究科学。能用就行</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 368</p>
<p>Successful businesses are built by solving critical problems for an audience that will pay for a solution to their issues. The Preparation Stage is when you make these foundational choices. Once in motion, a business has certain inertia that makes these decisions hard to change. Even though pivoting your business into new markets is sometimes the right choice, it’s extra effort. That’s why it’s a good idea to spend considerable time on getting it right in the first place.</p>
<p>Note - Location 371</p>
<p>为特定群体解决一个关键的问题,这个问值得他们花钱解决。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 378</p>
<p>They fail because there were not enough customers. They fail because the product solved the wrong problem. They fail because the product solved the problem the wrong way. And sometimes, they fail even though the product solved the customers&rsquo; problems.</p>
<p>Note - Location 380</p>
<p>一句话总结就是产品必须要真的有价值</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 385</p>
<p>Many successful bootstrapped businesses start with an audience, a specific niche. They find their customers&rsquo; critical problems and provide valuable solutions that people gladly pay for. Their product is centered around continuously providing value to new and existing customers. Audience, problem, solution, and product can be looked at individually.</p>
<p>Note - Location 387</p>
<p>Fake it until you make it . Who why how what</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 390</p>
<p>Who am I helping? You will discover how to find the perfect niche and make sure it can support your business in Step One: Your Audience. Why do they need help? Learn how to find and validate their critical problem in Step Two: Their Problem. How can I help them with that? Find a good solution and make sure it fits into your prospective customers&rsquo; workflow in Step Three: Your Solution. What can I create to help them that way? You&rsquo;ll learn how to create an easy-to-maintain and reliable product in Step Four: Your Product.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 400</p>
<p>A business would be nothing without customers. You can have the best product in the world, but you won’t be able to build any meaningful business if there is no one to pay for what you offer.</p>
<p>Note - Location 401</p>
<p>换句话说，没有客户的产品一文不值</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 402</p>
<p>where do you find those paying customers? The first step to building a business is answering that question, and for bootstrapped founders, there is one critical component: finding the perfect niche.</p>
<p>Note - Location 403</p>
<p>需要回答的第一个问题</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 406</p>
<p>For a bootstrapped business, the choice of your target audience has a few significant limitations: you will have to be careful to find a market that sits in the Goldilocks Zone between too small and too big, and, at best, it should grow in a certain way. You will discover how to find the numbers and figures to make informed choices about your audience.</p>
<p>Note - Location 408</p>
<p>市场规模太大会有巨头，太小无法支撑成本</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 417</p>
<p>So, what makes a niche interesting for a bootstrapper? What is it about niche customers that you can leverage to create a sustainable business? How deep a niche do you need to find a good audience?</p>
<p>Note - Location 419</p>
<p>为什么种子用户对你的东西感兴趣，你如何利用这些种子用户作为杠杆来撬动车轮转起来。</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 422</p>
<p>sometimes we look for immutable things like age or gender niches. Other times the specifics we’re interested in are fluid things like preferences or experience levels. Some niches can be large enough to contain millions of people, and others might just consist of a handful of individuals.</p>
<p>Note - Location 423</p>
<p>细分市场的一些共性</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 424</p>
<p>What unites all niches is that they are inclusive of some and exclusive of others. The members of the in-group will be reasonably similar, depending on the specificity of the niche. That’s why niches work so well for bootstrapped businesses: if you can provide a tool that solves a niche problem very well, you can be sure that everyone in the niche will be interested in it.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 427</p>
<p>InBev, the makers of Bud Light, spend more than $1.5 billion every year. They do that because they need to be present in the mind of every single shopper when they think of getting a beer.</p>
<p>Note - Location 429</p>
<p>大企业的玩法是烧钱直接给客户洗脑</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 431</p>
<p>A craft beer company might put up flyers in a local pub that is serving lots of craft beers, or allocate a budget to exhibiting at beer festivals. A niche business will market to its niche and no one else.</p>
<p>Note - Location 432</p>
<p>Niche 的营销绝应当精细化面对小众人群</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 436</p>
<p>If you filter a large group of people by several specific properties, you will end up with an audience that shares those properties. As a result, these people will also share many other things that can make building products and selling them very convenient.</p>
<p>Note - Location 438</p>
<p>Niche 有一些共性</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 438</p>
<p>People in your niche will likely have the same problems. If they love fantasy football, they all need to keep track of their teams. If they enjoy fly-fishing, they all need to find information on where to fish and how the weather will impact their chances of a catch. If you spend enough time investigating the problems of your niche, you will sooner or later surface their critical problems. These are the things that are common roadblocks for everyone in the niche. Solving that problem with a dedicated product will allow you to have a high chance of success with your bootstrapped business.</p>
<p>Note - Location 442</p>
<p>同一个 Niche 人群一定是有一些共同的问题，如果你花时间找到这些问题并解决，那你就能启动一个生意了</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 445</p>
<p>From a goal, you can usually infer a problem that is in the way of your customers&rsquo; path to success. Solve that problem, and you can help everyone in the niche reach their goals.</p>
<p>Note - Location 446</p>
<p>从一个目标中，你通常可以推断出一个阻碍客户成功之路的问题。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 454</p>
<p>“a group of people connected to one another, connected to a leader, and connected to an idea.”</p>
<p>Note - Location 455</p>
<p>部落</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 457</p>
<p>you can become a tribe leader yourself. There is room for a lot of leaders in most niche tribes. In such a position, you are regarded as an expert who also offers a product specifically designed for members of the tribe.</p>
<p>Note - Location 458</p>
<p>有人的地方就分左中右,位置足够,你总能在一个区域里当老大</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 460</p>
<p>People derive their identity from belonging to a tribe. If you can place your business in a way that makes your product a thing that “people in our tribe use,” then you will have a guaranteed sales funnel for as long as your niche exists.</p>
<p>Note - Location 461</p>
<p>部落认同感的人都会想要融入，成为部落标配是个极好的营销</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 469</p>
<p>The better you define your niche market, the more confident you can be in your numbers.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 481</p>
<p>Shared interests will allow you to speak to the needs of your niche audience directly. Creating content that has a lot of impact and will be read by a lot of people will be easier, as there is less competition for your audience’s attention.</p>
<p>Note - Location 483</p>
<p>部落聚集便于宣传</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 488</p>
<p>Partnerships in niches become a much more lucrative endeavor. Additional exposure and reach results in quick win-win situations, where both partners can significantly boost both their customer base and their reputation as an expert in the niche. Partnering up with other players in the niche allows you to reach customers at different stages of “niche proficiency,” increasing the breadth of your sales funnel.</p>
<p>Note - Location 491</p>
<p>与其他产品合作</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 491</p>
<p>If you lead a tribe, it will eventually do the marketing for you. A large following will amplify your messages with a lot of reach, giving you credibility and encouraging newcomers to become customers so they can belong to the tribe.</p>
<p>Note - Location 493</p>
<p>哪怕是个群主,也会有额外的公信力</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 494</p>
<p>She became an advocate for the needs of these teachers, and they followed her actively on social media, engaging in conversations, spreading the word, and, best of all, even defending the company and the product against people who dismissed or publicly disliked it. That’s the power of a tribe.</p>
<p>Note - Location 494</p>
<p>网络部落的力量</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 496</p>
<p>If you give people the opportunities to share your content and messages with other tribe members, they will. The interconnected nature of tribes facilitates this rapid exchange of information, and if you leverage those channels, your product will sell itself. At FeedbackPanda, it took one well-placed social media comment to start an avalanche of word-of-mouth referrals that lasted for years.</p>
<p>Note - Location 499</p>
<p>口碑是把双</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 505</p>
<p>If your product is shareable, spend time on creating a referral system early in the life of your business. If it’s not shareable, defer this kind of system until you have exhausted better, more effective marketing techniques.</p>
<p>Note - Location 506</p>
<p>喜欢炫耀是人的天性,要善加利用</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 511</p>
<p>Luckily, these influencers are also much cheaper to partner with than the prominent super-influencers. Often, they are not even aware of their influence, or they don’t necessarily see it as a monetizable activity. While I recommend you still offer them reasonable compensation, you can approach niche influencers as potential partners instead of just seeing them as a marketing channel.</p>
<p>Note - Location 513</p>
<p>与意见领袖合作是个不错的推广方法</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 517</p>
<p>Analyze your competitors for what they do well and what they don’t when you do your market research. If you’ve done your problem validation right, you will see gaps in the market that are not yet served. Build your products around those gaps, and look into partnering with your competitors to expand each other’s customer base.</p>
<p>Note - Location 519</p>
<p>分析竞品，准备差异化竞争</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 519</p>
<p>Look out for non-competitor competitive alternatives: the things people use instead of using an actual product. This can be Post-It notes, an Excel spreadsheet that does not involve numbers, anything that is a general tool applied to a specific problem. These types of makeshift solutions are where you can find your critical problems—and that is where you can best serve your niche.</p>
<p>Note - Location 522</p>
<p>你可以把一些凑合的草台方案做成一个产品</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 524</p>
<p>Like in machine learning, you run the risk of “overfitting” your niche; you might get too specific. There could be a few hundred “Star Trek fans that live in the New Orleans area and love to eat Quinoa,” but that won’t sustain a bootstrapped business.</p>
<p>Note - Location 526</p>
<p>市场规模过小，无法维持一个生意</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 530</p>
<p>In the best case, this will be the critical problem of everyone in the niche, and your product will ideally solve it well enough for your customers to tell everyone they know, and allow your product to sell itself.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 534</p>
<p>A bootstrapped business works best when it starts out in a niche. Most companies will do really well by just staying there. Some expand into other markets. But that initial audience is one of the most important things to carefully select when you start a business.</p>
<p>Note - Location 536</p>
<p>选择正确的方向会更轻松</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 537</p>
<p>A problem we experienced for ourselves. So we solved it for ourselves. We then saw that other teachers, just like Danielle, could benefit from our solution. They had the exact same problem. We knew our first version already solved the problem well. That’s why we knew other teachers would pay for it.</p>
<p>Note - Location 539</p>
<p>当你的产品解决了一个实际的问题，就有人会愿意付钱</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 542</p>
<p>Is the Audience Large Enough? Your audience will have to be big enough to sustain your business. It will likely also have to support competitors, as any successful business will attract competition.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 549</p>
<p>Is the Audience Small Enough? Contrary to popular belief, I think that for a bootstrapped company, in particular, some markets can be too big. Some audiences are too generic, some industries too vast for a great niche to exist. At least, in the beginning, you should have a clearly defined niche. As a bootstrapped entrepreneur, you will reach out to customers and be in direct contact.</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 557</p>
<p>Can They Pay? Will They Pay? Sometimes, you will be serving companies that have a budget for what you offer. Other times, you could help a currently underserved segment of a low-wage industry. The capacity and willingness to pay will be very different between those two.</p>
<p>Note - Location 559</p>
<p>部落人群的支付意愿与支付能力也非常重要，同时也要考虑对方是否愿意更换服务商，而说服白嫖党付钱也很难</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 569</p>
<p>If you have found a painful problem, a niche audience that is both small and big enough for your business, and you have made sure your audience is willing to pay for your solution, you have found your niche. From here you can build out your product and marketing strategies for that market.</p>
<p>Note - Location 571</p>
<p>发现小众痛点，就发现了目标市场</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 583</p>
<p>Knowing if you need to focus more on sales or on marketing is very important. Some markets require you to reach out to buyers individually. For others, a good and well-targeted marketing strategy could mean you will never have to talk to a single customer before they subscribe or purchase. Being aware of how this will develop over time is essential in order to decide where to focus your attention.</p>
<p>Note - Location 585</p>
<p>不要去把自己的产品搞到需要一对一推销,这很重要</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 586</p>
<p>What Are Good Markets for Bootstrapped SaaS? If you see that significant forces are terraforming a market, creating an opportunity where there was none before, that is a good sign. Whenever a new kind of technology or process gets traction in a field that has not seen much change before, it will create little points of friction. Some of them will be critical. These will be the ones that warrant creating a SaaS business.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 593</p>
<p>Some markets, where a lot of small deciders with their own budgets make decisions, are very lucrative. These people can be convinced without needing to deploy corporate diplomacy. You can show them a product, and they will try it out, as they have no one telling them not to. Small businesses and freelancers are great audiences for a bootstrapped SaaS, as they have budgets. Small budgets, maybe, but if there is a painful problem, there will be money to fix it.</p>
<p>Note - Location 596</p>
<p>有些小众市场本就有些拥有预算来解决问题的客户</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 599</p>
<p>What Are Bad Markets for Bootstrapped SaaS?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 601</p>
<p>Enterprise markets are hard to sell into for a small company, although it’s not impossible. Purchasing decisions take a long time, there are a lot of requirements even to be considered, and contracts tend to be custom and require a lot of work. Many enterprise customers won’t buy from small companies out of fear they will vanish within a few years, and that fear is not unfounded. In fact, even for your own bootstrapped business, I would recommend against using services offered by companies smaller than yourself. You will be better off looking for a market that is comprised of small to medium-sized businesses and self-employed freelancers.</p>
<p>Note - Location 606</p>
<p>To B 业务是基本不可能的,因为大企业怕你突然不干了,大企业需要稳定</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 608</p>
<p>Monopoly markets with just a few big players will severely limit your options.</p>
<p>Note - Location 609</p>
<p>巨头垄断的市场就别去了,没机会的</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 611</p>
<p>Markets where years of ruthless competition have created a large number of bottom feeders are hazardous.</p>
<p>Note - Location 611</p>
<p>充分竞争的市场也没戏,你打不过那些老家伙</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 618</p>
<p>usually are full of very similar competitors, fighting it out over price and marginal differences. This saturation makes it hard to enter a market, and even the businesses that are already in that market suffer.</p>
<p>Note - Location 619</p>
<p>同质化竞争开始时,市场就不再是原来的市场了。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 621</p>
<p>When markets shrink, that is often a sign of deterioration. Whenever the number of agents and purchasers in a market decreases, business growth stalls. People cut costs and unnecessary expenses get reduced. All businesses in that market will suffer.</p>
<p>Note - Location 623</p>
<p>市场开始萎缩的时候,基本就应该考虑退出了</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 637</p>
<p>When you’re starting a bootstrapped SaaS business, you have to find a painful problem to solve. For that, you have to find an audience first. But how do you figure out if the audience is big enough to support your business today and five years from now?</p>
<p>Note - Location 639</p>
<p>为谁解决一次个什么问题,这个谁的规模有多大呢?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 731</p>
<p>Identifying a Critical Problem: Working on the Right Thing Once you have found a suitable audience, you can start looking for problems. The great thing about niche markets is that the issues in them are specific and shared by the people in the niche. Solving a common problem will help a lot of people. You already have the right people. Now you just need the right problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 734</p>
<p>当你找到了目标人群，下一步就需要找出他们正在需要解决的痛点</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 735</p>
<p>You are looking for painful problems, and you want to solve the most painful of them all. You also need to validate that this is an actual problem that people need to have addressed. Sometimes, we just want to complain, but we don’t want to change our ways. You will need to find a problem so painful that we just have to deal with it.</p>
<p>Note - Location 737</p>
<p>寻找真正的痛点，有时候人人吐槽的，并不一定是真正的想要有所改变</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 740</p>
<p>I believe that many bootstrapped businesses only do half the work. They solve a problem, but they don’t address the most critical problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 741</p>
<p>没有解决核心问题的产品，几乎没有价值</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 747</p>
<p>why they think their company didn’t make it. The reasons expressed range from “Bad Business Model” to “Poor Product.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 750</p>
<p>You built a solution for customers who think they have that problem under control. You solved the wrong problem. You developed a solution that helps only at the margins. You solved the wrong problem. You built something, but your customers have bigger fish to fry. You solved the wrong problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 752</p>
<p>一些常见的错误痛点</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 753</p>
<p>You want to build a “need-to-have” instead of a “nice-to-have.” You want to develop a painkiller instead of a vitamin. You want to be their aspirin. How can this be done? By finding their most important problem: the one issue that is critical to their success.</p>
<p>Note - Location 756</p>
<p>你需要解决的是妨碍他们的核心问题</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 759</p>
<p>The most crucial problem a customer faces is on their minds most often. It’s the most important because it’s coming up frequently and is never easy to solve. It has the most impact on their lives, but it’s not always the obvious choice. If you can help a customer with their most critical problem, they will benefit the most.</p>
<p>Note - Location 760</p>
<p>什么样的问题算核心问题?</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 762</p>
<p>diligence.</p>
<p>Note - Location 762</p>
<p>勤勤恳恳</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 771</p>
<p>A Critical Problem Is Painful Problems can be a nuisance. They come up, and you either deal with them or ignore them. We can’t ignore critical problems. They persistently make the lives of those who have them harder until they are resolved. They can’t be just ignored, because they consistently reduce the quality of life.</p>
<p>Note - Location 773</p>
<p>关键痛点是非常痛苦且你无法逃避,必须面对的问题</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 776</p>
<p>Find the critical problem where ignoring something causes a lower quality of life.</p>
<p>Note - Location 776</p>
<p>关键痛点让生活品质下降</p>
<p>Note - Location 782</p>
<p>关键痛点往往又是浪费生命或者浪费金钱的,比如写日报</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 784</p>
<p>Find the critical problem at the intersection of something mandatory and something wasteful.</p>
<p>Note - Location 785</p>
<p>关键问题总是位于强制与浪费的交叉点</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 786</p>
<p>A Critical Problem Is Not Optional Some things can be ignored or delegated, but a critical problem can’t be. If it’s critical, people will have to deal with the problem every time it occurs. They can’t just opt out of it. Solving the problem is essential to making any kind of progress in the work.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 791</p>
<p>Find the critical problem where people would love to opt out, but can’t.</p>
<p>Note - Location 791</p>
<p>关键痛的点往往是不想干又不得不干的问题</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 793</p>
<p>A Critical Problem Occurs Frequently and Repeatedly The reason why critical problems are always on the minds of your customers is that the problems happen so often. Every day, every week, every month, the critical problems repeatedly occur. For your customers, it’s always the most urgent thing at that time. The issue needs to be solved there and then, every single time. If it’s not frequent, it is likely not a critical problem. If it occurs repeatedly and isn’t easily solved, it is likely to be a critical problem.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 799</p>
<p>Find the critical problem where people need to do the same thing over and over again.</p>
<p>Note - Location 800</p>
<p>关键痛点会一次又一次的刺痛你,永无止境</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 801</p>
<p>A Critical Problem Takes up Too Much Time If a problem can be solved quickly, people either solve it the moment it appears or they set aside some time to do the work in a batch later, without feeling like it’s a waste of time. If that is the case, the problem is not really critical. Only when you need to spend considerable time and effort each time you solve the problem will it be impossible to “just” deal with it. “Doing it later” also turns into a chore, as it may take hours or days to deal with a long queue of deferred problems. A critical problem will feel like an unwelcome chore: important, yet tiresome.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 808</p>
<p>Find the critical problem where solving a problem takes a long time every time the problem occurs.</p>
<p>Note - Location 809</p>
<p>关键痛点每一次都消耗你不少时间</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 810</p>
<p>A Critical Problem Forces People to Solve It Using Their Own System There is the joke that every SaaS is an Excel sheet transformed into business logic. The moment someone uses generic tools like word processors or spreadsheets to solve a problem, it’s an indicator that the problem is valuable enough to build tools. Most problems don’t have high complexity, and they can be solved on the spot. But a critical issue will be complicated enough to start developing a system. If your customers have a pile of Post-its or a chaotic assortment of Word and Excel files to solve a problem, you may have found a critical problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 815</p>
<p>关键痛点往往都正在用土办法解决</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 819</p>
<p>Find the critical problem where people are solution-aware and have already created their own simple systems to solve the problem.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 832</p>
<p>They’ll be willing to pay: if the solution saves them time if the solution saves them money if the solution makes them money</p>
<p>Note - Location 833</p>
<p>当你为他们提供这些服务,他们乐于掏钱</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 838</p>
<p>They Have No Interest in Paying With non-critical problems, customers often find alternative ways of solving the problem because they want to save money. It’s not worthwhile for them to look for and pay for a solution that they value less than alternative solutions.</p>
<p>Note - Location 840</p>
<p>可以不愿意花钱解决的问题不是关键痛点</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 853</p>
<p>Finding the Critical Problem So, how can you learn about which is the most critical problem your customers have? It’s quite straightforward: talk to them. Ask them what annoys them most. Find out where they want to be. Ask them what keeps them from being the best at what they are doing.</p>
<p>Note - Location 856</p>
<p>发现痛点最直接的方式就是和他们聊聊</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 859</p>
<p>Focus on what you can help them accomplish. Ask what customers want and which state they want to be in when the work is done. Don’t focus too much on the “how it’s done.” That is usually more based on tradition than on an optimized process.</p>
<p>Note - Location 861</p>
<p>直接询问客户想要什么产品是不行的，你需要知道他们在用过你的产品后会达到什么状态来判断</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 867</p>
<p>If you find something that will obviously make them significantly more money or save them a lot of time, then you have something to go on. Customers should really want to pay for it, almost have a burning desire to open their wallets. When they ask you if that is possible and you tell them it is, their mouth should drop to the floor.</p>
<p>Note - Location 870</p>
<p>如果你能帮他们多赚钱，或者能帮他们节约时间，他们会愿意打开钱包</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 886</p>
<p>Time-Related Pains Most productivity-related issues cause temporal pain: people feel like they’re wasting time. These pains are caused by suboptimal processes and friction between tasks. If tedious work takes a lot of time, it keeps you from doing important and useful things instead. That leads to time mismanagement and relevant actions not being taken. By solving the time-related problem, productive tasks can be accomplished faster and sooner. When people complain about inefficiencies, tedium, or pointless work, you’re looking at a time-related problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 890</p>
<p>浪费时间是最大的痛苦</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 896</p>
<p>If you hear people complaining about a waste of money, prohibitive costs, compliance, or the wrong people working on the wrong things, you’ve found a resource-related problem.</p>
<p>Note - Location 897</p>
<p>浪费钱也是一种痛苦</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 898</p>
<p>Self-Related Pains This group of problems is often overlooked. Everyone wants to be notable somewhere. This can mean holding a position in a company or being regarded as a supportive co-worker or friend. When people struggle with achieving these things, they feel self-related pains. The four essential concepts to look out for here are Reputation, Accomplishment, Advancement, and Empowerment.</p>
<p>Note - Location 901</p>
<p>个人焦虑也是痛点，罗振宇做的便是这个生意</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 933</p>
<p>Do They Know? The Problem with Problem Awareness When you’re conducting interviews with customers, you will hear them talk a lot about the problems that bother them. These are the known knowns. But your prospects will never be able to tell you about the issues they don’t realize they have.</p>
<p>Note - Location 935</p>
<p>有时候客户已经习以为常，需要我们来教客户偷懒</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 991</p>
<p>Efficiency What keeps you from being more efficient at work? Why can’t you do more of what you do? Which tasks feel like they are a drag?</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 993</p>
<p>Effectiveness What limits you from doing your job the right way? Which tasks are the most pointless? What annoys you about working with competitive products? What is your experience like with each of them?</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 996</p>
<p>Financials Where are you spending too much on tools? Where are you spending too much on consulting? What is your budget for software tools? What is your budget for outsourcing work?</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 998</p>
<p>Reputation What parts of your skill set do you need to</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 999</p>
<p>work on? Which parts of your job do you hesitate to start? How do you show your colleagues that you’re an expert? Empowerment How can you help other people succeed? Do you share success? Is lifting up people something you are expected to do? Accomplishment How do you celebrate your victories? How much do others see of your work? What’s in the way of your next big success? Advancement What would it need for you to climb the career ladder one more step? Where do you want to be professionally? How can you reach financial security and stability? Where do you see yourself growing toward? What challenges did you have in your professional career so far? What challenges do you have in your professional career at this point?</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 1009</p>
<p>What part of your job do you loathe? What tasks do you delegate the most? What tasks should not be part of your work? Is there anything that seems utterly needless in your day-to-day work? If you wanted to shock the whole industry, what would you change about it?</p>
<p>Highlight(blue) - Location 1077</p>
<p>Avoid People Who Are Trying to Please You Compliments are a problem. They don’t help you. If compliments happen, ignore them. If the customer continues to compliment everything you do, the data will not help you. You can salvage these types of conversations. Dive deep into problems and their implications. Completely ignore any of their opinions about your product, your ideas, or your plans. Focus exclusively on their day-to-day operations, and redirect all talk of your product toward their experiences.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1080</p>
<p>忽略那些给你好评的人，他们的夸奖对于你改进产品没有价值</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1095</p>
<p>Avoid People Who Only Tell You Their Ideas You are validating a problem, not your customer’s assumption. If they are barraging you with their ideas, you will be limited to the outcomes of their perception, not the reality of their problems. Customers have a hard time understanding what they truly value, so their solutions are limited to what they know. Experts can be blinded by years of routine, overvaluing the status quo, and undervaluing even paradigm-shifting improvements.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1099</p>
<p>不要相信有很多想法的客户，他们并不懂自己真正想要的是什么</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1139</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs are good at coming up with ideas. We envision solutions to the problems that trouble the audience we have chosen to help. We think deeply about a problem, mentally shape a product, and see how much it would benefit the quality of life. Then we get to work and build the prototype, eager to release it as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1141</p>
<p>解决方案不是凭空冒出来的，要在实践中获得</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1161</p>
<p>A good question here is, &ldquo;At what stage of your workflow will you be using this solution?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1223</p>
<p>Throughout your solution validation conversations, you want to project a clear interest in solving your customer&rsquo;s problems without causing new ones. If you communicate this clearly in each call, you will create goal alignment between you and your prospect: you both want a great solution that makes things easier for the customer.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1225</p>
<p>解决痛点的目的是让客户更加轻松</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1226</p>
<p>Asking the Right Questions: Focus on Problems not Solutions When you talk to your customers or prospects, you will find that there are questions that always produce meaningful results: where they are now? Where do they want to be? What stands in the way of getting there? Essentially, this is applying the jobs-to-be-done framework to your communication strategy, trying to find their realistic and aspirational states, and then building a solution that allows them to go from one state to the other.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1231</p>
<p>问出正确的问题，关注问题本身而不是解决方案</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1246</p>
<p>So, what should you ask about? Ask about where progress is hindered. Progress is a clear indicator of jobs-to-be-done. After all, you have to move from what is to what ought to be in some way. Progress is that transition. Ask people where they perceive it. Ask about tension and friction during value creation. Where are things harder to accomplish than they ought to be? That is why your customers want to use your product. Once you have found hindered progress, tension, or friction, discover the underlying needs and desired outcomes of the processes involved. Ask about the context of the job-to-be-done: who is involved, who holds the stakes, and who is ultimately responsible for the job-to-be-done?</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1264</p>
<p>the MVP, the Minimum Viable Product.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1269</p>
<p>a few general guidelines that will make sure you can create a product that stands a chance: Your product will never be finished—treat it as an ongoing concern at all times. Allow for quick and safe releases, release early, and release often. The less exciting your tech choices, the better. The fewer things you have to build yourself, the better.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1272</p>
<p>关注的是产品，而不是技术与完成度。敏捷迭代</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1274</p>
<p>“If you&rsquo;re not embarrassed by the first version of your product, you have launched too late.”</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 1426</p>
<p>While you will likely be adding and changing features more than removing them in the early stages of your business, prepare that eventually, you will need to remove features. Avoid becoming too attached. You may be reluctant to remove something you spent a lot of time on. However, you&rsquo;d rather have a slim and focused product than a behemoth that does a thousand things, but none of them well.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1428</p>
<p>你的产品应当小而强，并非大而全，核心功能强就好</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 1436</p>
<p>&ldquo;Art is never finished, only abandoned.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1439</p>
<p>If software can never be truly finished, any stage of it is your best guess at what it should be at the time it&rsquo;s created. As the MVP is the first version of your product that your audience will be exposed to, it is crucial to get it &ldquo;right enough&rdquo; while being okay with it not being &ldquo;perfectly right&rdquo; at the same time. The MVP is your first real contact with your customers. It has two main functions: to allow your early adopters to gauge the value of your service, and to enable you to charge them money to gauge their sincerity. The MVP is the first handshake between you and your customers. To have your MVP leave a great first impression, you will need to scope it sufficiently and time it well.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1444</p>
<p>软件不会被完成，只会被放弃，所以从 MVP 开始就应该收费</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1447</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s a minimal product? It&rsquo;s the core functionality only, a simple tool without any fancy additions. What&rsquo;s a viable product? It&rsquo;s the essence of the solution to your audience&rsquo;s problem, a tool that does exactly what it promises to do, and nothing more.</p>
<p>Highlight(pink) - Location 1451</p>
<p>A minimum viable product should contain a few structural components to make it usable by your audience: your users should be able to sign up and log in, solve their problem, and be able to pay for your product. Anything else is cruft, at least for your MVP.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1452</p>
<p>什么是最小可用产品呢？</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1473</p>
<p>Timing Your MVP It&rsquo;s incredibly hard to time when your MVP is done. Here&rsquo;s the problem: you&rsquo;re much too invested. You have the grand vision of what your product could be. And here you are, looking at a version that is slimmed down to the extent of being unrecognizable. It will always feel like it&rsquo;s not good enough yet.</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1479</p>
<p>The happy path for any customer is to ship the MVP as soon as humanly possible. You need your customers to interact with your product at the earliest possible moment. Only then can you find out what works and what doesn&rsquo;t. You need the MVP to become part of their daily workflow.</p>
<p>Highlight(orange) - Location 1488</p>
<p>If you want it to measure customer commitment, add a rudimentary payment system from the beginning. Give liberal amounts of free trial time, but set an end to it. An indefinite trial period could keep people around, but it won&rsquo;t allow you to determine if your product produces enough value to warrant paying for it.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1490</p>
<p>让第一批用户永久免费</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1882</p>
<p>As technical founders, we&rsquo;re supposed to choose the technology that works best for us and our business. But we often let the cargo-culting around the newest, hottest tech stack get to us. Many technical founders see a new startup as an opportunity to figure out a modern tech stack. That is a dangerous move. Not only do you have to deal with the inherently hazardous nature of creating a new business, but now there is also the chance that the new and mostly untested tech stack may not be able to solve the problem you&rsquo;re trying to solve.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1886</p>
<p>创业本就是冒险,别为你的冒险添加额外的技术风险。</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1976</p>
<p>A business is more than a landing page, a product, and a bank account. A business is a complex system of processes. Building a product may come easy to you if you&rsquo;re technically inclined, but turning it into a value-generating machine is a whole different kind of challenge. Others may have trouble coming up with the product but thrive on building the structures needed to sell it over and over again.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1979</p>
<p>创业不是简单的一个产品加一个银行帐号</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1983</p>
<p>a sellable business is a well-structured business. Nobody wants to buy a business that isn&rsquo;t easy to run. But you don&rsquo;t actually ever need to sell your sellable business. You can enjoy the benefits of an easy-to-operate company and keep it for yourself.</p>
<p>Note - Location 1985</p>
<p>流程标准化的好处</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 1989</p>
<p>Forget Goals, Create Systems: Foundations of a Sustainable Business</p>
<p>Bookmark - Location 2102</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2332</p>
<p>“I want to provide value to my customers that makes their lives easier.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2350</p>
<p>“I can start with something that works.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2361</p>
<p>“I need to know enough to help.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 2379</p>
<p>“I can get people to join my cause when I am overwhelmed.”</p>
<p>Highlight(yellow) - Location 3562</p>
<p>Building a product is not enough. No matter how good your product is, if nobody knows where to find it, you don&rsquo;t have a business. Spreading the word is an essential part of running a business, and so is convincing potential customers to try the product and eventually purchase it.</p>
<p>Note - Location 3564</p>
<p>无论你的产品又多好,你都需要渠道</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>神书《纳瓦尔宝典：财富和幸福指南》</title>
      <link>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%A5%9E%E4%B9%A6%E7%BA%B3%E7%93%A6%E5%B0%94%E5%AE%9D%E5%85%B8%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 12:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.xgdebug.com/posts/self/%E7%A5%9E%E4%B9%A6%E7%BA%B3%E7%93%A6%E5%B0%94%E5%AE%9D%E5%85%B8%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1人应该寻求财富而不是金钱或地位&#34;&gt;1、人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人不应该通过繁重的工作获得财富。&lt;br&gt;
每周花 80 小时在餐馆工作，无法使你变得更富有。&lt;br&gt;
辛勤的劳作是无法避免的，但应该以正确的方式努力。&lt;br&gt;
人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位。&lt;br&gt;
如果你认为财富不重要，财富就会远离你。&lt;br&gt;
财富就是睡觉时仍在赚钱的资产。&lt;br&gt;
没有财富性资产，你睡觉的时候，就没有任何收入；你退休的时候，就不能继续挣钱了。&lt;br&gt;
总之，没有财富，你就无法做到非线性赚钱。&lt;br&gt;
一般来说，财富是通过创办自己的公司或者投资来创造的。&lt;br&gt;
它们都不是通过投入大量时间来实现的，大富豪和你一样，每天也只有 24 小时。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="1人应该寻求财富而不是金钱或地位">1、人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位</h2>
<p>人不应该通过繁重的工作获得财富。<br>
每周花 80 小时在餐馆工作，无法使你变得更富有。<br>
辛勤的劳作是无法避免的，但应该以正确的方式努力。<br>
人应该寻求财富，而不是金钱或地位。<br>
如果你认为财富不重要，财富就会远离你。<br>
财富就是睡觉时仍在赚钱的资产。<br>
没有财富性资产，你睡觉的时候，就没有任何收入；你退休的时候，就不能继续挣钱了。<br>
总之，没有财富，你就无法做到非线性赚钱。<br>
一般来说，财富是通过创办自己的公司或者投资来创造的。<br>
它们都不是通过投入大量时间来实现的，大富豪和你一样，每天也只有 24 小时。</p>
<h2 id="2获得财富的关键">2、获得财富的关键</h2>
<p>要获得财富，可以向社会大众提供有价值的东西——尤其是他们不知道如何获得的。<br>
而且要大规模地供应。<br>
互联网已经极大地拓宽了职业生涯的可能性，多数人对此仍没有清晰的认识。<br>
学会营销，学会创造。<br>
如果这两件都会，没有什么可以阻挡你成功。</p>
<h2 id="3用特殊知识武装你自己">3、用特殊知识武装你自己</h2>
<p>特殊知识是不可以通过培训获得的知识。<br>
如果能通过训练获得，那其他人也可以获得，然后取代你。<br>
特殊知识通常是技术含量高和创造性的。<br>
不可能被外包或自动化的。<br>
（如洞察力） 在真正的好奇心和热情驱使下，将能发现特殊的知识。<br>
创造特殊知识的过程，对你而言，感觉像是在玩，而对别人来说像是工作。<br>
通常，特殊知识在知识的边界，也就是那些现在才弄明白或者真的很难弄明白的东西。<br>
如果你没有百分之百的投入，别人百分之百投入了就会胜过你。<br>
并且他们不只是强你一点点，会比你强很多，因为在思想领域的想法，复利会起作用，杠杆也会起作用。<br>
特殊知识可能是以下这些： 销售技巧。<br>
有音乐天赋。<br>
执着的性格：这意味你能用心研究事物。<br>
热爱科幻：这意味你可以快速吸收很多知识。<br>
玩了很多游戏：这会对游戏理论比较了解。<br>
八卦：这可能帮助你成为非常有趣的记者。<br>
特殊知识是这样一种奇怪组合，来自你的 DNA，你独特的成长环境，和你对这些知识的回应。<br>
这些几乎是融入你的个性和身份的，然后你可以不断磨练它。<br>
学习微观经济学、博弈论、心理学、洗脑术、伦理学、数学和计算机科学。</p>
<h2 id="4用杠杆武装你自己">4、用杠杆武装你自己</h2>
<p>商业杠杆主要有资本、人力、复制成本极低的产品（代码和媒体）。<br>
资本就是指钱。<br>
为了融资，就需要用你特殊的知识，配合你的责任感，展示出你良好的判断力。<br>
人力就是指为你干活的人。<br>
它是最古老和争夺最激烈的杠杆。<br>
人力杠杆会让你父母感到有面子，但不要浪费生命去追求这点。<br>
资本和劳动力是需要获得许可才能使用的杠杆。<br>
人人都在追逐资本，但总得有掏钱的人。<br>
人人都想要去领导其他人，但总得有人做手下。<br>
代码和媒体是无需许可就能用的杠杆，它是新富豪背后的杠杆。<br>
你可以创建软件和媒体，它们能在你睡眠时仍为你干活。<br>
一大群机器人供免费使用——为了节约空间和热效能，它们被打包放进数据中心，去使用它们吧！ 运用特殊知识，配合杠杆，最终会得到你应该得到的。</p>
<h2 id="5一句话产品化你自己">5、一句话：产品化你自己</h2>
<p>这是什么意思呢？“产品化”和“你自己”。<br>
“你自己”有特殊性，“产品化”有杠杆性。<br>
“我在产品化它吗？我可以规模化它？我可以通过人力杠杆、或资本、或代码、或媒体放大它？”所以，这种说法非常方便记忆。<br>
如果你想更富有，你要弄清楚你可以为社会提供哪一样东西，社会还不知道如何得到的，但又是社会想要的，对你来说提供这样东西是自然而然的，它在你的技能范围内，在你的能力范围内。<br>
接着，就是想办法扩大规模，因为只生产一个是远远不够的。<br>
你可能需要生产数千份，或者数万份，或者数百万份，或者数十亿份，这样每个人都可以拥有一个。<br>
史蒂夫·乔布斯（当然包括他的团队）想清楚了社会需要智能手机。<br>
这种智能手机拥有当时手机的所有功能，同时也有更多其它的新功能，并且更容易使用。<br>
因而，他们想出了怎么制造智能手机，再接着就是想清楚怎么大规模生产智能手机。<br>
你要成为能规模化提供这些产品或服务的人。<br>
这才是如何赚钱的真正难题。</p>
<h2 id="6注意你的人品">6、注意你的人品</h2>
<p>在我的生活中，认识一些极度成功、非常受欢迎、非常聪明的人。<br>
然而，我看到他们做了一两件对其他人不太好的事情。<br>
我会说，“嘿，我认为你不应该对别人做这样的事。<br>
因为这最后会伤到你自己。<br>
” 从内心深处我们都知道自己是谁。<br>
你不可能对自己隐藏任何事。<br>
你做得对不对，你是很清楚的，如果你有太多的道德瑕疵，你将不会尊重你自己。<br>
这个世界最糟糕的结果是没有自尊。<br>
如果你都不爱你自己，谁会爱你？ 如果我看到有人做这种事，第一次我会提醒他们，不过通常他们不会改，然后我就和他们保持距离。<br>
我把他们从我的生活切割出去。<br>
如果有人总说他们自己是多么的诚实，他们很有可能是不诚实的。<br>
这只是一些我学到的有效指标。<br>
当有人花很多时间在谈论他们的价值观或谈论他们自己时，意味着他们在掩盖某些事。<br>
我在心里说：“想靠近我的，你的价值观必须要比我更好。<br>
”</p>
<h2 id="7聪明人真的了解一件事">7、聪明人真的了解一件事</h2>
<p>如果有人使用很多复杂的词汇和很多大概念，他们很有可能不知道他们自己在谈论什么。<br>
我认为最聪明的人能把事情向小孩子讲明白。<br>
如果你无法向小孩子讲明白，那么你并不是真的知道。<br>
真正聪明的思考者是思维清晰的思考者，他们理解非常非常基本的基础知识。</p>
<h2 id="8跳出自己看真相">8、跳出自己看真相</h2>
<p>想象我的某位朋友正在经历某些困难的事，如分手、事业、生意失败或健康问题，当他需要我的建议时，往往只需几分钟，我就能准确告诉他，“噢，那个女孩，忘掉她吧，反正她对你不好。<br>
你将会更快乐。<br>
相信我。<br>
你将来会找到更合适的。<br>
” 但他自己就很难看明白这点。<br>
因为他正处于痛苦和折磨中，他的愿望与现实是有冲突的，从而阻止了他看清真相。<br>
同样的事会发生在我们做决定的时候。<br>
为了看清真相，你必须要放下自我，因为自我并不想面对真相。</p>
<h2 id="9真正重要的是闲暇时间">9、真正重要的是闲暇时间</h2>
<p>只有在你感到无聊之后，才会有伟大的想法。<br>
好的想法从不会在你充满压力、忙碌、四处奔波或仓促的时候出现。<br>
如果你的日程表每周没有一两天是不用一直开会、不用一直在忙的，你就无法去思考。<br>
你也不会有和你生意相关的好想法。<br>
你也不可能做出好的判断。<br>
我鼓励每周至少拿出一天（更好的是有两天，因为预备两天的话，你肯定能抽出一天），这样你就有时间去思考了。<br>
珍惜你的时间，它是你的全部。<br>
它比你的金钱更重要。<br>
它比你的朋友更重要。<br>
它比任何东西都重要。<br>
你的时间就是你的一切。<br>
不要浪费你的时间。</p>
<h2 id="10读书能让你成功">10、读书能让你成功</h2>
<p>每天花一小时阅读科学、数学和哲学，很有可能在七年内让你登上人类成功的高层梯队。<br>
我花了很多时间看书。<br>
我唯一真正的朋友是书。<br>
书是伟大的朋友，因为过去几千年来最好的思想家会告诉你他们的智慧。<br>
任何一本能存活两千多年的书，都是经过很多人筛选的，也更有可能是正确的，我想重新读这些书。<br>
事实是，我读书不是为了自我提升。<br>
我阅读是出于好奇和兴趣。<br>
最好的书就是你会着迷的那本。</p>
<h2 id="11为自己的目标做事">11、为自己的目标做事</h2>
<p>我只是真正想为自己的目标而做事。<br>
无论是生意、健身、恋爱、友谊，还是其它的，我认为生命的意义是为自己的目标而做事。<br>
当你为自己而做事时，你能创造出你最好的作品。<br>
即使你做这些是为了赚钱，但实际上你也将会是最成功的。<br>
追随你真正的好奇心，而不是时下的热点事物。<br>
如果你的好奇心把你带到一个社会最终也会去的地方，你将会获得丰厚的报酬。<br>
当你约会的时候，有某个瞬间认识到这段关系不会通往婚姻时，你或许应该继续前行了。<br>
当你在学习某些东西时，例如地理或历史课，你意识到你永远也不会用到这些信息，就放弃这门课程。<br>
这是在浪费时间。<br>
这是在浪费脑力。</p>
<h2 id="12成为一个整体上更好的决策者">12、成为一个整体上更好的决策者</h2>
<p>成为一个整体上更好的决策者。<br>
决策是一切。<br>
是的。<br>
决策是一切。<br>
事实上，有人在 80%的时间而不是 70%的时间都能够做出正确的决策，他在市场中的价值和报酬将高出数百倍。<br>
我认为人们很难去理解杠杆的一个基本事实。<br>
如果我掌管着 10 亿美元，且我经常比其他人多 10%的正确率，我的决策能在一次判断上带来一亿美元的价值。<br>
拥有现代技术和庞大的劳动力以及资本，我们的决策能被杠杆放大的倍率越来越高。<br>
如果我面对一个困难的选择，像下面这些问题： 我应该和这个人结婚吗？ 我应该做这个工作吗？ 我应该买这间房子吗？ 我应该搬到这个城市吗？ 我应该和这个人合伙做生意吗？ 如果你无法下决定，就回答否。<br>
原因是，现代社会充满了选择。<br>
有非常多的选择。<br>
我们生活在一个有 70 亿人的星球，我们可以通过互联网联系到每个人。<br>
有数十万种职业供你选择。<br>
有如此多的选择。<br>
当你选择某些事物时，你会被锁定一段很长的时间。<br>
创业可能需要花费 10 年。<br>
你开始一段感情可能需要 5 年或者更多。<br>
你搬到一个城市可能会待上 10 到 20 年。<br>
这些都是有非常非常长期影响的决定。<br>
只有在我们十分确定的时候才会说”是“。<br>
你从不可能做到绝对确定，但你要做到非常肯定。<br>
如果你有两个选择，并且是相对均等的选择，那么就选择在短期内更困难和更痛苦的那条路。<br>
实际情况是，其中一条路要承受短期的痛苦。<br>
另一条路是在未来在更远的地方才会感到痛苦。<br>
然而，你的大脑想要避免冲突而试图去避开短期的痛苦。<br>
按照定义，如果两个选择是差不多的，其中一个有短期痛苦，那么这个选择就和长期收益有关。<br>
根据复利法则，长期收益是你想要得到的。<br>
你的大脑过于看重短期的幸福，而试图去避免短期的痛苦。<br>
咖啡因是另外一种用长期后果换取短期利益的东西。<br>
本质上，你必须透过你的生活，用好的习惯去替换你不经意养成的坏习惯，承诺成为一个更快乐的人。</p>
<h2 id="13关于幸福">13、关于幸福</h2>
<p>孔子说，人有两次生命，第二次生命始于你意识到生命只有一次之时。<br>
那你第二次生命是在什么时候、怎样开始的呢？（孔子说：我没有说过这样的话。<br>
） 我读过布莱斯·帕斯卡（Blaise Pascal）的一句话。<br>
大概意思是：“人类的全部不幸是因为他们不能安静地待在他们的房间里。<br>
”如果你坐上 30 分钟并感觉到快乐，你就是成功的。<br>
这是非常强的境界，不过很少人能做到。<br>
你要学习的核心技能是，在大多数情况下做到随遇而安、顺势而为。<br>
你可以从生活中得到几乎任何你想要的东西，只要它是你最想得到的东西。<br>
处理冲突的第一规则是：不要和那些经常发生冲突的人在一起。<br>
我对不能持久或难以持续的事物不感兴趣，包括问题多多的关系。</p>
<h2 id="14人生的头等大事">14、人生的头等大事</h2>
<p>我人生的头等大事，高于我的幸福，高于我的家庭，高于我的工作，就是我自己的健康。<br>
首先是我的身体健康。<br>
第二，是我的心理健康。<br>
第三，是我的精神健康。<br>
然后，是我家人的健康。<br>
然后，是我家庭的幸福。<br>
在那之后，我就可以去世界其它地方做任何我需要做的事情了。<br>
基本上，每当你把好习惯推荐给别人时，他们都会为自己找一个借口，通常最普遍的借口就是“我没有时间”。<br>
你听到这个，就知道他是在说“这不是高优先级事项”。<br>
如果某些事是你的头等大事，你就会去做。<br>
这就是生活运转的方式。<br>
如果你有 10 到 15 个优先级很含糊而又不着急的事项，你最终不会做它们之中的任何一个。<br>
我所做的就是决定我人生中的头等大事，高于我的幸福，高于我的家庭，高于我的工作，那就是我的健康。<br>
我的身体健康成为了我的头等大事，那样我就永远也不能说我没有时间。<br>
早晨，我锻炼身体，不管需要多长时间，我都会坚持锻炼。<br>
未锻炼完，我不会开始一天的工作。<br>
我不在乎世界是否正在崩溃和融化，它可以再等 30 分钟，直到我锻炼完。<br>
就像生活中的其它事情一样，如果你愿意做出短期的牺牲，你就会有长期的好处。<br>
“容易的选择，艰难的生活。<br>
艰难的选择，轻松的生活。<br>
”</p>
<h2 id="15不和自己的想法斗争">15、不和自己的想法斗争</h2>
<p>不要把自己看得太重。<br>
你只是一只有计划的猴子而已。<br>
不做任何决定，不下任何判断，只是接受一切。<br>
如果我一边走一边这样做十到十五分钟，我会进入一种非常平静、感恩的状态。<br>
无选择的意识对我很有用。<br>
我学到的另一个方法是，坐在那里，闭上眼睛，每天至少一个小时。<br>
你向任何发生的事情屈服——不做任何努力。<br>
你不为做某些事情而努力，也不为反对某些事情而努力。<br>
如果有想法在你的脑海流动，你就随这些想法流动。<br>
“如果想法来了，想法来了。<br>
我不和它们做斗争。<br>
我也不会去拥抱它们。<br>
我不会去想它们。<br>
我不会去拒绝它们。<br>
我就只是闭着眼睛在那里坐上一个小时，什么也不做。<br>
” 这是一种快乐、幸福和平静的状态。<br>
一旦你拥有它，你就不想放弃它。<br>
如果你每天早上只需坐着闭上眼睛，就能获得一个小时幸福的自由时光，那是超值的。<br>
它将改变你的生活。<br>
你所要做的就是坐在那里，什么也不要做。<br>
就只是坐下来。<br>
闭上你的眼睛说：“我只是想让自己休息一个小时。这是我远离生活的一个小时，这个小时我什么也不做”</p>
<h2 id="16让意识和心灵协调相处">16、让意识和心灵协调相处</h2>
<p>佛教徒谈论意识与自我，他们真的是把你的大脑当做一个多层次的机制：内核级的操作系统在运行，然后，还有一些应用程序在上面运行。<br>
我正在回到我意识层的操作系统，它总是平静的，总是平和的，通常是快乐和满足的。<br>
我试着保持在这样的状态下，而不是激活猴心（指意识层面之下的难以控制的心灵）。<br>
猴心总是担心、害怕和焦虑，它有不可思议的作用，但我尽量不激活它，直到我需要它。<br>
如果我 24 个小时不间断地运行它，我就会浪费能量，而猴心就会成了我，我比我的猴心更重要。<br>
心灵本身就是一种肌肉——它可以被训练和调节，但它已经被社会胡乱地调教成了我们无法控制的样子。<br>
如果你带着意识和意图去审视你的心智，我想你可以把自己的思想、情绪、思想和反应都提取出来，然后你就可以开始重新设置了。<br>
你可以按照自己的意愿来重写这个程序。</p>
<h2 id="17如何定义智慧">17、如何定义智慧？</h2>
<p>一个人理解他所作所为的的长期后果。</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
